<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE glossary PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<glossary id="glossary">
  <title>Glossary of Terms</title>

  <para>This glossary contains definitions for manufacturing and technical
  terms used within the xTuple ERP user guide. If a definition below contains
  unfamiliar terms, please look elsewhere in the glossary for additional
  information. To see terms used in context, consult the index.</para>

  <!--
  <glosslist>
  -->

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>abc class</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>ABC Classification</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A method for grouping together items having similar transaction
      value. Those items having the greatest transaction value are considered
      class A items, while those having the least transaction value are
      considered class C items. The acronym ABC stands for activity-based
      costing.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>absolute calendars</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Absolute Calendar</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A type of calendar consisting of fixed time periods with specific
      dates defining the periods. Distinguished from a relative calendar,
      whose periods are not fixed but are defined in relation to a point in
      time. The following example illustrates the kind of fixed time period to
      be found in an absolute calendar: 01/01/2002 to 03/31/2002.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>accounts payable</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Accounts Payable</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Refers to amounts due to vendors for credit purchases.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>accounts receivable</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Accounts Receivable</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Refers to amounts due from customers for credit sales.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>actual costs</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Actual Cost</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The real-time cost associated with an item, including current
      material and production charges. The actual cost of an item may
      fluctuate given changes in the cost for materials, or other costs
      related to changes in bills of materials or routings. The actual cost
      provides a current record of charges actually incurred by an item. By
      comparing the actual cost to the standard cost, managers can determine
      whether costing and production goals are being met.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>xtuple administrators</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Administrator</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An administrator is a person charged with maintaining the correct
      functioning of an xTuple ERP installation. Sometimes called a systems
      administrator, an xTuple ERP administrator monitors the software,
      maintains users, and performs other important technical tasks.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>item aliases</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Alias</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Also known as an item alias, an alias provides a means for
      cross-referencing internal and external customer item information. For
      example, a customer may refer to an item by a different item number than
      you do. To avoid confusion and to simplify item lookups you can create
      an item alias linking the customer's external item number to your own
      internal item number. The item alias acts as a substitute or alternate
      identifier. In this way, items may be located using either internal or
      external item information. Multiple aliases can be assigned to one item,
      allowing you to cross-reference an item using many different item
      numbers.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>alignment pages</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Alignment Page</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A formatted grid template printed from within the
      <guimenu>System</guimenu> module. Alignment pages are used during the
      creation of report definitions to ensure reports print correctly on your
      local or network printer.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>allocation</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>inventory</primary>

        <secondary>allocation defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Allocation</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A term used to describe the status of inventory quantity. Quantity
      in an item site is considered allocated if either of the following two
      conditions exist: 1) The quantity is required by an unissued work order
      material requirement, or 2) the quantity is required by an unissued
      sales order line item. Once either requirement is issued, the quantity
      is no longer considered allocated; instead, the quantity is considered
      to be relieved.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>allowable parts</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Allowable Part</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Designation given to an item that may be stored in a restricted
      site location.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm>APICS</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Originally an acronym for the American Production and Inventory
      Control Society, the organization is now known as APICS: The Educational
      Society for Resource Management.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>application programming interfaces</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>API</primary>

        <see>application programming interfaces</see>
      </indexterm>Application Programming Interface (API)</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A set of tools and protocols used by software programmers to
      enable disparate software applications to communicate with each
      other.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>ARBL</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>ARBL</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A naming convention designed to maximize specificity in the naming
      of site locations. The acronym stands for aisle, rack, bin,
      location.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>available to promise</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>ATP</primary>

        <see>available to promise</see>
      </indexterm>Available to Promise</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Uncommitted inventory quantity available to support new sales
      orders or the difference between sales orders already booked and the
      quantity that operations is planning to produce.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>available qoh</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>inventory</primary>

        <secondary>available qoh defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Available QOH</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A term used to describe inventory that is available immediately to
      satisfy work order and sales order demand. Available quantity on hand
      (QOH) is the same as usable QOH.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>available qty</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>Inventory</primary>

        <secondary>available qty defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Available Qty.</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Also known as availability, this term describes inventory that
      considers future demands and orders. The following formula can be used
      to define available qty.: </para>

      <para>Usable QOH + (future supplies within the time horizon) - (demands
      within the time horizon).</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>authentication</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Authentication</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A computer security measure used in networked settings to verify
      the identity of users attempting to connect to a system.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>average costing</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Average Cost</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A costing approach where cost distribution is based on an average
      of all costs accumulated.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>backflush</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Backflush</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The automatic deduction from inventory of component item
      quantities executed at the time production is posted for a work order.
      In xTuple ERP, backflushing is synonymous with the pull issue method.
      Issue methods are assigned to component items within a bill of
      materials.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>backlog</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Backlog</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Refers to sales orders that have either not yet been shipped or
      have been shipped but are not yet invoiced.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>backorders</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Backorder</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Refers to unshipped line items on a shipped sales order. For
      example, if a customer orders three line items, but only one of the line
      items is shipped, the remaining two line items would be on
      backorder.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>bar codes</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Bar Code</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An alternating series of vertical bars and white spaces of varying
      widths used to encode information that can be read by electronic
      scanners. Bar codes increase efficiency and greatly limit data entry
      errors. Standard bar code formats supported by xTuple ERP include the
      following: Code 3of9, Code 3of9 Extended, Code 128, UPC-A, UPC-E, EAN-8,
      EAN-13.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>batch manager</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Batch Manager</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A utility within the <guimenu>System</guimenu> module which
      enables users to manage server-intensive requests, including, for
      example, database queries, reorder level updates, and large print
      jobs.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>bills of lading</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Bill of Lading (BOL)</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A document issued by a carrier to a shipper which lists and
      acknowledges the contents of a shipment to be transported by the
      carrier. A bill of lading (BOL) specifies terms of delivery and serves
      as a contract between carrier and shipper.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>bills of materials</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Bill of Materials (BOM)</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A list of component parts and specified quantities required to
      manufacture an item.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>bills of operations</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Routing</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A sequential list of operations required to manufacture an
      item.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>bill-to names</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Bill-To Name</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The name of the customer to be billed for a sales order. In some
      cases, the bill-to name on a sales order will differ from the ship-to
      name on the same order.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>purchase orders</primary>

        <secondary>blanket defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Blanket P/O</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A term used to describe customer purchase orders which may be used
      for more than one sales order.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>bookings</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Booking</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Any open, invoiced, or closed sales order line item. Because
      bookings represent both active and past customer demand, sales order
      line items that have been deleted before any activity is registered are
      not considered bookings.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>breeder bills of materials</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Breeder Bill of Materials</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A bill of materials for a breeder item, showing a list of
      by-products and any associated co-products.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>breeder items</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Breeder Item</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A logical item from which co-products and by-products are
      produced. An example use for a breeder item is the screening of raw
      gravel to produce different sizes of gravel. The breeder item's bill of
      materials (BOM) defines the inputs in this case raw gravel and the
      outputs are defined on its breeder BOM (i.e., small, medium and large
      gravel). A work order is created for the breeder item, but this item is
      never stocked or produced; again, it is a logical item. Instead, raw
      gravel is consumed by the breeder's work order, along with labor, and
      the resulting quantities of co-products and by-products are
      recorded.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>buy cards</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Buy Card</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A list, formerly recorded on a card, showing an historical record
      of items bought from specified vendors.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>by-products</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>By-Product</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An item of value that is produced as a result of operations being
      performed on a breeder item.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>capacity buffer</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>buffers</primary>

        <secondary>capacity defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Capacity Buffer</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The relative load of a resource compared to the desired lead time
      of items coming out of that resource. For example, suppose we have a
      shop with a typical lead time of two weeks that has a milling department
      heavily loaded. Perhaps we have identified milling as our shop's
      bottleneck and will use the buffer management system to monitor it. The
      capacity buffer would be two-weeks worth of load, meaning that the
      milling department can be loaded with up to two-weeks worth of work
      before it is considered fully-consumed. The capacity buffer size is
      entered as "Max Days Load" by the user when they run the capacity buffer
      status report. When the <guimenuitem>Buffer</guimenuitem> column in the
      display for milling equals 100 we know it is fully consumed.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>capacity planning</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Capacity Planning</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The process used to determine how much labor, machinery, and other
      resources will be required to manufacture current products and/or new
      products in the future.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>carriers</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Carrier</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A transportation company responsible for transporting shipments
      from one location to another.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm>Character</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Any alphanumeric character both upper and lower case including
      punctuation marks, white space, and other keyboard symbols.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>characteristics</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Characteristic</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>User-defined definition of an item which may be used to provide
      additional layers of description to an item. For example, item
      characteristics might be used to specify season or primary vendor. These
      constitute static descriptions which are not processed by xTuple ERP,
      but are useful for informational purposes.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>child items</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Child Item</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A synonym for component item.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>class codes</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Class Code</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An inventory control mechanism used for categorizing items
      regardless of item type. Distinguished from product category, which
      categorizes sold items only.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>commissions</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Commission</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The percentage of a sales order's value paid to a sales
      representative for services rendered.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>components</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Component</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An item that is required for the production of another item.
      Components are the items listed on a bill of materials. Also known as
      component item.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>items</primary>

        <secondary>configured defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Configured Item</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A manufactured item that may have item options added to it.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>control methods</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Control Method</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A designation which regulates how an item site handles inventory
      transactions. Item sites may be controlled by the following methods:
      regular, lot number, serial number, or none.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>co-products</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Co-Product</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An item that is processed at the same time as a breeder item,
      leading to the production of by-products. Co-products may absorb some of
      the costs associated with the production of by-products.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>cost categories</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Cost Category</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A classification applied to item sites which specifies how costs
      should be distributed to the general ledger whenever inventory is
      received, moved, consumed, produced, shipped, scrapped, or
      returned.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>costing elements</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Costing Element</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A term used to describe a specific type of cost incurred by items.
      The following costing elements exemplify some of these specific costs:
      material, labor, overhead. Costing elements may be system-defined or
      user-defined.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>count slips</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Count Slip</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A tool used to contribute inventory count totals to a count
      tag.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>count tags</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Count Tag</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The tool used to spearhead inventory counts. A count tag collects
      inventory count totals either independently or from affiliated count
      slips to determine the actual quantity on hand (QOH) for an individual
      item. When posted, the count tag total replaces the QOH balance
      displayed in the system.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>credit memos</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Credit Memo</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An accounting mechanism used to confirm that items have been
      returned by a customer or that an allowance has been made to a customer.
      Confirmation results in a debit to the customer's accounts receivable
      account. Sales order credit memos are used to issue credit for sold
      inventory. Receivables credit memos are miscellaneous, meaning they are
      not tied to a specific sales order.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>cumulative schedules</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Cumulative Schedules (MPS)</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Cumulative schedules allow the forced accumulation of inventory in
      a discontinuous, or lumpy, demand situation where load leveling or
      continuous production is desired. With this setting, MPS may release
      more, but never less, than the quantity dictated in a cumulative MPS
      schedule.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>customers</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Customer</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A purchaser who buys the items and services you sell.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>cycle counts</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Cycle Count</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A cycle count is a periodic issue of a count tag to count
      inventory quantity within an item site. The frequency of cycle counts is
      defined at the item site level. Because cycle counts may be conducted
      frequently, they provide better visibility into inventory levels than
      annual inventory counts.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>cycle counters</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>cycle counts</primary>

        <secondary>cycle counters defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Cycle Counter</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An employee whose job it is to perform cycle counts.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>cycle count tags</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>cycle counts</primary>

        <secondary>cycle count tags defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Cycle Count Tags</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The count tags created when a cycle count is performed.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>data caches</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Data Cache</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A computer storage area where commonly used information can be
      stored to facilitate the retrieval and use of that information.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm>Data Entry</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The process of typing information into fields found on xTuple ERP
      screens.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>data entry formats</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Data Entry Format</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Refers to the combination of keyboard characters supported by
      xTuple ERP data entry fields. Any data entered into a field must
      correspond to the format supported by that field. For example, date
      formats must be entered into date fields. Monetary formats must be
      entered into monetary fields. Some fields have no format restrictions
      and allow an unlimited number of alphanumeric characters. Data entry
      formats may differ from locale to locale.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>databases</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Database</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A collection of electronic information that is organized to allow
      for the rapid storage and retrieval of information. A digital filing
      system.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>debit memos</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Debit Memo</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An accounting mechanism used to debit a customer's accounts
      receivable accounts. Debit memos are not tied to a specific sales order.
      They may be used as miscellaneous receivables invoices.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>destinations</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Destination</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The geographic location where a shipment is received.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm>Display</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An on-screen representation of an xTuple ERP report.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>dispositions</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Disposition</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The method in which a return material authorization will be
      handled.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry id="glossary.DTD">
    <glossterm><indexterm>
        <primary>DTD</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>DTD</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A DTD is a document type definition. It is the part of the world
      wide web consortium's standard definition of XML which is used to
      describe valid XML document formats.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>effectivity</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Effectivity</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The period of time within which an item is considered valid. An
      effectivity period is usually defined by effective and expiration dates.
      Effectivity applies to components in a bill of materials, operations in
      a routing, and prices on a pricing schedule.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>effort</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Effort</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The amount of time a user spends clocked-in to a work order
      divided by the number of work orders the user is working on at the same
      time.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>electronic data interchange</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Electronic Data Interchange (EDI)</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A system for exchanging information electronically between
      businesses, using the Internet.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>engineering change notices</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Engineering Change Notice (ECN)</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Notification given by product engineers signifying that changes
      have been made to the design or configuration of a manufactured
      item.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>event fences</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Event Fence</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A setting on the Item Site master specifying the period of time,
      measured in days, within which event notifications related to the item
      site should be issued. If an event affecting the item site occurs within
      the event fence, then the system will issue a notification.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>events</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Event</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Any one of a limited set of possible occurrences precipitated by
      user activity which xTuple ERP defines as having special importance. For
      example, an event has occurred if QOH for an item falls below zero, if a
      work order is created, if a sales order line item is cancelled, etc. An
      event may trigger an event notification, depending on a user's
      preference settings. For a complete list of system-defined events, see
      <xref linkend="appendixa"/>.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>event notification</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Event notification</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A system-generated alert sent to a user whenever an event the user
      subscribes to occurs.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>event manager</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Event Manager</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A utility within the <guimenu>System</guimenu> module which
      enables users to view and manage their event notifications.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>execution days</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Execution Day</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A setting within an Operation screen associated with either a
      routing or a work order which defines when the specified operation
      should begin. For example, if the value "1" is entered in the
      <guilabel>Execution Day</guilabel> field, the operation will begin on
      the first day of the manufacturing process. If "2" is entered, the
      operation will begin on the second day, etc.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>expedite exceptions</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Expedite Exception</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An indication that an order is late. These late orders need to be
      acted on or expedited. Examples of late orders would include a work
      order whose start date is past due or a planned purchase order which has
      not yet been released.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>expense categories</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Expense Category</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A classification used for assigning purchasing expenses to
      specified general ledger accounts. Expense categories are only used for
      non-inventory items.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>explosion</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Explosion</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The process whereby work order material requirements and work
      order operations are created for a work order.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>fields</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Field</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Refers to those areas found on xTuple ERP screens where data can
      be entered. Examples include item number fields, date fields, comment
      fields, etc.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>firming</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Firm</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A process whereby planned orders are solidified in the schedule.
      When you specify that a planned order is firm, you are indicating that
      material requirements planning (MRP) should not delete it when running
      planned replenishment orders unless specifically told to do so.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>firmed orders</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Firmed Order</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A planned order that has been firmed in the schedule. Also known
      as firm planned order.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>fiscal years</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Fiscal Year</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The accounting year for a company. May or may not coincide with
      the calendar year.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>forward-updating</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Forward-Update</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A process either automatic or manual which carries the ending
      balance for an accounting period forward through to the current account
      period.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>free on board</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Free On Board (FOB)</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The point at which ownership of goods being shipped transfers from
      the seller to the buyer. Also the point at which the buyer assumes
      responsibility for transportation costs and risks.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>freezing</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Freezing</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A mechanism for temporarily locking quantity on hand (QOH) values
      at item sites to facilitate inventory counting and ensure accurate
      totals. When an item site is frozen, any inventory transactions entered
      against that item site including work orders will not affect the QOH for
      that item site. Because of this, inventory counting can proceed using a
      fixed baseline total. When the item site is thawed, any post-freeze
      activity is reconciled, bringing the QOH total to its correct value. The
      freezing/thawing mechanism is designed to ensure you get accurate
      inventory counts without having to shut down operations. Term is also
      applied to accounting periods. When an accounting period is frozen, only
      users granted the privilege of posting to a frozen period can do so.
      Once an accounting period is closed it can no longer be posted
      into.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>freight</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Freight</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The contents of a shipment.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>general ledger</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>General Ledger (GL)</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The accounting record which lists all the accounts used by a
      company.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>hold</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Hold</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A sales order control which enables agents to delay the packing or
      shipping of sales order line items.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>implosion</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Implosion</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The process whereby a work order's material requirements and work
      order operations are deleted. Only work orders with exploded (E) status
      can be imploded. Released (R) or in-process (I) work orders cannot be
      imploded. When a work order is imploded, its status changes to open
      (O).</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>input mask</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Input Mask</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A template typically featuring separator characters used to guide
      users doing data entry. A form of light data validation.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>insufficient Inventory</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>Inventory</primary>

        <secondary>insufficiency defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Insufficient Inventory</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Inventory is considered insufficient if existing quantity on hand
      (QOH) will not meet the specified demand; however, replenishment orders
      do exist in the system—and, once these replenishment orders are
      received, the demand will be satisfied. Insufficient inventory will have
      positive availability, distinguishing it from short inventory, whose
      availability is negative.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>Inventory</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Inventory</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Refers to items a company owns and expects to either sell or
      consume as part of its normal operations.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>invoices</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Invoice</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A printed list of items sold to a customer. Also serves as a bill
      sent to the customer.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>issue methods</primary>

        <secondary>term defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Issue Method</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The means by which component items are deducted from inventory for
      work order processing. The issue method a component item assumes is
      determined at the bill of materials level. xTuple ERP recognizes three
      issue methods: pull, push, and mixed.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>items</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Item</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Any unique product, material, subassembly, or part, whether
      purchased or manufactured.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>item controls</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Item Controls</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A series of specifications applied to an item at the item site
      level. Examples of item controls include ABC class designation, cycle
      count frequency, and reorder level limits.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>item images</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Item Image</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An electronic graphics file which may be linked with an item in
      the Item master. An item image may be a visual representation (i.e.,
      photograph) of an item or any related graphic. xTuple ERP supports the
      following image file types: .PNG, .XPM, .JPG, or .GIF.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>item options</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Item Option</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An add-on, attribute, or quantity which may be assigned to a
      configured item.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>item sites</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Item Site</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An item site identifies and defines the methods and controls used
      when maintaining a given item within a given site.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>item sources</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Item Source</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A vendor who supplies a given item to a company. Because multiple
      vendors may supply a single item, a single item may have multiple item
      sources.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>item substitutes</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Item Substitute</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An item which may be used as a replacement for another
      item.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>job items</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Job Item</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A manufactured item used specifically for make-to-order scenarios
      where simplified production is required. The <guimenuitem>Job
      Costing</guimenuitem> option at the item site level is used to
      distinguish job items from regular manufactured items. Job items cannot
      be maintained in inventory. And they also have no concept of standard
      cost or cost variances. All costs for job items are actual. The work
      orders which create job items can only be created via a sales order. The
      costs for job work orders are accumulated to WIP, and then transferred
      directly to cost of sales when the job is shipped. Bill of material and
      routing items may be assigned to job items; however, they will not roll
      up to a standard cost for job items.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>keyboard shortcuts</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Keyboard Shortcut</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An alternative method for performing computer operations using the
      keyboard instead of the mouse. An example of a keyboard shortcut would
      be <guibutton>CTRL + S</guibutton>. Selecting the
      <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key on the keyboard followed by the
      <guibutton>S</guibutton> key will in many cases perform a
      <guibutton>SAVE</guibutton> operation. This same operation could be
      handled by pulling down the <guibutton>FILE</guibutton> menu and
      selecting <guibutton>SAVE</guibutton>, using the mouse.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>key files</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Key File</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A service-independent encryption seed file, which enables you to
      read encrypted credit card information.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>kits</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Kit</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An item type that automatically explodes bill of material items on
      to a sales order for shipping.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>label forms</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Label Form</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A report definition that prints supported label types.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>labor rates</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Labor Rate</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The cost charged by a work center per hour for labor. A setup
      labor rate is charged for preparing a work center to run an operation,
      and a run labor rate is charged for executing the operation. Routinely
      performed operations may be assigned a standard labor rate.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>lead times</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Lead Time</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An item control which specifies the number of days required to
      either procure or manufacture an item. For purchased items, lead time
      refers to days required to procure. For manufactured items, lead time
      refers to days required to produce. Lead times are specified at the item
      site level.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>list prices</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>List Price</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The stated selling price for a sold item. Also known as the
      catalog price.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>locales</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Locale</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A mechanism for defining certain display formats based on
      linguistic and cultural conventions. For example, the manner in which
      currency, date, and price formats are displayed is controlled by locale
      settings. xTuple ERP supports multiple locales.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>locations</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Location</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A physical location within a site for example, a bin, shelf,
      aisle, etc. Also known as site location.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>lots</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>lots</primary>

        <secondary>numbering of defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Lot Number</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A unique identifier assigned to a series or batch of items
      produced at the same time which share the same specifications.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>lower level</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Lower Level</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The component level. For example, lower level costs are associated
      with component items.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>make-to-order</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>items</primary>

        <secondary>make-to-order defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Make-to-Order</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An adjective describing a production process in which an item is
      manufactured after a sales order requests the item. If an item is
      make-to-order, the <guilabel>Stocked At</guilabel> flag in the Item Site
      master is turned off. When sales orders are issued for make-to-order
      items, Purchase requests or work orders will automatically be generated
      to meet sales order demand.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>make-to-stock</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>items</primary>

        <secondary>make-to-stock defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Make-to-Stock</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An adjective describing a production process in which an item is
      typically manufactured before sales orders for the item are received. If
      an item is make-to-order, the <guilabel>Stocked At</guilabel> flag in
      the Item Site master is turned on. When sales orders are issued for
      make-to-stock items, purchase requests will not be generated.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>man hours</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Man Hour</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The labor of one worker for one hour.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>manufactured</primary>

        <secondary>item type defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Manufactured Item</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An item that is made, assembled, or otherwise produced.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>master production scheduling</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Master Production Scheduling (MPS)</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The process of planning production to meet the demands of current
      and forecasted orders.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>master scheduling</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Master Scheduling</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A synonym for master production scheduling.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>material receipts</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Material Receipt</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An inventory transaction that records the receiving of items into
      inventory.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>material requirements planning</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Material Requirements Planning (MRP)</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A time-phased approach used to calculate the materials required to
      fulfill the master production schedule (MPS). The MRP calculation is
      made by exploding the material requirements for current and planned
      orders, with adjustments made for both existing quantity on hand (QOH)
      and specified lead times. Where shortages are found or anticipated,
      replenishment orders are recommended. Also, orders are recommended for
      rescheduling wherever inventory is found to be insufficient to meet the
      MPS.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>metacharacters</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Metacharacter</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Special keyboard character used to facilitate pattern matching.
      Sometimes referred to as a wildcard.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>mixed</primary>

        <secondary>issue method defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Mixed</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A material issue method which declares that a component item is
      expected to take upon itself the issue method applied to it initially at
      the time of work order explosion. If the component item is pulled to a
      work order initially, then the issue method for that item will remain
      pull in the work order material requirements. If the item is initially
      pushed to a work order, its issue method will remain push. The mixed
      issue method allows for flexibility in the building of work order
      material requirements.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>multiple location control</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Multiple Location Control (MLC)</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A setting defined at the item site level which indicates that item
      quantities for an item may be maintained in more than a single site
      location.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>netable qoh</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Netable QOH</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A term used to describe inventory that is allowed to be used for
      inventory planning purposes (i.e., MRP). All quantities (usable and
      non-usable) outside of non-netable locations are considered part of
      netable quantity on hand (QOH).</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>netable location</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Netable Location</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A term for a location where the inventory is considered
      netable.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>non-netable qoh</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Non-Netable QOH</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A term used to describe inventory that is not to be used for
      inventory planning purposes (i.e., MRP). Only quantities located in
      non-netable locations are considered part of non-netable quantity on
      hand (QOH).</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>non-netable location</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Non-Netable Location</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A term for a location where the inventory is considered
      non-netable.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>non-usable qoh</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Non-Usable QOH</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A term used to describe inventory which is not available for
      issuing to sales orders or work orders. For example, inventory waiting
      to be scrapped may be flagged as non-usable.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>on order</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>Inventory</primary>

        <secondary>on order defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>On Order</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A term used to describe the status of inventory quantity. Quantity
      in an item site is considered on order if either of the following two
      conditions exist: 1.) the quantity is expected via an unreceived
      purchase order line item, or 2.) the quantity is expected via an
      unreceived work order. Once either quantity is received, the quantity is
      no longer considered on order.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>operations</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Operation</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A job, task, or process required for the production of an item.
      Operations are defined sequentially in a routing. The routing may be
      modified at the work order stage, where work order operations may be
      defined. Operations are performed in work centers.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>opportunities</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Opportunity</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A favorable chance for booking sales revenue.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>order parameters</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Order Parameter</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A series of specifications applied to an item at the item site
      level which are used by material requirements planning (MRP) when
      generating MRP planned replenishment orders. Examples of order
      parameters include reorder level, order up to level, and lead
      time.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>order up to levels</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Order Up To Level (OUT)</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Indicates the level of planned availability an item site should be
      replenished up to when material requirements planning (MRP) is run. In
      cases where the reorder level for an item site exceeds the order up to
      (OUT) level, MRP will replenish the item site up to the reorder level.
      OUT levels are defined on the Item Site master.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>outside processes</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Outside Process</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An external process or service that is performed by someone (i.e.,
      a vendor) outside your company. An item type. Outside process items are
      treated by the system in much the same way as purchased items are. For
      example, outside process items will be handled in the same way as
      purchased items are when material requirements planning (MRP) is
      run.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>overhead</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Overhead</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The costs associated with the provision and maintenance of a
      manufacturing facility. These costs include but are not limited to costs
      related to building rental, utilities, machinery, supervision,
      maintenance, etc.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>packages</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Packages</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Compressed files which may contain either a.) custom software
      designed to extend the functionality of xTuple ERP without touching the
      core xTuple ERP source code or b.) upgrade bundles designed to migrate
      xTuple ERP databases from one version to the next.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>packing lists</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Packing List</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A document indicating the items that need to be picked for a sales
      order.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>parameters</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Parameter</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A definition or limit used to shape a query. See also, order
      parameter.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>parent items</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Parent Item</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A top-level manufactured item. Refers to both root items and also
      the top-level items in subassemblies. Component items are the children
      of the parent item.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>shipping</primary>

        <secondary>partial defined</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>partial shipments</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Partial Shipment</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A shipped order having a line item whose full quantity is not
      included in the shipment. For example, if customer ABC orders 20 units
      of item XYZ, but only 10 units are shipped, that partial line item
      quantity (10) would constitute a partial shipment of the ordered
      item.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>pattern matching</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Pattern Matching</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A method for shaping database queries using regular expressions to
      improve the precision of results. xTuple ERP supports pattern matching
      using regular expressions in accordance with the portable operating
      system interface (POSIX) standard.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>phantoms</primary>

        <secondary>item type defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Phantom Item</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An item type used to classify items that are commonly used
      together during a manufacturing process.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>pick lists</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Pick List</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A printed list showing the work order material requirements for a
      specified work order. A pick list is part of a bill of materials.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>planned availability</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Planned Availability</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A synonym for availability.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>planned expenses</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Planned Expense</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A projected cost arising from the master production schedule
      (MPS).</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>planned orders</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Planned Order</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Planned orders are a vehicle used by master production scheduling
      (MPS) and material requirements planning (MRP) to create soft demands
      for materials and capacity required to meet the production plan. These
      planned orders are converted to actual work orders or purchase orders as
      their lead time approaches.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>planned revenues</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Planned Revenue</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Projected income arising from the master production schedule
      (MPS).</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>planners</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Planner</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Those employees of a company responsible for planning, scheduling,
      or procurement.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>planner codes</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Planner Code</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A planning mechanism designed to categorize items within
      designated codes.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>ports</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Port</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An entrance to or exit from a data network.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>POSIX</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Portable Operating System Interface (POSIX)</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An international standard defining how applications obtain the
      basic services of an operating system.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>postgresql</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>PostgreSQL</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An enterprise-class object-oriented relational database management
      system (ORDBMS). The premiere open source database.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>pricing schedules</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Pricing Schedule</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A grouping of sold items indicating the prices assigned for
      specified quantity breaks. Pricing schedules may be assigned to
      individual customers or to groups of customers by customer type.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>privileges</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Privilege</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A security measure designed to regulate through authorization the
      activity of users connected to a computer network or system. Typically,
      a user is able to perform an action if the privilege to perform that
      action has been granted to the user. If not granted the privilege, the
      user will be prevented from performing the action. Sometimes referred to
      as permission.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>product categories</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Product Category</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A classification used to categorize sold items. Distinguished from
      class code, which categorizes items regardless of item type.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>production</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Production</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The process whereby subcomponents are converted into manufactured
      items.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>production plans</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Production Plan</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A mechanism used for loading sales forecasts into the system. The
      master production scheduling (MPS) system accounts for production plans
      when MPS is run.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>prospects</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Prospect</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A potential customer.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>proximo</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Proximo</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A billing term used to specify that payment is expected on a
      certain day of the month as in the 15th or the last day of the
      month.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>pull</primary>

        <secondary>issue method defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Pull</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An inventory issue method in which component items are
      automatically deducted from inventory at the time of work order
      explosion. Synonymous with backflushing.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>pull-through</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Pull-through</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A term used to describe the backflushing of work order
      operations.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>purchase orders</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Purchase Order</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A written authorization used to formalize purchase transactions
      with vendors.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>purchase requests</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Purchase Request</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An internal notification used to alert purchasing agents of the
      need to purchase materials.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>purchased</primary>

        <secondary>item type defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Purchased Item</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An item that is bought from vendors.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>push</primary>

        <secondary>issue method defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Push</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An inventory issue method in which component items must be
      specifically selected for issuance to a work order.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>quantity on hand</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Quantity on Hand (QOH)</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The total of all inventory regardless of status. Quantity on hand
      (QOH) includes usable, non-usable, netable, and non-netable
      inventory.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>quotes</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Quote</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A statement issued to a customer indicating pricing and sales
      terms for specified quantities of sold items. Often a precursor to a
      sales order.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>quantity breaks</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Quantity Break</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The minimum quantity of an item that must be purchased in order to
      receive a specified price. Quantity breaks are used in both sales order
      and purchase order pricing.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>queries</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Query</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A request for information issued to a database.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>receiving</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Receiving</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The business function responsible for the receipt of materials
      into inventory.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>regular expressions</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Regular Expression</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A combination of characters and metacharacters used in pattern
      matching to shape database queries. Also known as Regex.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>reject codes</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Reject Code</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A means for labeling purchased items when and if they are returned
      to the vendor who supplied them. A reject code explains why an item is
      being returned.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>relative calendars</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Relative Calendar</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A type of calendar in which periods are defined in relation to a
      point in time. Examples of points in time that a relative calendar
      period might be defined in relation to include the following:
      <guilabel>Current Day</guilabel> or <guilabel>Beginning of Current Month
      </guilabel>or <guilabel>Beginning of Next Quarter</guilabel>. Relative
      calendars are considered more flexible than absolute calendars because
      their periods do not describe static, fixed points in time.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>Inventory</primary>

        <secondary>relief of defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Relieved</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A term used to describe the status of allocated inventory
      quantity. Allocated quantity is considered relieved if either of the
      following two conditions exist: 1) quantity allocated to a work order
      material requirement has been issued, or 2) quantity allocated to a
      sales order line item has been issued.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>reorder exceptions</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Reorder Exception</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An indication that an item site's projected availability will drop
      below the reorder level for the item site—or to zero or below if no
      reorder level exists. Reorder exceptions are a type of event.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>reorder levels</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Reorder Level</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Specifies when a planned replenishment order should be created for
      an item site. If planned availability falls below the reorder level,
      then a replenishment order will be created when material requirements
      planning (MRP) is run. The quantity of the replenishment order will be
      enough to restore planned availability back to the reorder level or to
      the order up to (OUT) level, if the OUT level is greater. Reorder levels
      are defined on the Item Site master.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>replenishment orders</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Replenishment Order</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A planned order issued by material requirements planning (MRP) to
      resupply an item whose available quantity has fallen below its reorder
      level at the point when MRP is run.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>reports</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Report</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Printed information showing the results of a query run against a
      database.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>restricted</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Restricted</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A term used to describe site locations. If a location is
      restricted, only items specifically assigned to the location may be
      stored there. If a location is not restricted, it will accept any items
      from the same site.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>revision</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Revision</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An independent, historical snapshot of an entire bill of materials
      or routing that will be permanently saved.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm>RMA Hold</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A hold status for replacement sales orders that prevents items
      from being issued to shipping if the receipt of all original goods is
      required first.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>root items</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Root Item</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An item that is not the child of another other item. A top-level
      manufactured item, for example.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>rough-cut capacity plans</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Rough-Cut Capacity Plan</glossterm></glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The plan that results when the master production schedule is
      converted into specific requirements.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>routings</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Routing</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A printed list showing the work order operations for a specified
      work order.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>run time</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Run Time</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The amount of time required to complete an operation for a
      manufactured item.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>safety stock</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Safety Stock</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The quantity of stock for an item you want to keep in inventory to
      protect against unplanned, unforeseeable trends in your order
      forecasts.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>sales orders</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Sales Order</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An order placed by a customer for the purchase of sold
      items.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>sales representatives</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Sales Representative</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A representative to whom sales orders may be credited and
      commissions paid.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>scrap</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Scrap</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Inventory that is damaged and cannot be used. Also, work order
      material that cannot be used during the production of a work
      order.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>serial numbers</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Serial Number</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A unique number used to identify a particular item.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>servers</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Server</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A computer or process which provides resources and services to
      other computers connected to the network.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>service Item</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Service Item</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An item type used for situations where the cost is variable. Work
      orders for service items are always linked to sales orders. They are not
      received into inventory or closed via the manufacturing interface, but
      rather closed when linked sales order lines are shipped. WIP accumulated
      for service work will be posted to cost of sales at shipping.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>setup time</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Setup Time</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The amount of time required to prepare a work center for the
      performance of an operation. Setup time is charged only once per
      operation, regardless of the quantity ordered.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>shipping</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Shipping</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The business function responsible for the outgoing shipment of
      goods.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>shipping contents</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Shipping Contents</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The inventory contained in the shipping WIP for a given
      site.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>shipping zones</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Shipping Zone</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A defined geographic region, which can be used to perform sales
      analysis.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>ship-to addresses</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Ship-To Address</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An address to which sales order items are shipped. Customers may
      maintain multiple ship-to addresses.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>ship vias</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Ship Via</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The means to be used for shipping a sales order.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>shortage</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>Inventory</primary>

        <secondary>shortage defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Shortage</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A term used to describe inventory whose availability is
      negative.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>sites</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Site</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A physical production or storage facility.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>site locations</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Site Location</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A physical location within a site for example, a bin, shelf,
      aisle, etc. Also known as a location.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>site zones</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Site Zone</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A defined section or area within a site. For example, separate
      site zones might be designated to define areas where orders are
      selected, picked, and packed.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm>Sold Item</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An item that can be sold to customers.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>sold ranking</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Sold Ranking</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Specifies the order in which item sites will be chosen during
      sales order and quote creation.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>ssl</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>SSL</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An acronym for secure sockets layer. SSL is a security protocol
      designed to provide communications privacy for client/server
      applications like xTuple ERP which communicate over the Internet.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>standard costs</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Standard Cost</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The cost used for posting general ledger transactions. Standard
      cost is distinguished from actual cost in the sense that standard cost
      is fixed, whereas actual cost is subject to fluctuations arising from
      material or production changes. The two costs may diverge. However, they
      can be brought back into alignment by posting actual cost to standard.
      Differences between standard and actual costs can be used by managers to
      determine whether costing and production goals are being met.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>standard journals</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Standard Journal</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Used to define reoccurring general ledger (G/L) entries.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>standard journal groups</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Standard Journal Group</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Used to define groups of standard journals that are often posted
      together, such as during period end.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>standard labor rates</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Standard Labor Rate</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A labor rate used by work centers for standard, defined job
      positions.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>standard operations</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Standard Operation</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A template that describes an operation which may be used in
      multiple routings.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>stock buffer</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>buffers</primary>

        <secondary>stock defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Stock Buffer</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An accumulation of items stored in inventory that act as a hedge
      against demand where the required service time is shorter than a time
      buffer for that item would allow. For example: If we have a standard
      part that takes two weeks to produce, but which we must be able to ship
      in one day, we would stock that item to ensure the one-day service
      level. In another case, we may be able to produce the item in a day, but
      sometimes seasonal load changes result in a production bottleneck where
      the backlog on a critical resource for that item is greater than a day.
      The stock buffer allows us to continue shipping the item under those
      circumstances. It is important to note that due dates are irrelevant for
      orders with stock buffers. The buffer size is determined by the reorder
      level at the item site.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>subassemblies</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Subassembly</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A manufactured component item.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>tax authorities</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Tax Authority</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Any entity legally-authorized to collect taxes for example, city,
      county, state, or federal government agencies.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>tax codes</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Tax Code</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The rate used when taxes are applied to a transaction. Tax codes
      may contain one or multiple layers of taxation. For example, a single
      tax code might include only the rate for state tax; whereas, another tax
      code might combine both city, county, and state tax rates.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>tax registrations</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Tax Registration</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The registration number used by tax authorities to identify
      businesses and/or individuals. An employer identification numbers (EIN)
      is an example of a tax registration number.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>tax selections</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Tax Selection</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A matrix used to find the tax code to apply to an item given the
      item's tax type and the tax authority with jurisdiction over the
      transaction.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>tax types</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Tax Type</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A system for classifying goods and services into taxable
      categories.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>terms</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Terms</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Determines payment details for accounts payable and accounts
      receivable.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>thawing</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Thawing</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The process of unlocking QOH values at item sites that have been
      frozen for inventory counting purposes. See "freeze."</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>this level</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>This Level</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The parent item level. For example, this level costs are
      associated with the parent item they refer to.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>throughput</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Throughput</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Indicates the number of units, in the given item's inventory unit
      of measure (UOM), that can be produced in a minute and also the number
      of minutes that are required to produce one unit, expressed in the given
      item's inventory UOM.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>time buffer</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>buffers</primary>

        <secondary>time defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Time Buffer</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The lead time, measured in working days, of a supply order for an
      item that is not stocked. By working days we mean the days that the shop
      is available to work, which may exclude weekends or holidays. For
      example: If a shop typically has a three-week lead time, but does not
      work weekends, then the time buffer for that shop would typically be 15
      working days. The xTuple ERP constraint management system looks at the
      start and finish dates of a discrete purchase order or work order,
      removes non-working days for the order's site, and then calculates the
      time buffer.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>time fence</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Time Fence</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The time fence (also known as the demand fence) is used by the
      master production scheduling (MPS) system to evaluate when forecasted
      demand (i.e., from production plans) should be used in place of actual
      demand (i.e., from sales orders) and vice versa. Measured in days, the
      demand time fence is the period of time extending from the current day
      to the number of days into the future as specified in this field. The
      demand time fence option applies only to those items which currently
      appear on a released production plan. If demand for these items falls
      within the demand time fence period, then the forecast will be ignored.
      If demand falls outside the demand time fence, then the larger of actual
      or forecasted demand will be used. MPS responds to the demand it locates
      by creating firm planned orders for the required quantities.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>time-phased</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Time-Phased</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A reference to certain displays and reports which represent data
      in relation to specified calendar periods.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>toolbars</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Toolbar</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The row of icons or buttons near the top of the application
      desktop which activate functions when selected.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>tooling</primary>

        <secondary>item type defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Tooling Item</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A material resource used in the manufacturing process that is
      returned upon completion of a work order—for example, a reusable mold,
      apparatus, fixture, or tool. It may be included on a bill of materials
      (BOM) for an item, usually specifying a fixed quantity. Tooling items
      can be purchased, manufactured, or sold. A manufactured tool can have a
      routing, a BOM, and a work order. As with other material items, tools
      can be tracked as serialized items. The cost of a tooling item is not
      included in the overall cost of the parent item where it is used.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>transactions</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Transaction</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Any event involving a change in inventory value or status, and the
      resulting recording of such events in the general ledger (G/L). xTuple
      ERP recognizes both inventory transactions and G/L transactions. For a
      complete list of inventory transaction types, see <xref
      linkend="appendixa"/>.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>transit sites</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>sites</primary>

        <secondary>transit defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Transit Site</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A special site used by transfer orders used to account for
      in-transit inventory.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>transformations</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Transformation</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The process of converting quantity of one item into quantity of
      another item.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>travelers</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Traveler</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A collection of printed documents which accompanies a work order.
      Traveler documents may include the pick list, routing, or packing list.
      Also known as a work order traveler or shop traveler.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>unallocated</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Unallocated</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Describes the quantity on hand (QOH) remaining after allocations
      have been accounted for, as in: </para>

      <para>QOH - Allocated Qty. = Unallocated Qty. </para>

      <para>See also: Allocation.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>units of measure</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Unit of Measure (UOM)</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The standard amount in which quantities of an item are managed
      (e.g., each, pounds, gallons, etc.). In addition to its inventory unit
      of measure (UOM), an item may be maintained in multiple other UOMs,
      including shipping UOM, purchasing UOM, etc.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>usable qoh</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Usable QOH</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A term used to describe inventory that is available immediately to
      satisfy work order and sales order demand. Usable quantity on hand (QOH)
      is the same as available QOH.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>usage statistics</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Usage Statistics</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Records indicating inventory transaction activity.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>user preferences</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>User Preferences</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Controls found within the <guimenu>System</guimenu> module which
      users can manipulate to customize their interaction with xTuple ERP. For
      example, users may customize the appearance of their application desktop
      or specify the events they are subscribed to.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>utilities</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Utility</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A software tool designed to perform a specific function.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>validator</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Validator</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A formatting requirement used to strictly enforce data entry
      rules. If you specify a validator for a field, then users will have to
      conform to the format when entering data. Any data which does not
      conform will not be accepted.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>variances</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Variance</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>The difference between an expected result and an actual
      result.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>vendor ranking</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Vendor Ranking</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Specifies the order in which item sources will be chosen during
      purchase order creation.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>vendors</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Vendor</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A supplier of purchased items.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>vouchers</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Voucher</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A document authorizing payment to vendors who have either
      performed services or supplied goods. A voucher vouches for the fact
      that these goods or services have been provided.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>work in process</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>WIP</primary>

        <see>work in process</see>
      </indexterm>WIP</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An acronym for work in process. Refers to inventory in various
      stages of completion ranging from work order material requirements in
      production to packaged inventory awaiting shipment.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>work centers</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Work Center</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A collection of machines or labor that performs a specific task
      when building a manufactured item. Work centers are used by the routing
      to determine the amount of available and required manufacturing capacity
      to produce the manufactured item. Work centers also determine per-minute
      run and setup time costs. A single site may contain multiple work
      centers.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>work orders</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Work Order</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A document which demands the production of manufactured
      items.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>work order material requirements</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Work Order Material Requirement</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Indicates the quantity of a given component item that is required
      to complete the parent work order. A material requirement is derived by
      multiplying the work order quantity times the specifications set forth
      in the parent item's bill of materials (BOM). The BOM specifications may
      be altered at the work order level to fulfill the requirements of a
      particular work order.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>work order operations</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Work Order Operation</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>Indicates the amount of run and setup time at a given work center
      that is required to complete the parent work order. An operation is
      derived by multiplying the work order quantity times the specifications
      set forth in the parent item's routing. The routing specifications may
      be altered at the work order level to fulfill the requirements of a
      particular work order.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry id="glossary.XSLT">
    <glossterm><indexterm>
        <primary>XSLT</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>XSLT</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>An XML transformation language designed by the World Wide Web
      consortium as part of the extensible stylesheet language. This is
      supported by xTuple as a mechanism for importing data from XML files
      into the database. Files containing XSLT are often called
      <wordasword>stylesheets</wordasword>.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <glossentry>
    <glossterm><indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>zones</primary>

        <secondary>defined</secondary>
      </indexterm>Zone</glossterm>

    <glossdef>
      <para>A defined geographic region or specific site area. See shipping
      zone or site zone.</para>
    </glossdef>
  </glossentry>

  <!--
  </glosslist>
  -->
</glossary>
