<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="accountingPeriods">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>accounting periods</primary>

      <secondary>master list of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Accounting Periods</title>

  <para>Accounting periods contain transactional activity within clearly
  defined time periods—usually months. You will typically find twelve
  accounting periods within a fiscal year. An accounting period must be
  defined in order to post transactions to the general ledger. If no
  accounting period exists, transactions cannot be posted. It is likewise not
  possible to post transactions into closed accounting periods. You may only
  post into open accounting periods. Privileged users may post into frozen
  periods, but the frozen period must be open in order for the posting to
  succeed.</para>

  <note>
    <para>The privilege <literal>PostFrozenPeriod</literal> allows users who
    are granted this privilege to post transactions into frozen accounting
    periods. For transactions to post successfully, frozen periods must also
    be open.</para>
  </note>

  <para>To access the master list of accounting periods, go to
  <guimenuitem>Accounting &gt; Fiscal Calendar &gt; Accounting
  Periods</guimenuitem>. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/accountingPeriods.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Accounting Periods Master List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>The Accounting Periods screen displays information on all existing
  accounting periods, including period name, period start date, period end
  date, period number, period qtr, period year, closed status and frozen
  status.</para>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>CLOSE PERIOD</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an accounting period and then select this button to
        close the period. Transactions may not be posted into closed periods.
        To post transactions to a closed period, you must reopen the
        period.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>FREEZE PERIOD</guibutton></term>

      <listitem id="accountingPeriodsFREEZEPERIOD">
        <para>Highlight an accounting period and then select this button to
        freeze the period. Privileged users may post transactions into frozen
        periods, as long as the frozen period is open.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <xi:include href="accountingPeriod.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
