<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="accountingPeriod">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>accounting periods</primary>

      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Accounting Period</title>

  <para>To create a new accounting period, select the
  <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/accountingPeriod.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Create New Accounting Period</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating a new accounting period, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name to describe the accounting period. This name will
        be used as the period's column header text when a financial report is
        generated. If not specified, then the period's start and end dates
        will be used as the column header text. When a new period is added,
        the beginning and end dates default to the next logical month. Dates
        are not editable on periods with adjacent periods or when trial
        balance activity exists.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Start Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the start date for the accounting period. The start date
        is only editable if all periods are open—and the date must fall before
        the end date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>End Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the end date for the accounting period. The end date is
        only editable on a period when it is the last period and there is no
        trial balance activity in it.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Fiscal Year</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select a fiscal year from the drop down list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Number</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select the accounting period number. This feature provides the
        ability to customize your accounting periods so you're not limited to
        monthly accounting periods. For example, this feature adds support for
        4-4-5 Accounting.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Quarter</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select which quarter the accounting period belongs to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Closed</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate the accounting period is closed. You may not
        close an accounting period until a subsequent period has been created.
        Once a period is closed, transactions cannot be posted into it—unless
        the period is reopened first.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>The trial balances for an accounting period will automatically
    forward-update at the moment when an accounting period is either closed or
    created. Also, the system will automatically reset the beginning balances
    for revenue and expense accounts to $0 at the start of a new fiscal
    year.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Frozen</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate the accounting period is frozen. Trial
        balances may not be updated for accounting periods which are frozen
        except where the permission to post to frozen periods is granted. This
        restriction applies to all accounts. If this option is not selected,
        the accounting period is considered not frozen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
