<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="adjustmentTrans">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>miscellaneous adjustments</primary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>adjustments</primary>

      <secondary>miscellaneous for inventory</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>inventory</primary>

      <secondary>miscellaneous adjustments to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Adjustment Transaction</title>

  <para>To make a miscellaneous adjustment to the quantity on hand (QOH) for
  an item, select the "Adjustment Transaction" option. The following screen
  will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/adjustmentTrans_tabCost.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Enter Adjustment Transaction</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <note>
    <para>Use the Adjustment transaction utility to handle inventory
    adjustments not covered by another transaction type—for example, Receipt
    from Purchasing, Receipt from Manufacturing, Scrap, etc. For a complete
    list of inventory transaction Types, see <xref
    linkend="Section461282"/>.</para>
  </note>

  <para>When creating an Adjustment transaction, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Transaction Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date you want the transaction to be posted to the
        General Ledger. The current day's date will display by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the item you want to create an
        Adjustment transaction for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the site where the Adjustment transaction should be
        recorded. If an item is located in more than one site, be sure to
        specify the correct site for the Adjustment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Adjustment Qty.</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The number entered will adjust the QOH for the specified item.
        Field accepts positive and negative numbers. To enter a negative
        number, simply prefix the number with a minus symbol.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Relative</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to make a relative adjustment to the item's QOH. The
        "Before" value, which represents current QOH, will increase or
        decrease relative to the number entered in the "Adjustment Qty."
        field. The new QOH value will appear beneath the "After" heading.
        Non-netable QOH is not included in these values.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Absolute</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to make an absolute adjustment to the item's QOH. The
        "Before" value, which represents current QOH, will be changed to the
        new value entered in the "Adjustment Qty." field. This absolutely new
        QOH value will appear beneath the "After" heading. Non-netable QOH is
        not included in these values.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Document #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Creates a user-defined reference for the Adjustment transaction.
        The Document reference will be posted with the General Ledger (G/L)
        transaction record when the Adjustment is generated. This field may be
        used for internal tracking and auditing purposes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Adjust Value</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The Cost tab will be visible only if Average Costing is enabled
        on the Configure Inventory screen. The Cost tab will be enabled only
        if Average Costing is the Cost Method selected for the item site being
        adjusted. If Adjust Value is checked then the transaction will affect
        the value of perpetual inventory using the following Costs:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Calculated</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Use the average cost calculation to determine perpetual
              inventory value and distribute costs for this
              transaction.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manual</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Use the total cost entered to determine perpetual
              inventory value and distribute costs for this
              transaction.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To enter Notes related to the Adjustment transaction, select the
  "Notes" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/adjustmentTrans_tabNotes.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Adjustment Transaction Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When entering Notes related to an Adjustment Transaction, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Notes related to the adjustment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
