<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="apAccountAssignment">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>account assignments</primary>
      <secondary>creating new for payables</secondary>
    </indexterm>Payables Assignment</title>
  <para>To create a new payables assignment, select the
  <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/apAccountAssignment.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create new Payables Assignment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new payables assignment, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <note>
    <para>By default, the screen will limit your account number choices to
    only those accounts having the correct account type for the chosen
    context. However, privileged users may override this default behavior by
    manually entering any account number listed in the chart of
    accounts.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Vendor Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to assign the payables accounts to all vendor
        types.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected Vendor Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify vendor type you want to associate with the payables
        assignment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vendor Type Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a vendor type pattern to select a range of vendor types.
        Refine your search using regular expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Payables Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a general ledger (G/L) account to assign as the default
        payables account. This is a liability account. It will be credited
        when vouchers are posted and debited when checks are posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Prepaid Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to assign as the default payables prepaid
        account. This is an asset account. It should not be confused with or
        used interchangeably with the default payables account. The prepaid
        account will be credited when miscellaneous payables credit memos are
        posted and debited when miscellaneous payables debit memos are
        posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to distribute purchasing discounts to.
        This is a revenue account. It will be credited when purchasing
        discounts are applied to selected payments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
