<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="applyARCreditMemo">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>credit memos</primary>

      <secondary>applying unapplied</secondary>
    </indexterm>Apply Receivables Credit Memo</title>

  <para>To apply a credit memo to either open invoices or open debit memos,
  select the <guibutton>APPLY</guibutton> button on the List Unapplied
  Receivables Credit Memos screen. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/applyARCreditMemo.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Apply Receivables Credit Memo</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When applying a credit memo amount, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the customer number of the customer associated with the
        unapplied credit memo amount. The customer name and billing address
        will also display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Available to Apply</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the credit memo amount which is available to be
        applied.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Applied</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the amount of the credit memo applied to the specified
        document.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Balance</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the amount of the credit memo remaining to be applied,
        if any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Document #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the credit memo number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Distribution Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the date the credit memo applied amount was
        applied.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Find Document</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>To search for an invoice in the open items display, begin typing
        an invoice number into this field. As you type, the list will
        automatically scroll toward the invoice number you are typing. You can
        also search for invoices manually by scrolling through the
        list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Items</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists open receivables for the specified
        customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>APPLY TO BALANCE</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to apply the available balance to the open receivables.
        If the applied balance exceeds the amount due on an open item, the
        remaining balance will be applied to the next open amount.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>APPLY LINE BAL.</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an open item and then select this button to apply the
        credit to the balance for the line.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>APPLY</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an item and then select this button to apply an amount
        to the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>CLEAR APPLICATION</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an item and then select this button to remove any
        amount applied toward the item. If you encounter pending amounts you
        cannot clear, check for unposted cash receipts or uninvoiced sales
        orders having credit allocations on them. To clear the pending
        amounts, post the related cash receipts and/or invoice the related
        sales orders.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <xi:include href="arCreditMemoApplication.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
