<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="applyDiscount">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>discounts</primary>

      <secondary>applying to open payables</secondary>
    </indexterm>Apply Discount</title>

  <para>To apply a billing terms discount and have the discount amount
  deducted from the total owed, select the <guibutton>APPLY
  DISCOUNT</guibutton> button. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/applyDiscount.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Apply Billing Terms Discount</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <note>
    <para>Discounts are posted to the general ledger (G/L) when the check they
    are associated with is posted. Any time prior to the posting of the check,
    the discount can be edited or reversed.</para>
  </note>

  <para>When applying a billing terms discount, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vendor</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name of the vendor who is owed payment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Doc. Type</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the document type. Valid document types include posted
        vouchers and miscellaneous payables debit memos.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Doc #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the document number of the document being selected for
        payment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Doc. Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the document's origination date. In the case of a
        voucher, the document date is the same as the invoice date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Terms</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the billing terms selected at the time the document was
        posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the expiration date for the billing terms discount
        period. The discount date will display in red type once the discount
        period has expired. Once the discount period has expired, the system
        will no longer automatically update the <guilabel>Discount
        Amount</guilabel> field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount %</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the discount percentage, as specified in the billing
        terms.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total Owed</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount from the original document.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total Discountable Owed</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount due of voucher line items marked as
        discountable. If line items are not marked as discountable, they will
        not appear in this total.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discounts Applied</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the amount of any discounts previously applied to the
        selected document.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount Amount</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of the discount to be applied to the total
        owed. As long as the discount period has not expired, the system will
        automatically calculate the discount amount for you. The discount
        amount will be equal to the total owed multiplied by the discount
        percentage. The account used for posting discounts to the G/L is
        defined on the Payables Assignments screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>OK</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to apply the entered discount amount to the selected
        document.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
