<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="arAccountAssignment">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>accounts receivable</primary>

      <secondary>creating new assignment for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Receivables Assignment</title>

  <para>To create a new receivables assignment, select the
  <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/arAccountAssignment.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Create New Receivables Assignment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating a new receivables assignment, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <note>
    <para>By default, the screen will limit your account number choices to
    only those accounts having the correct account type for the chosen
    context. However, privileged users may override this default behavior by
    manually entering any account number listed in the chart of
    accounts.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected Customer Type</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the customer type you want to associate with the
        receivables assignment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Type Pattern</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a customer type pattern to select a range of customer
        types. Refine your search using regular expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>A/R Account</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a general ledger (G/L) account to assign as the default
        receivables account. This is an asset account. For example, it will be
        debited when invoices are posted and credited when cash receipts are
        posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Prepaid Receivables Account</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to assign as the default receivables
        prepaid account. This is a revenue contra account. It will be debited
        when miscellaneous receivables credit memos are posted and credited
        when miscellaneous receivables debit memos are posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight Account</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to assign as the default freight account.
        This is a revenue account. It will be credited when invoices are
        posted and debited when sales order credit memos are posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Deferred Revenue Account</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to assign as the default deferred revenue
        account. This is a liability account. It is an optional account, as
        systems may be configured to ignore it when handling customer
        deposits. When this account is used, it will be credited when
        unapplied cash receipts are posted and debited when the receivables
        credit memos resulting from unapplied cash receipts are applied to
        open receivables.</para>

        <note>
          <para>You can disable the use of a deferred revenue account for
          handling customer deposits at the system level.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount Account</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to assign as the default receivables
        discount account. This is a revenue account. It will be debited when
        cash receipts are posted and the invoice the cash receipt is applied
        to is still within its discount terms.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
