<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="archivesalesHistory">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales history</primary>
      <secondary>archiving of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Archive sales History</title>
  <para>If your system contains older sales history information which you no
  longer need for sales Analysis purposes, you may archive that
  history—effectively removing it from view. Any archived sales history will
  not be shown in sales Analysis reports. If you ever want to view archived
  sales history again, you may restore it at any point. For more information,
  see <xref linkend="restoresalesHistory" />.</para>
  <para>To archive sales history, select the "Archive sales History" option.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/archivesalesHistory.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Archive sales History</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>Archiving sales history does not delete sales history. Rather, the
    historical data is simply relocated to a storage archive on the database.
    You may restore sales history from the archive at any time.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When archiving sales history, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Customer Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to archive sales history for all Customer Types.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify Customer Type whose sales history you want to
        archive.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a Customer Type pattern to select a range of Customer
        Types. Refine your search using Regular Expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Product Categories</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to archive sales history for all Product
        Categories.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify Product Category whose sales history you want to
        archive.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a Product Category pattern to select a range of Product
        Categories. Refine your search using Regular Expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Archive Freight, sales Tax and Misc. Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to archive all the sales information which is not
        directly related to the item sites for a sales order—that is, Freight
        charges, Tax, etc.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>All Sites</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to archive sales history for all sites.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify site whose sales history you want to archive.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Start Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>sales history generated on or after this date will be
        archived.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>End Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>sales history by Shipping Zone by item generated on or before
        this date will be archived.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>OK</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Archives sales History using the specified parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
