<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="bomItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>bills of materials</primary>
      <secondary>adding new components to</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>components</primary>
      <secondary>adding to BOMs</secondary>
    </indexterm>Bill of Materials Item</title>
  <para>To add new components to a bill of materials, select the
  <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/bomItem.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Add New BOM Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Bill of materials component items must have an item site defined to
    be valid.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When adding a new component item to a bill of materials, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the item you want to add to the bill of
        materials.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure. You may also select a global
        conversion ratio here. Global conversions have the label
        <literal>Global</literal> appended to them.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Description of item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>effectivity</primary>
          <secondary>in BOMs</secondary>
        </indexterm>Effectivity</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the component's effectivity, using the following
        parameters:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Effective</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The system enables you to specify when a component can be
              used in a bill of materials. For example, the company's
              engineering department may be working on a new design for an
              existing item—but that new design will not be available for use
              until a given date in the future. In this case, you can specify
              a future effective date to indicate when the component will be
              available for use.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Expires</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The system also enables you to specify when a component is
              planned to be obsoleted from (i.e., no longer used in) a bill of
              materials. As mentioned above, the company's engineering
              department may be working on a new design for an existing
              item—but that new design will not be available for use until a
              given date in the future. In this case, the old component item
              must be marked for expiration on the date when the new item
              becomes effective. Setting this parameter will instruct the
              system to stop using the specified component on the date entered
              into this field.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Create Child W/O at Parent W/O Explosion</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create work orders for manufactured components when
        their parent items are exploded. This option applies only to
        manufactured items appearing as components on a bill of materials. If
        selected, a work order will automatically be created for the
        manufactured component when the parent item is exploded. The impact on
        work order numbers will be visible. For example, a "-1" will be
        appended to the parent level work order and a "-2" to the child level
        work order—as in, #1061-1 and #1061-2. If this option is not selected,
        a child work order will not be created when the parent item is
        exploded.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The <guilabel>Create Child W/O at Parent W/O
          Explosion</guilabel> option will cause the creation of lower level
          work orders BOTH at work order explosion and also during the
          explosion that takes place during Master production Scheduling (MPS)
          and material requirements Planning (MRP) runs.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Issue Child W/O to Parent W/O at Receipt</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to have the completed item (i.e., subassembly) issued to
        the parent work order at the point when production for the child work
        order is posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Fixed Qty.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use this option to specify a "flat" quantity of material
        required that is independent of the total quantity produced on a batch
        or work order. For example, tooling items added to a bill of materials
        generally have a fixed quantity regardless of the total quantity of
        finished goods produced. Batch size does have an impact on the costing
        for fixed quantity items, however. For example, if the parent item's
        batch size is 100 and the cost of the fixed quantity item is $100,
        then the fixed item's cost should be distributed across the batch, as
        in the following: ((1/100) * $100) = $1.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>To ensure fixed quantity item costs are distributed accurately
          across an entire batch, make sure you select the
          <guilabel>Fractional</guilabel> option on the Item master for the
          item. If the item is not fractional, then the batch size conversion
          may not prorate the fixed quantity costs accurately.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Per</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the quantity of the component item required per bill of
        materials. This is a required field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Issue UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the unit of measure (UOM) you want to use when issuing
        item quantity to work orders. You may also select a global conversion
        ratio here. Global conversions have the label
        <literal>Global</literal> appended to them. Unless you specify an
        alternate UOM, the inventory UOM will be used by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scrap %</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Number entered should represent a percentage of material
        quantity that is additionally consumed as Scrap. This is a required
        field.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>Using the <guilabel>Create Child W/O at Parent W/O
          Explosion</guilabel> option can greatly simplify the processing of
          work orders. If this option is not selected, child work orders will
          need to be created independently.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>issue methods</primary>
          <secondary>within BOMs</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>bills of materials</primary>
          <secondary>issue methods for</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>push</primary>
          <secondary>issue method defined</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>pull</primary>
          <secondary>issue method defined</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>mixed</primary>
          <secondary>issue method defined</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>issue methods</primary>
          <secondary>push as</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>issue methods</primary>
          <secondary>pull as</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>issue methods</primary>
          <secondary>mixed as</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>issue methods</primary>
          <secondary>backflush as</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>backflush</primary>
          <secondary>as issue method</secondary>
        </indexterm>Issue Method</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Method: Select one of the available issue methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Push</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the component item to be issued to work
              orders by a specific material issue transaction. Because a
              specific material issue transaction must be used,
              <guilabel>Push</guilabel> items enable you to monitor material
              usage variances. Standard issue quantities are not automatically
              backflushed to work orders, as is true for
              <guilabel>Pull</guilabel> items. If a component item uses the
              <guilabel>Push</guilabel> issue method, you must manually issue
              quantities to work orders.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Pull</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the component item to be issued to work
              orders by a material backflush. <guilabel>Pull</guilabel> items
              are automatically issued to work orders when work order
              production is posted. Using the <guilabel>Pull</guilabel> issue
              method saves time, since materials do not need to be manually
              issued to work orders by a specific material issue
              transaction.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Mixed</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the component item to take upon itself
              the issue method applied to it initially—that is, either
              <guilabel>Pull</guilabel> or <guilabel>Push</guilabel>.
              Assigning the <guilabel>Mixed</guilabel> issue method to a
              component item gives you the flexibility of deciding on a work
              order by work order basis whether you want to assign the
              <guilabel>Pull</guilabel> or <guilabel>Push</guilabel> method to
              the component item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
        <note>
          <para>You can define a default issue method for new bill of
          materials component items at the system level.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>engineering change notices</primary>
          <secondary>in BOMs</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>ECN</primary>
          <see>engineering change notices</see>
        </indexterm>ECN #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Engineering Change Notice number—if applicable—for the
        specified component item.</para>
        <note>
          <para>BOM-defined Substitutions are the only Substitutes which may
          be implemented during work order processing. To substitute a
          component item on a work order, use the
          <guilabel>Substitute</guilabel> option found on the right-click menu
          of the Maintain Work Order Material Requirements screen.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term>Used At</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which operation the component is used at. Using the
        lookup feature located to the right of the field, select a routing
        sequence number to identify which operation the component is used at.
        Linking a component with an operation will have certain effects.
        First, when posting operations, components that are linked to a given
        operation will be backflushed if the issue method for the components
        is either <guilabel>Pull</guilabel> or <guilabel>Mixed</guilabel> and
        the operation is set to auto issue components. Secondly, work order
        paperwork, such as routings, will show the relationship between linked
        work order material requirements and work order operations.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>If an operation is expired, the link between the operation and
          the component item will be removed.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term>Schedule w/ W/O Operation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate that this component is not due until the work
        order operation that will consume it is scheduled to begin. The
        scheduling of operations is handled by the Execution Day indicator on
        the Routings Item screen. For example, let's say we have an operation
        with an Execution Day = 5. This means the operation is scheduled to
        begin five days after the start date of the work order. Components
        scheduled with this operation are due the day before the operation
        starts—that is, on day four after the work order start date—to ensure
        they will be available when the operation is scheduled to begin. If
        this option is not selected, then the component scheduling will be
        governed by the start and due dates set on the Work Order
        header.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter additional notes related to the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add Reference information related to a BOM item, select the
  <guimenuitem>Reference</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="images/bomItem_referencePage.png"/>
    </imageobject>
    <caption>Add Reference to BOM Item</caption>
  </mediaobject>
  <para>The Reference field can be used to identify any additional attributes
  associated with an item.</para>
  <para>To add Substitution information related to a BOM item, select the
  <guimenuitem>Substitution</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="images/bomItem_substitutionsTab.png"/>
    </imageobject>
    <caption>Add Substitution to BOM Item</caption>
  </mediaobject>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Substitutions</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Choose one of the following item Substitution options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>No Substitutions</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if no Substitutions exist for the component
              item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item-Defined Substitutions</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if Substitutions are defined on the Item master for
              the component item. Selecting this option will not cause
              item-defined Substitutions to display here. You are simply
              indicating that Item master level Substitutions do exist.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>BOM-Defined Substitutions</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to define item Substitutions at the bill of
              materials level.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>To ensure availability, a BOM-defined Substitution must be located
    in the same site as the component item it replaces. If the Substitute is
    located in a different site, it will not be available for
    substitution.</para>
  </tip>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>substitutions</primary>
      <secondary>creating new bom-defined</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>bom-defined substitutions</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create a new BOM-defined Substitution, select the
  <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemSubstitute.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Add New BOM-Defined Substitution</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding a new BOM-defined Substitution, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number (Root Item)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays item number of specified component item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number (Substitution)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the Substitute item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Substitute/Parent UOM Ratio</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicate the ratio between the Issue UOM for the specified BOM
        item and the corresponding Issue UOM for the Substitute item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ranking</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
        value up to a maximum of 9. Enter the specified ranking order of the
        item Substitute. You may assign the same ranking to multiple items, if
        this is appropriate.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add comments to a component item, select the
  <guimenuitem>Comments</guimenuitem> tab at the bottom of the Bill of
  Materials Item screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/bomItem_commentsTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Add Comment to BOM Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/comments.xml" xpointer="commentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
  <para>To view or maintain the current standard costs for the selected item,
  select the <guimenuitem>Costs</guimenuitem> tab at the bottom of the Bill of
  Materials Item screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/bomItem_costsTab.png"/>
      </imageobject>
      <caption>BOM Item Costs</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When opening the bill of materials item costs, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Costs are specific to this Bill of Material Item</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this option to manually edit the current standard costs
        of the item. If this option is not selected, a read only list of the
        current standard costs for the item is displayed.</para>
        <note>
          <para>If this option is unchecked after the costs have been changed,
          the list will revert to displaying standard costs.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Costing Elements</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>A list of the costing elements with current standard cost of the
        bill of material item is displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>bills of materials</primary>
      <secondary>linking to routings</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>bills of operations</primary>
      <secondary>linking to BOMs</secondary>
    </indexterm>link a Bill of Materials component to a routing item, select
  the lookup feature located to the right of the <guilabel>Used At</guilabel>
  field. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/booItemList.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Routing Items</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When linking bill of materials components to routings items, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The component item selected on the Bill of Materials screen will
        display here.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Routing Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists routing items for the same manufactured item whose
        bill of materials is being specified. Highlight the operation you want
        to link the bill of materials item to, then hit the
        <guibutton>SELECT</guibutton> button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>CLEAR</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Removes the link between a bill of materials component and a
        routing item if such a link has been made.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SELECT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Links the routing item to the specified bill of materials
        component. Highlight the desired routing item before selecting the
        <guibutton>SELECT</guibutton> button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>On a bill of materials, if the parent item is a configured item (i.e.,
  configured job item or Reference item), then you will have the option to
  link BOM items to specific parent item characteristics. For example, let's
  say the parent item has a characteristic for paint finish with the values
  "Flat" and "Glossy". At the BOM item level, you can specify whether the BOM
  item goes with "Flat" or "Glossy". If you choose "Glossy" to associate with
  the BOM item, then that means the BOM item will be included as a material
  requirement whenever orders call for the "Glossy" version of the parent
  item. If no characteristic association is made at the BOM item level, then
  the BOM item will always appear on work orders—regardless of the
  parent-level configuration selection. To associate characteristics with a
  BOM item, select the <guimenuitem>Configuration</guimenuitem> tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/bomItem_configurationTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Configure BOM Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>You can learn more about item configuration in xTuple ERP by reading
    the <ulink
    url="http://wiki.xtuple.org/AssembleToOrderConfiguratorTopic">Assemble to
    Order (ATO) Configuration Topic</ulink>.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When associating characteristics with a BOM item, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Characteristic</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a characteristic from the list of characteristics. These
        characteristics are item characteristics defined on the Item master
        for the parent item on the bill of materials. Linking parent
        characteristics to child BOM items means the child item will be
        included as a material requirement whenever orders call for the same
        parent item characteristic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Value</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a value to associate with the selected item
        characteristic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
