<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="boo">
  <title>Enter New Routing</title>

  <para>To enter a new routing, select the <guimenuitem>Enter New
  Routing</guimenuitem> option. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/boo.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Create New Routing</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating a new routing, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the manufactured item you want to
        create a routing for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure (UOM).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>operations</primary>

          <secondary>expired from routings</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>routings</primary>

          <secondary>expired operations in</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>expiration</primary>

          <secondary>of operations in routings</secondary>
        </indexterm>Show Expired Operations</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display expired operations in the Routing display.
        Expired operations are operations that have been expired from the
        routing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>operations</primary>

          <secondary>adding to routings in future</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>routings</primary>

          <secondary>future operations in</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>future</primary>

          <secondary>of operations in routings</secondary>
        </indexterm>Show Future Operations</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display future operations in the Routing display.
        Future operations are operations that will be added to the routing at
        a future point in time.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>routings</primary>

          <secondary>revisions for</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>revisions</primary>

          <secondary>in routings</secondary>
        </indexterm>Revision</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>If revision control is enabled at your site, specify the routing
        revision number you want to view. If none exists, simply enter a value
        to create one. The status of the revision will also be displayed. The
        following statuses apply to revisions:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Active</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>This is the current, default revision used for costing and
              material requirements planning (MRP). Only one revision can be
              active at the same time. Active revisions may be modified.
              However, once a revision has been deactivated, it may only be
              reactivated if you have enabled the configuration option to
              allow for substitute revisions.</para>

              <tip>
                <para>The active revision becomes inactive when a pending or
                substitute revision is activated. To activate a pending or
                substitute revision, right-click on the magnifying glass next
                to the item number and select
                <guimenuitem>Activate</guimenuitem>. Inactive revisions cannot
                be modified.</para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Pending</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>This is a revision that has never been used, but is under
              development or consideration. You may store multiple pending
              revisions. When a pending revision is entered in the
              <guilabel>Revision</guilabel> field, an option to activate the
              item will dynamically appear in the <guimenu>Context</guimenu>
              menu after you right-click on the magnifying glass next to the
              item number. Select <guilabel>Activate</guilabel> from this
              <guimenu>Context</guimenu> menu to convert a pending revision to
              the active revision.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Substitute</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>If you have enabled the configuration option to allow for
              substitute revisions, this status will be available. If enabled,
              any active revision will become a substitute revision when it is
              deactivated. Substitute revisions serve as alternate revisions
              which can be activated at a later date.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Inactive</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>This is a formerly active revision. Inactive revisions
              cannot be modified—only viewed. They are stored to provide
              historical, point-in-time build information, which may be used
              for various purposes throughout the application. For example,
              privileged users may select inactive revisions when processing
              work orders or purchase orders. There is no limit to the number
              of inactive revisions you may save.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Document #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>If desired, enter a document number to further identify the bill
        of materials (BOMs).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Revision Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Indicates the date of the revision. This field updates every
        time the routing is saved.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>Once a revision date has been entered, the date field cannot be
    erased. The specific date may be updated to reflect subsequent revisions,
    but the field will never be null as long as the BOMs exists.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>work in process</primary>

          <secondary>boo-defined locations for</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>bills of operations</primary>

          <secondary>wip locations and</secondary>
        </indexterm>Final Location</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select a final work-in-process (WIP) location. This is an
        optional selection which may be used for tracking the site locations
        of finished goods inventory as it moves through the manufacturing
        process. The feature applies only to top-level, multiple location
        control (MLC) items whose production is posted through work order
        operations posting. If you choose to track finished MLC goods using
        this feature, then the final location is the location where inventory
        will be located when operations posting for the work order is
        completed. If you do not wish to track WIP locations for finished MLC
        goods, then you can ignore this option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>bills of operations</primary>

          <secondary>production lead times in</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>lead times</primary>

          <secondary>in routings</secondary>
        </indexterm>Production Lead Time</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Lead time: Displays production lead time for the specified item.
        The production lead time value is equal to the maximum execution day
        value specified for listed operations. Each operation must have an
        execution day specified. Based on values entered for all listed
        operations, whichever execution day value is the maximum, that value
        will be displayed as the production lead time for the routing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Close Work Order when full Qty. Posted</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to automatically close work orders when the full work
        order quantity is posted when posting operations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Routing</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists all operations for the selected routing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>ACTIVATE</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to activate a pending revision. This button will only be
        visible when a pending revision number is entered in the
        <guilabel>Revision</guilabel> field.</para>

        <tip>
          <para>When you activate a pending revision, the currently active
          revision will become inactive. Inactive revisions cannot be
          modified.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>DEACTIVATE</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to deactivate a substitute revision. This button will
        only be visible when a substitute revision number is entered in the
        <guilabel>Revision</guilabel> field. Once the revision is inactive, it
        cannot be modified.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>EXPIRE</guibutton></term>

      <listitem id="booEXPIRE">
        <para>Highlight an operation and then select this button to expire the
        operation, causing it to be hidden from view on the list—unless the
        <guilabel>Show Expired Operations</guilabel> option is specifically
        chosen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
    <para>If the operation is expired on the current day, the operation will
    still appear as an option when selecting <guilabel>Used At</guilabel>
    operations on a bill of materials (BOM) if done during the same current
    day. Once a day passes, however, the expired operation will no longer
    appear as a <guilabel>Used At</guilabel> option on the BOM.</para>
  </tip>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>MOVE UP</guibutton></term>

      <listitem id="booMOVEUP">
        <para>Highlight an operation and then select this button to move the
        operation up the routing list. Sequence numbers, which are incremented
        in multiples of ten, are automatically adjusted to reflect the change
        in position.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>MOVE DOWN</guibutton></term>

      <listitem id="booMOVEDOWN">
        <para>Highlight an operation and then select this button to move the
        operation down the routing list. Sequence numbers, which are
        incremented in multiples of ten, are automatically adjusted to reflect
        the change in position.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <xi:include href="booItem.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
