<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="booItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>Routings</primary>

      <secondary>creating new operation in</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>operations</primary>

      <secondary>adding new to Routings</secondary>
    </indexterm>Routing Item</title>

  <para>To add a new operation to a routing, select the
  <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/booItem.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Add New Operation to Routing</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When adding a new operation to a routing, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays item number specified in Routing screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure (UOM).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Standard Oper.</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select a standard operation to use for the operation, if any.
        Instructions associated with the standard operation will be displayed
        below.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Operation Type</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>If a standard operation is specified, the operation type
        associated with the standard operation will be displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description to further identify the operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Work Center</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify work center to be used for the specified
        operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tooling Reference</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Use this field to briefly describe any tooling required for the
        operation. For example, if you are making plastic products, the
        tooling reference might refer to the mold used to form the
        plastic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Oper. Seq.#</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays operation sequence number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>execution days</primary>

          <secondary>in routings</secondary>
        </indexterm>Execution Day</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
        value up to a maximum of 99. This feature enables you to schedule work
        order materials with work order operations. For example, let's say we
        have an operation with an execution day = 5. This means the operation
        is scheduled to begin five days after the start date of the work
        order. Components scheduled with this operation are due the day before
        the operation starts—that is, on day four after the work order start
        date—to ensure they will be available when the operation is scheduled
        to begin. If this option is not selected, then the component
        scheduling will be governed by the start and due dates set on the work
        order header. Based on the values entered for all listed operations,
        whichever execution day value is the maximum, that value will be
        displayed as the production lead time for the routing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>effectivity</primary>

          <secondary>in routings</secondary>
        </indexterm>Effectivity</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the operation's effectivity, using the following
        parameters:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Effective</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>The system enables you to specify when an operation can be
              used in a bill of materials (BOM). For example, the company's
              engineering department may be working on a new design for an
              existing item—but that new design will not be available for use
              until a given date in the future. In this case, you can specify
              the effective date when the component will be available for
              use.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Expires</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>The system also enables you to specify when an operation
              is planned to be obsoleted from (i.e., no longer used in) a
              BOMs. As mentioned above, the company's engineering department
              may be working on a new design for an existing item—but that new
              design will not be available for use until a given date in the
              future. In this case, the old component item must be marked for
              expiration on a given date. This expiration date will most
              likely coincide with the effective date of the replacement part.
              Setting this parameter will instruct the system to stop using
              the specified component on the date entered into this
              field.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>

        <note>
          <para>Standard operations are intended as initial templates used to
          set up routing items. Any changes made to a standard operation will
          not automatically ripple throughout all your routing items that use
          the standard operation.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>setup time</primary>

          <secondary>in routings</secondary>
        </indexterm>Setup Time (min)</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Amount entered represents the number of minutes required to set
        up the work center for the operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report Cost as (Setup Time)</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify whether you want to report setup costs as
        <guilabel>Direct Labor</guilabel>, <guilabel>Overhead</guilabel>, or
        <guilabel>None</guilabel>. Specify the <guilabel>None</guilabel>
        option if you would do not want to track setup time as part of the
        operation's cost.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report Setup Time</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to report setup time. Must be selected for labor costs
        associated with setup to be tracked in the G/L and elsewhere. If not
        selected, these costs will not be reported.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>run time</primary>

          <secondary>in routings</secondary>
        </indexterm>Run Time (min)</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Amount entered represents the number of minutes required to run
        the production UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report Cost as (Run Time)</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify whether you want to report setup costs as
        <guilabel>Direct Labor</guilabel>, <guilabel>Overhead</guilabel>, or
        <guilabel>None</guilabel>. Specify the <guilabel>None</guilabel>
        option if you would do not want to track setup time as part of the
        operation's cost.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report Run Time</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to report run time. Must be selected for labor costs
        associated with run time to be tracked in the G/L and elsewhere. If
        not selected, these costs will not be reported.</para>

        <note>
          <para>When operations are posted, inventory transaction records will
          be posted to the general ledger if at least one of the operations in
          the list of work order operations has either or both of the
          inventory handling options selected. If items are backflushed at an
          operation, select the <guilabel>Auto. Issue Components</guilabel>
          option. If finished items are received into inventory at an
          operation, select the <guilabel>Receive Inventory</guilabel>
          option.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>per</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the standard quantity that will be produced during a
        typical run-time period. The value entered here is equivalent to a run
        size, batch size, or economic order quantity (EOQ) for this particular
        operation. Because work order operations roll into the actual and
        standard costs for manufactured items, you should specify a per
        quantity which accurately reflects your normal batch size for the
        operation. Specifying a standard batch size helps ensure your
        operations costs are evenly distributed. The following equation
        indicates how operations costs are distributed using batch
        sizes:</para>

        <equation>
          <mathphrase>((Setup Time * Setup Cost) + (Run Time * Run Cost))/per
          = Extended Total</mathphrase>
        </equation>

        <para>The following table illustrates two examples of how differing
        batch sizes produce different operations costs per unit:</para>

        <para><table>
            <title>Example Batch Sizes with Operations Costing</title>

            <tgroup cols="6">
              <thead>
                <row>
                  <entry><para> Setup Time (Mins) </para></entry>

                  <entry><para> Run Time (Mins) </para></entry>

                  <entry><para> Units in Run ("per") </para></entry>

                  <entry><para>Setup Cost from WC (Per Min)</para></entry>

                  <entry><para>Run Cost from WC (Per Min)</para></entry>

                  <entry><para> Extended Cost per Unit </para></entry>
                </row>
              </thead>

              <tbody>
                <row>
                  <entry><para> 15 </para></entry>

                  <entry><para> 100 </para></entry>

                  <entry><para> 10 </para></entry>

                  <entry><para>$0.500</para></entry>

                  <entry><para>$0.417</para></entry>

                  <entry><para>$4.920</para></entry>
                </row>

                <row>
                  <entry><para> 15</para></entry>

                  <entry><para> 1000 </para></entry>

                  <entry><para> 100 </para></entry>

                  <entry><para>$0.500</para></entry>

                  <entry><para>$0.417</para></entry>

                  <entry><para>$4.245</para></entry>
                </row>
              </tbody>
            </tgroup>
          </table></para>

        <note>
          <para>Labor and <indexterm significance="normal">
              <primary>overhead</primary>

              <secondary>in routings</secondary>
            </indexterm>overhead costs associated with setup and run times
          must be reported if they are to be tracked in the G/L and elsewhere.
          To report setup and run times, select the appropriate boxes in the
          Operations screen.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>units of measure</primary>

          <secondary>in routings</secondary>
        </indexterm>Production UOM</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select a UOM—or enter a free-form UOM. Specify a UOM to be used
        optionally when work order operations are posted for the specified
        operation. Different operations in a single routing may use different
        production UOMs. For example, if you are producing soup, you might mix
        the soup in one operation using UOM = BATCH. But when canning the
        soup, the canning operation might use UOM = CAN.</para>

        <note>
          <para>When posting work order operations, you are given the option
          to post operations using production UOMs or inventory UOMs.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Production/Inventory Ratio</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is the ratio that normalizes quantities to create a
        production UOM for use when posting work order operations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Receive Inventory at this Operation</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate that the manufactured item should be received
        into inventory at this operation. The manufactured item will be
        received into inventory via a receive from manufacturing (RM)
        transaction, when the operation is posted.</para>

        <note>
          <para>The <guilabel>Receive Inventory</guilabel> option may only be
          selected once per routing. Finished items may only be received into
          inventory once in the operations sequence.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Auto. Issue Components at this Operation</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Issue components at this operation: Select to automatically
        issue components used at this operation. This setting will only affect
        component items whose issue method is either pull or mixed. Component
        items using the push issue method must be issued to work orders using
        a specific material issue transaction.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>May Overlap with Preceding Operation</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to allow the operation to overlap with the preceding
        operation. If selected, you are indicating that this operation may be
        posted before the preceding operation is complete. If not selected,
        the operation may not be posted before the preceding operation is
        complete.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>work in process</primary>

          <secondary>boo-defined locations for</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>bills of operations</primary>

          <secondary>wip locations and</secondary>
        </indexterm>WIP Location</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select a work-in-process (WIP) location. This is an optional
        selection which may be used for tracking the site locations of
        finished goods inventory as it moves through the manufacturing
        process. The feature applies only to top-level, multiple location
        control (MLC) items whose production is posted through work order
        operations posting. If you choose to track finished MLC goods using
        this feature, then the WIP location entered here is the location where
        inventory will be located when the preceding operation for the work
        order is posted. A proceeding operation must exist for the location
        entered here to be used. If you do not wish to track WIP locations for
        finished MLC goods, then you can ignore this option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>throughput</primary>

          <secondary>at operation level</secondary>
        </indexterm>Throughput</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Indicates the number of units, in the given item's inventory
        UOM, that can be produced in a minute—and also the number of minutes
        that are required to produce 1 unit, expressed in the given item's
        inventory UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>Bill of materials (BOM) items may be associated with operations—either
  materials, tools, or finished goods themselves. In an effort to help manage
  this relationship, the Operation screen includes the ability to both modify
  the source BOM and also modify the links between the operation and component
  items. To view components associated with an operation, select the
  <guimenuitem>Materials</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/booItem_materials.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Components Associated with Operation</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When viewing components associated with an operation, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Expired</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display expired components associated with the
        operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Future</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display future components associated with the
        operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Revision</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which BOM revision you want to use in conjunction with
        the specified operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Materials</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display includes components associated with the
        operation.</para>

        <warning>
          <para>Changes made to components on the Operation screen will be
          reflected in the source BOMs.</para>
        </warning>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>EXPIRE</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a component and then select this button to expire the
        item from the BOM.</para>

        <tip>
          <para><indexterm significance="normal">
              <primary>bills of materials</primary>

              <secondary>deleting items from</secondary>
            </indexterm>If your site is configured to allow the deletion of
          BOM items, you will see a <guilabel>Delete</guilabel> option in the
          right-click menu on this screen.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>ATTACH</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to associate a component with the operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>DETACH</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a component and then select this button to break the
        link between the item and the operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To associate instructions with an operation, select the
  <guimenuitem>Instructions</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/booItem_instructions.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Operational Instructions</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When associating instructions with an operation, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Instructions</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        instructions related to the operation. If you are using a standard
        operation, the instructions (if any) associated with the standard
        operation will be displayed here. You have the option to edit these
        instructions, but any edits are <emphasis>ad hoc</emphasis> in nature.
        Edits are not saved back to the standard operation and they will be
        lost if you change standard operations for any reason.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Fixed-Width Font</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display text in the <guilabel>Instructions</guilabel>
        field in fixed-width font. This is a useful feature for displaying
        tables, matrixes, and other format-driven texts.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>You may associate images with an operation, thereby making these
  images available to be printed on routings. To associate an image with an
  operation, select the <guimenuitem>Images</guimenuitem> tab. The following
  screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/booItem_booimage.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Operation Images</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When associating images with an operation, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Images</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists stored images available for association with the
        specified operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <xi:include href="../widgets/imageAssignment.xml"
              xpointer="imageAssignmentWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
