<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section role="distribution">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>vendor catalog</primary>

      <secondary>management of</secondary>
    </indexterm>External Vendor Catalog</title>

  <para>The external vendor catalog is designed to help distributors manage
  not only their own items but also the potential items they have access to.
  These external items can come from pricing services such as Trade Service
  (<ulink
  url="http://www.tradeservice.com">http://www.tradeservice.com</ulink>)?or,
  if your vendor provides price sheets, you can also create custom maps to
  import the vendor's items into xTuple ERP.</para>

  <note>
    <para>To learn more about building your Catalog using vendor provided
    price sheets, check out the <ulink
    url="http://xtupleuniversity.com/xwdpricesheet-install">xwdpricesheet
    package</ulink> video at xTuple University: <ulink
    url="http://xtupleuniversity.com/">http://xtupleuniversity.com/</ulink>.</para>
  </note>

  <para>To access the external vendor catalog, select the "External Vendor
  Catalog" option in the Item menu or by clicking on the "Vendor Catalog"
  button on the sales Order Item or Purchase Order Item screens. The following
  screen will appear.</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/catalogList.png" />
        </imageobject>

        <caption>External Vendor Catalog</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When accessing the external vendor catalog, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Filter</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Use the filter to manage and save search criteria.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Query Limit</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Use this option to limit the number of query results when
        working with large data sets.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Commodity Code</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Commodity Code information. You can select a Commodity
        Code to filter the query results to an individual Commodity Code or
        select a Commodity Code family to filter the query results to the
        Commodity Codes of the family.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Catalog</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays items appearing in the external vendor catalog. If an
        item displays in red type, that means the item has already been
        converted to an inventory item in xTuple ERP.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CONVERT</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an external vendor catalog item in the list and then
        select this button to convert the Catalog item to an inventory item in
        xTuple ERP. The Vendor Catalog Conversion screen will be displayed.
        You have the options to create a new inventory item or add the Catalog
        item as a new item source for an existing inventory item. When
        creating a new inventory item, an item, item site(s), item source,
        item Cost, item UOM Conversion, and item Tax Type are created using
        the information of the Catalog item and the appropriate Provider entry
        in your Vendor Catalog Conversion Configurations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
