<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="catCostList" role="distribution">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>vendor catalog</primary>
      <secondary>costs for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Vendor Catalog Costs</title>
  <para>The Vendor Catalog Costs screen allows you to manage the costs
  associated with any external vendor catalog items which you've converted to
  inventory items in xTuple. From this one screen you can both view your
  converted items and manage their item costing information. Changes you make
  to an item's costing information on this screen will be transferred to the
  xTuple items when you run the <guilabel>Update</guilabel> option.</para>
  <para>To view and manage your converted vendor catalog items, go to
  <guimenuitem>Products &gt; Item &gt; Catalog Cost</guimenuitem>. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/catCostList.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Vendor Catalog Costs</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The Vendor Catalog Costs screen displays cost and pricing information
  for xTuple inventory items converted from your external vendor catalog. Item
  and item source records are both displayed here. To modify information for
  an item, select the <guimenuitem>Edit</guimenuitem> option from the
  right-click menu.</para>
  <note>
    <para>If your pricing configuration is configured to <guilabel>Use
    Wholesale Price for Unit Cost for Markups</guilabel>, then your sales
    commission is based on the item's wholesale price. The
    <literal>catcost</literal> information can be used to manage those costs,
    as well, reflecting a true cost for commissions.</para>
  </note>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>UPDATE CATCOST</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update your xTuple item information with the
        information shown on the Vendor Catalog Cost screen. If the two sets
        of information are in sync, no changes will be made.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>DELETE CATCOST</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to temporarily clear all item information from the
        catalog cost table. When you select the <guibutton>UPDATE
        CATCOST</guibutton> button, this information will be refreshed with
        the current xTuple item information on file.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>UPDATE ITEMS</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update the catalog cost data using information from
        your external vendors' price sheet(s). If you are coordinating with
        multiple price sheets, you will be given the option to choose the
        provider whose updates you want to apply.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="catCost.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
