<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="characteristic">
  <title>Characteristic</title>

  <para>To create a new characteristic, select the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton>
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/characteristic.png"/>
      </imageobject>

      <caption><para>Create New Characteristic</para></caption>
    </mediaobject></para>

  <para>When creating a new characteristic, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a unique name to identify the characteristic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Type</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the following characteristic type options:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Text</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the characteristic to be a text string.
              Text type characteristics have access to the <guilabel>Input
              Mask</guilabel> and <guilabel>Validator</guilabel>
              options.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>List</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the characteristic to present a list of
              possible values. If selected, you will have the option to enter
              possible characteristic values and their preferred sort
              order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Date</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the characteristic to be a date string.
              The formatting of date type characteristics conforms to the
              <guilabel>Locale</guilabel> setting for the logged in
              user.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the sort order for the characteristic. This option is
        useful whenever you present multiple characteristics in a given
        context. For example, if you have five contact characteristics
        defined, the sort order will determine which characteristic appears at
        the top of the sort order when a contact record is being entered or
        edited.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Include in searches</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate you want the characteristic to be included in
        searches related to records where the characteristic is used. Not
        selecting this option means the characteristic will not be included in
        searches. This feature exists to help improve potential performance
        penalties incurred when multiple characteristics are included in
        search criteria. If you use multiple characteristics to define certain
        records (e.g., items, customers, etc.), you can improve search
        performance by choosing to only include in searches those
        characteristics which you are most likely to search on.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Allow unique Characteristic assignment only</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to restrict use of the characteristic to only
        once per object association. For example, if want to make sure a
        contact characteristic is used only once per contact record, then you
        should select this option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>May be used on</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select one or more of the following characteristic assignment
        options by selecting the relevant check boxes. The characteristic will
        then be available for use in the specified screen(s). The following
        characteristic assignments options are supported: account, address,
        contact, customer, employee, fixed asset, incident, invoice, invoice
        item, item, item group, lot/serial, maintenance order, opportunity,
        project, project task, purchase order, purchase order item, purchase
        request, quote, quote item, sales order, sales order item, vendor,
        voucher, work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Options</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The options presented will vary depending on the characteristic
        type you choose. The range of possible options are described
        below:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Text options</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>The following options will be available for text type
              characteristics. These advanced options are not required, but if
              used they will enforce greater consistency and control over the
              values entered for your text type characteristics. Typically
              when using these advanced validation features, you will specify
              either an input mask or a validator. If you decide to use both
              at once, they must be coordinated and consistent—otherwise users
              will experience difficulties when attempting to enter text type
              characteristic values.</para>

              <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Input Mask</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select from the available options—or manually enter
                    an input mask of your own design. An input mask creates a
                    template to guide users as they enter values for a
                    characteristic. It is a form of light data validation. For
                    example, if you specify the input mask
                    <guilabel>00/00/0000</guilabel>, then users will be
                    presented with the following template when they are
                    entering values for the characteristic: __/__/____. In
                    this case, users will simply have to fill in the blanks
                    between the separators.</para>

                    <variablelist>
                      <varlistentry>
                        <term>00/00/0000</term>

                        <listitem>
                          <para>Select this format to prompt users to enter a
                          date format with the pattern shown (e.g.,
                          MM/DD/YYYY).</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </varlistentry>

                      <varlistentry>
                        <term>### - ### - ####</term>

                        <listitem>
                          <para>Select this format to prompt users to enter a
                          numerical format with the pattern shown. This
                          example would be a good match for telephone numbers
                          (e.g., 757-555-1111).</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </varlistentry>

                      <varlistentry>
                        <term>### - ## - ####</term>

                        <listitem>
                          <para>Select this format to prompt users to enter a
                          numerical format with the pattern shown. This
                          example would be a good match for social security
                          numbers (e.g., 012-34-5678).</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </varlistentry>

                      <varlistentry>
                        <term>00,000.00</term>

                        <listitem>
                          <para>Select this format to prompt users to enter a
                          price format with the pattern shown.</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </varlistentry>
                    </variablelist>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Validator</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select from the available options—or manually enter
                    a validator of your own design. A validator is used to
                    strictly enforce the format of data users can enter in a
                    field. If you specify a validator for a characteristic,
                    then users will have to conform to the format when
                    entering values for the characteristic. Values which do
                    not conform will not be accepted.</para>

                    <variablelist>
                      <varlistentry>
                        <term>[Y/N]</term>

                        <listitem>
                          <para>Select this boolean validator to require users
                          to enter <guilabel>Y</guilabel> or
                          <guilabel>N</guilabel> for yes or no.</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </varlistentry>

                      <varlistentry>
                        <term>\S+</term>

                        <listitem>
                          <para>Select this validator to require users to
                          enter one or more non-white-space characters. So,
                          for example, this validator would accept the value
                          <guilabel>Inventory</guilabel> but not
                          <guilabel>Inventory Availability</guilabel>.</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </varlistentry>

                      <varlistentry>
                        <term>[1-9]\d{0,3}</term>

                        <listitem>
                          <para>Select this validator to require users to
                          enter a number from 1-9999.</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </varlistentry>

                      <varlistentry>
                        <term>[A-Z]\d{5}[1-9]</term>

                        <listitem>
                          <para>Select this validator to require users to
                          enter a value where the first character is A-Z, the
                          next five characters are numbers 0-9, and the last
                          character is a number 1-9. While this pattern may
                          not be very useful for most people, it does
                          illustrate how you can create your own regular
                          expressions to design a validator to meet your own
                          custom needs.</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </varlistentry>

                      <varlistentry>
                        <term>(https?:\/\/(?:www\.|(?!www))[^\s\.]+\.[^\s]{2,}|www\.[^\s]+\.[^\s]{2,})</term>

                        <listitem>
                          <para>Select this validator to require users to
                          enter a website address (e.g., <ulink
                          url="http://www.xtuple.com">www.xtuple.com</ulink>).</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </varlistentry>
                    </variablelist>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>List options</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>The following options will be available for list type
              characteristics:</para>

              <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term><guibutton>NEW</guibutton></term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select to create a new value for the
                    characteristic.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Value</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Use your mouse to click in the
                    <guilabel>Value</guilabel> field. Once you see the cursor
                    in the <guilabel>Value</guilabel> field, you can begin
                    typing your value information. The value entered here will
                    appear as a listed option when the specified
                    characteristic is used. For example, possible values might
                    be <guilabel>True</guilabel> and
                    <guilabel>False</guilabel>—or any other combination of
                    values you can imagine.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Order</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Specify the sort order for each value in the list.
                    If the order of the value <guilabel>True</guilabel> is
                    <guilabel>1</guilabel> and the value for
                    <guilabel>False</guilabel> is <guilabel>2</guilabel>, then
                    <guilabel>True</guilabel> will appear above
                    <guilabel>False</guilabel> in the characteristic
                    list.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry>
                  <term><guibutton>DELETE</guibutton></term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Highlight a characteristic value and select this
                    button to remove the value from the list.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Date options</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>There are no options for date type characteristics. The
              formatting of date type characteristics conforms to the
              <guilabel>Locale</guilabel> setting for the logged in
              user.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Use the <guimenuitem>Description</guimenuitem> tab to enter a
        brief description of the characteristic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
