<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="classCode">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>class codes</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Class Code</title>
  <para>To create a new class code, select the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton>
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/classCode.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create new Class Code</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Create your class codes using a logical, hierarchical structure.
    This will make it easier to retrieve class code information in the
    future.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new class code, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Class Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a unique code to identify the class code.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description to further identify the class code.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Item Tax Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Lists the tax zone defaults for different tax types.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>When you create a default item tax type, this will be the tax type
  that will be automatically assigned when a newly-created item is assigned to
  the class code. Items which have already been created and are in the
  database will not have their tax types changed, even if you edit the
  default. To create a default tax type, select the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton>
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemtax.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create new tax type</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new item tax type default, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax zones</primary>
          <secondary>for sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm>Tax Zone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the tax zone you want to associate with the specified
        tax type. Creating a relationship between a tax zone and a tax type
        enables you to determine how tax will be applied when processing
        transactions using the item. If you select the
        <guilabel>Any</guilabel> option, this means any defined tax zone is a
        possible match.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Consider creating separate tax types for any groups or classes of
    items which are taxed at different rates.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the tax type you want to associate with the specified
        tax zone. Tax types provide a system for classifying goods and
        services into taxable categories. Creating a relationship between a
        tax zone and a tax type enables you to determine how tax will be
        applied when processing transactions using the item. If you select the
        <guilabel>Any</guilabel> option, this means any defined tax type is a
        possible match.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
