<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="configureCRM">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>configuration</primary>
      <secondary>of crm module</secondary>
    </indexterm>Configure CRM</title>
  <para>To configure the <guimenu>CRM</guimenu> module, select the <guimenuitem>Configure CRM</guimenuitem> option. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureCRM.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Configure CRM Module</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When configuring the <guimenu>CRM</guimenu> module, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>crm accounts</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Account # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available CRM account number generation
        methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manual</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>CRM account numbers must be entered manually whenever you
              create a new CRM account.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>CRM account numbers will be automatically incremented by 1
              each time a new CRM account is created. These
              automatically-generated numbers may not be edited. They are
              read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Allow Override</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>CRM account numbers will be automatically generated and
              incremented, as under the <guilabel>Automatic</guilabel> option described above.
              However, this option also allows you to manually override the
              CRM account number at the time of CRM account creation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Next #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the next available CRM account number. The next
              CRM account created will use the number specified here. Leave
              this field blank if you will be creating CRM account numbers
              manually.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Incident # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, incident numbers are generated automatically.
        However, you have the ability to specify the next available
        number.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Next #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the next available incident number. The next
              incident created will use the number specified here.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Projects</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enable project functionality. This option must be
        enabled for project Accounting to be enabled.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry role="xtprjaccnt">
            <term>Enable Project Accounting</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to enable the features related to the project
              Accounting package. When project Accounting is enabled, all G/L
              accounts are eligible to have transactions performed against
              them—and to have an extra dynamic segment for the project number
              appended to the G/L account number. Project Accounts are created
              on the fly as transactions are performed against them,
              eliminating the need for users having to create G/L accounts for
              every possible G/L account and project combination. Financial
              statement and transaction reporting will display
              project-specific transactions just as though the project number
              were the last segment of the G/L account. Various reports can be
              filtered by project transaction.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry role="xtte">
            <term>Project Labor And Overhead</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter a G/L account to be used when approving Time Sheets
              for employees who record time against projects. For this account
              to be used, the employee must have a rate defined on their
              employee record—and they must also not be a contractor.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatically create Projects for sales Orders</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to create a project for every sales order when a
              new sales order is created.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Opportunity Changes to the Change Log</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to have the system automatically log changes made to
        opportunity records under the <guimenuitem>Comments</guimenuitem> tab for each opportunity
        where the changes are made. If not selected, opportunity changes will
        not be tracked automatically.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Incident Public checkbox</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to show the <guilabel>Public</guilabel> checkbox option on the
        Incidents screen. In not selected, the "Public" checkbox will not be
        shown. This option applies primarily to sites where the xTuple Web
        Portal has been implemented. With the Web Portal, xTuple incidents may
        be viewed by customers, vendors, and others on your website. Depending
        on your website rules, private incidents may be hidden from most
        website users.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Incidents Public by Default</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If you are showing the "Public" checkbox on incidents, select
        this option to make incidents publicly viewable by default. Incidents
        will be private by default if this option is not selected. Regardless
        of the setting you make here, the <guilabel>Public</guilabel> flag can be overridden on
        the Incident screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Require SO/PO/WO assignment to Project</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If selected, you will be required to link a project before
        saving sales orders, purchase orders, or work orders. If not selected,
        the project association won't be required at order entry.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Warning Period for Project Due Dates</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify how far in advance you want to be notified of a
        project's approaching due date. The warning consists of a color-coded
        alert on the Order Activity by project report.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="xtconnect">
      <term>Default Incident Email Delivery Profile</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the default EDI email delivery profile you want to use
        when emailing incidents.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="xtconnect">
      <term>Email Delivery when Incident</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the options below to trigger email notifications when
        incident events occur.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Created</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>When incident is created, email notification is
              sent.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Assigned</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>When user is assigned to incident, email notification is
              sent.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Status Changed</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>When status of an incident is changed, email notification
              is sent.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Updated</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>When incident is updated, email notification is
              sent.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Comments Added</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>When comments are added to an incident, email notification
              is sent.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
        <note>
          <para>The following tokens are supported in EDI profile for CRM
          incidents:</para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>&lt;/email1&gt; = incident owner email address</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>&lt;/email2&gt; = incident assignee email address</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>&lt;/email3&gt; = incident contact email address</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>&lt;/description&gt; = incident description</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>&lt;/docnumber&gt; = incident number</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>&lt;/doctype&gt; = "INCDT"</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>&lt;/docid&gt; = incident primary key id</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>&lt;/docbody&gt; = Builds text of fields, notes and
              history of incident record</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>&lt;/comments&gt; = incident comments</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Incident Status Colors</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The incident color configuration option supports simple color
        names (e.g., red, blue, green, etc.), as well as the full range of
        hexadecimal codes (e.g., #FFA0A0, #FF50A8, etc.). Specify how you want
        incidents on the Incident Workbench to appear according to their
        various statuses:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>New</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the color for incidents whose status is <guilabel>New</guilabel>. The
              default color is set to <emphasis>white</emphasis>. Setting no value in this field
              will cause new incident rows to be rendered all <emphasis>black</emphasis>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Feedback</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the color for incidents whose status is
              <guilabel>Feedback</guilabel>. The default color is set to <emphasis>white</emphasis>. Setting no
              value in this field will cause new incident rows to be rendered
              all <emphasis>black</emphasis>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Confirmed</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the color for incidents whose status is
              <guilabel>Confirmed</guilabel>. The default color is set to <emphasis>white</emphasis>. Setting no
              value in this field will cause new incident rows to be rendered
              all <emphasis>black</emphasis>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Assigned</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the color for incidents whose status is
              <guilabel>Assigned</guilabel>. The default color is set to <emphasis>white</emphasis>. Setting no
              value in this field will cause new incident rows to be rendered
              all <emphasis>black</emphasis>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Resolved</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the color for incidents whose status is
              <guilabel>Resolved</guilabel>. The default color is set to <emphasis>white</emphasis>. Setting no
              value in this field will cause new incident rows to be rendered
              all <emphasis>black</emphasis>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Closed</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the color for incidents whose status is <guilabel>Closed</guilabel>.
              The default color is set to <emphasis>white</emphasis>. Setting no value in this
              field will cause new incident rows to be rendered all
              <emphasis>black</emphasis>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Country for Addresses</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want a default country (e.g., United States) to be
        used whenever new addresses are created. While a default address will
        be set, the choice can be overridden manually when creating or editing
        addresses. If not selected, users will need to manually select a
        country when entering addresses.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Enforce Valid Country Names</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If selected, users will be required to select from a list of
        valid countries when creating or editing addresses. Once this box is
        checked and you save the configuration, it will be disabled and you
        cannot uncheck it. If not selected, users will be permitted to enter
        ad hoc country names.</para>
        <warning>
          <para>When you select this option, the application will warn you if
          it finds you have addresses with invalid country names. This
          includes addresses themselves and also documents which use
          addresses—namely, sales orders, invoices, etc. The warning message
          refers to a <literal>fixCountry.gz</literal> extension package,
          which can be downloaded for free from the <ulink
          url="http://www.xtuple.com/xchange">xTuple xChange</ulink>.</para>
        </warning>
        <tip>
          <para>To learn more about editing the list of country names, please
          see <xref linkend="countries" />.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/invalidCountries.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Invalid Countries Warning Message</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
</section>
