<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="configurePO">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>configuration</primary>
      <secondary>of purchase module</secondary>
    </indexterm>Configure Purchase</title>
  <para>To configure the <guimenu>Purchase</guimenu> module, select the <guimenuitem>Configure Purchase</guimenuitem>
  option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configurePO.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Configure Purchase Module</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When configuring the <guimenu>Purchase</guimenu> module, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>purchase orders</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Order # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the available purchase order number generation
        methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Purchase order numbers will be automatically incremented
              by one each time a new purchase order is created. These
              automatically-generated numbers may not be edited. They are
              read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manual</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Purchase order numbers must be entered manually whenever
              you create a new purchase order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Allow Override</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Purchase order numbers will be automatically generated and
              incremented, as under the <guilabel>Automatic</guilabel> option described above.
              However, this option also allows you to manually override the
              purchase order number at the time of purchase order
              creation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Next #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The next sequentially available purchase order number will
              display here. You may change the number—creating a new basis for
              the next purchase order number—by typing the new number into
              this field. Any changes you make here will be reflected the next
              time a new purchase order is created in the <guimenu>Purchase</guimenu>
              module.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>vouchers</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Voucher # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, voucher numbers are automatically generated. This
        system setting cannot be changed.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Next #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The next sequentially available voucher number will
              display here. You may change the number—creating a new basis for
              the next voucher number—by typing the new number into this
              field. Any changes you make here will be reflected the next time
              a new voucher is created in the <guimenu>Purchase</guimenu> module.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>purchase requests</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Purchase Request # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available purchase request number generation
        methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Purchase request numbers will be automatically incremented
              by 1 each time a new purchase request is created. These
              automatically-generated numbers may not be edited. They are
              read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manual</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Purchase request numbers must be entered manually whenever
              you create a new purchase order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Allow Override</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Purchase request numbers will be automatically generated
              and incremented, as under the <guilabel>Automatic</guilabel> option described
              above. However, this option also allows you to manually override
              the purchase request number at the time of purchase request
              creation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Next #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The next sequentially available purchase request number
              will display here. You may change the number—creating a new
              basis for the next purchase request number—by typing the new
              number into this field. Any changes you make here will be
              reflected the next time you issue a new purchase request within
              the <guimenu>Purchase</guimenu> module.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Purchase Order Copies</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicate the copies you want to print.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Vendor</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to print one vendor copy.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Internal</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to print a specified number of internal copies.
              When you select this option, the <guilabel># of Copies</guilabel> field will be
              enabled.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term># of Copies</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the number of copies you want to print.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>vendors</primary>
          <secondary>default settings for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Vendor Defaults</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the following vendor defaults:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Ship Via</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the default ship via to be used for purchase
              orders.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Purchase Order Changes to the Change Log</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post to the Change Log any changes made to purchase
        orders.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post Vendor Changes to the Change Log</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post to the Change Log any changes made to vendor
        masters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Earliest Avail. as Due Date for purchase order item</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to use item source Earliest Available dates as the
        default due date when entering manual purchase order line items. If
        not selected, the due date field will be left blank when entering
        purchase order line items—requiring users to enter the date manually.
        Earliest Available dates are determined by adding item source Lead
        Times to the current date.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The <guilabel>Use Earliest Avail.</guilabel> option applies only to purchase
          orders entered manually. This option does not impact the scheduling
          of POs generated from MRP planned orders.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Prevent Purchase Order Items when no Std. Cost Exists</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to prevent users from entering purchase order
        line items for items which have no standard cost. If selected, users
        will be shown a message stating the problem. The solution is to add
        standard cost to the item(s) in question.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Check Print Purchase Order on Save by Default</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to prompt users to print purchase orders whenever
        purchase orders are saved. If selected, users will be presented with a
        Print Purchase Order screen whenever a purchase order is saved. To
        bypass this feature, do not select this option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Copy Purchase Request notes to Purchase Order Item notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want notes entered on a purchase request to
        transfer to the corresponding purchase order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Require Tax on Purchase Orders</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to require that tax be added to all purchase
        orders. If not selected, tax will not be required.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>drop shipping</primary>
          <secondary>system settings for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Enable Drop Shipments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enable drop ship functionality in the system.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>These drop ship configuration settings will be disabled if
          there are unfinished drop ship transactions in the system. To
          re-enable these options so you can modify the configuration, you
          must first complete all pending drop ship transactions. For example,
          all drop ship purchase receipts must be fully vouchered.</para>
        </tip>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Select Drop Shipped Orders for Billing on Receipt</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to have drop ship items automatically shipped and
              selected for billing at the point when they are received. If not
              selected, drop ship items will need to be manually shipped and
              selected for billing after receipt.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
