<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="configureSO">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>configuration</primary>
      <secondary>of sales module</secondary>
    </indexterm>Configure sales</title>
  <para>To configure the <guimenu>Sales</guimenu> module, go to
  <guimenuitem>Sales &gt; Setup</guimenuitem>. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureSO.png"
                     id="configureSO.imagedata" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption id="configureSO.caption">Sales configuration</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When configuring the <guimenu>Sales</guimenu> module, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Sales Order # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available sales order number generation
        methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manual</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Sales order numbers must be entered manually whenever you
              create a new sales order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Sales order numbers will be automatically incremented by 1
              each time a new sales order is created. These
              automatically-generated numbers may not be edited. They are
              read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Allow Override</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Sales order numbers will be automatically generated and
              incremented, as under the <guilabel>Automatic</guilabel> option
              described above. However, this option also allows you to
              manually override the sales order number at the time of sales
              order creation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Next #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The next sequentially available sales order number will
              display here. You may change the number—creating a new basis for
              the next sales order number—by typing the new number into this
              field. Any changes you make here will be reflected the next time
              a new sales order is created.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Quote # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available quote number generation
        methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manual</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Quote numbers must be entered manually whenever you create
              a new quote.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Use Quote #'s</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Quote numbers will be automatically incremented by one
              each time a new quote is created. These automatically-generated
              numbers may not be edited. They are read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Use Quote #'s, Allow Override</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Quote numbers will be automatically generated and
              incremented, as under the <guilabel>Automatic</guilabel> option
              described above. However, this option also allows you to
              manually override the quote number at the time of quote
              creation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Use S/O #'s</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Quote numbers will be automatically incremented by one
              each time a new quote is created, using the same number
              generation method specified for the creation of sales order
              numbers. These automatically-generated numbers may not be
              edited. They are read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Next #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The next sequentially available quote number will display
              here. You may change the number—creating a new basis for the
              next quote number—by typing the new number into this field. Any
              changes you make here will be reflected the next time a new
              quote is created.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>return authorizations</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Return Auth. # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available return authorization number
        generation methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manual</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Return authorization numbers must be entered manually
              whenever you create a new return authorization.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Use R/A #'s</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Return authorization numbers will be automatically
              incremented by one each time a new return authorization is
              created. These automatically-generated numbers may not be
              edited. They are read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Use R/A #s, Allow Override</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Return authorization numbers will be automatically
              generated and incremented, as under the
              <guilabel>Automatic</guilabel> option described above. However,
              this option also allows you to manually override the return
              authorization number at the time of return authorization
              creation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Next #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The next sequentially available return authorization
              number will display here. You may change the number—creating a
              new basis for the next return authorization number—by typing the
              new number into this field. Any changes you make here will be
              reflected the next time a new return authorization is
              created.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales credits</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Sales Credit # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available sales credit number generation
        methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manual</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Sales credit numbers must be entered manually whenever you
              create a new sales credit.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Use Sales Credit #'s</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Sales credit numbers will be automatically incremented by
              one each time you issue a new sales credit. These
              automatically-generated numbers may not be edited. They are
              read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Use Sales Credit #'s, Allow Override</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Sales credit numbers will be automatically generated and
              incremented, as under the <guilabel>Automatic</guilabel> option
              described above. However, this option also allows you to
              manually override the sales credit number at the time of sales
              credit creation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic, Use S/O #'s</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Sales credit numbers will be automatically incremented by
              1 each time a new sales credit is created, using the same number
              generation method specified for the creation of sales order
              numbers. These automatically-generated numbers may not be
              edited. They are read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Next #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The next sequentially available sales credit number will
              display here. You may change the number—creating a new basis for
              the next sales credit number—by typing the new number into this
              field. Any changes you make here will be reflected the next time
              you issue a new sales credit.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>invoices</primary>
          <secondary>numbering of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Invoice # Generation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available invoice number generation
        methods:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Invoice numbers will be automatically incremented by 1
              each time a new invoice is created. These
              automatically-generated numbers may not be edited. They are
              read-only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Automatic With Override</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Invoice numbers will be automatically generated and
              incremented, as under the <guilabel>Automatic</guilabel> option
              described above. However, this option also allows you to
              manually override the invoice number at the time of invoice
              creation.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Next #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The next sequentially available invoice number will
              display here. You may change the number—creating a new basis for
              the next invoice number—by typing the new number into this
              field. Any changes you make here will be reflected the next time
              you create a new invoice.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To establish general settings for the <guimenu>Sales</guimenu> module,
  select the <guimenuitem>General</guimenuitem> tab. The following options
  will appear:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Print sales Order on Save by Default</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to prompt users to print sales orders whenever sales
        orders are saved. If selected, users will be presented with a Print
        Sales Order screen whenever a sales order is saved. To bypass this
        feature, do not select this option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Perform Credit Limit check on S/O Save</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to perform a check of customers' credit
        before their sales orders are saved. This credit check compares the
        customer's credit limit to the sum of their open sales orders and open
        receivables. If the customer is found to be over their credit limit,
        the sales order cannot be saved—except by users with the override
        privilege. If this option is not selected, normal credit checking will
        occur during the shipping phase.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Date Control</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select from the following date control options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Allow ASAP Schedule Dates</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Selecting this option will cause sales order line items to
              default to the current date if no schedule date is
              entered.</para>
              <note>
                <para>The allocation of available credit memos occurs only
                once—when a sales order is saved for the first time.
                Subsequent saves will not result in additional
                allocations.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Enable Promise Dates</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to display a <guilabel>Promised Date</guilabel>
              field on the Sales Order Line Item screen, by default. If not
              selected, there will be no <guilabel>Promised Date</guilabel>
              field shown on that screen.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Change Log</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select from the following change log options</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Post Customer Changes</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to post to the change log any changes made to
              Customer masters.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Post sales Order Changes</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to post to the change log any changes made to sales
              orders.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Enable Reservations</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enable the sales order reservations functionality
        system-wide. This feature allows for the hard allocation of quantity
        to sales orders. When this feature is selected, the Issue Stock to
        Shipping screen will enforce and disable the option to require
        sufficient inventory. If not selected, the sales order reservation
        options will be hidden from view.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Require Reservations</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>When checked, the quantity issued to shipping will be
              limited by the quantity reserved for a sales order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Reserve by Location</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to set sales reservations for discrete locations
              and lots. The hard allocation of quantity will be for particular
              locations and will prevent other orders from issuing reserved
              inventory. The sales order pick list will print the reserved
              location to expedite inventory picking. You may choose the order
              of precedence for selecting locations: lowest quantity first,
              highest quantity first, or alpha by location name.</para>
              <note>
                <para>Changing the <guilabel>Reserve by Location</guilabel>
                option from enabled to disabled will remove all location
                reservations.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Lowest Quantity First</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Locations for the item will be sorted ascending by
              quantity. Reservations will start with the location with the
              lowest quantity and continue until the quantity required is
              fully reserved or there is insufficient quantity on hand
              (QOH).</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Highest Quantity First</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Locations for the item will be sorted descending by
              quantity. Reservations will start with the location with the
              highest quantity and continue until the quantity required is
              fully reserved or there is insufficient QOH.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Alpha by Location Name</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Locations for the item will be sorted ascending
              alphabetically by the location name. Reservations will start
              with the first location and continue until the quantity required
              is fully reserved or there is insufficient QOH.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Allow Manual Reservations</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, this option allows a user to choose a
              specific lot to be reserved for a sales order item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Control</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select from the following ship control options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Show <guibutton>Save and Add to Packing List</guibutton>
            button on Sales Order</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the <guibutton>SAVE AND ADD TO PACKING
              LIST</guibutton> button to always be displayed on the Sales
              Order header screen. If this option is not selected, the
              <guibutton>SAVE AND ADD TO PACKING LIST</guibutton> button will
              only be displayed for newly-entered sales orders which have not
              yet been saved.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Firm sales orders when added to Packing List Batch</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to make sales order line items firm when the sales
              order they are on is added to the packing list batch.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Enable Shipping interface from Sales Order screen</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to enable the performance of limited shipping
              functionality from the Sales Order header. If selected, users
              will be able to issue stock to shipping and also return stock
              from shipping directly from the Sales Order header. If not
              selected, these shipping options will not be available on the
              Sales Order header.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Check 'Approve for Billing' option on Ship Order</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the <guilabel>Approve for
              Billing</guilabel> option to be selected by default whenever you
              ship sales order line items. Selecting this option reduces steps
              in the billing process. Specifically, if an order is selected
              for billing when it is shipped, you do not then have to take the
              extra step of independently selecting the order for billing.
              This can save time and also ensure your shipped orders are
              selected for billing at the time of shipment.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Credit Control</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select from the following sales credit control options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Restrict Sales Credits to Items on their Apply-To
            Document</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want to restrict sales credit items to their
              apply-to document. Selecting this option narrows the sales
              credit item selection process to only those items which appeared
              on the invoice the sales credit is being applied to. If not
              selected, a sold Item master list will appear instead when
              selecting sales credit items for sales credits applied to a
              specific invoice. This setting has no bearing on unapplied sales
              credits.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Allocate Sales Credits to New Sales Order on Save</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to have open sales credits for a customer
              automatically allocated to any new sales orders entered for that
              customer. This functionality helps reduce customer credit
              balances by ensuring that customer credits are consumed when new
              sales orders are entered. Any available, open sales credits are
              eligible for allocation. The allocation of available sales
              credits occurs only once—when a sales order is saved for the
              first time. Subsequent saves will not result in additional
              allocations. Sales credits which have been allocated to a sales
              order are applied at the point when the invoice resulting from
              the sales order is posted. Once the full balance of a sales
              credit has been applied, the sales credit is then closed. The
              printed invoice the customer receives will indicate whether
              sales credits have been applied. In addition, the total due from
              the customer will be automatically adjusted to reflect any
              applied credits.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Quotes After Converted</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to be able to view historical quotes after
        they have been converted to sales orders. If you don't select this
        option, converted quote information will not be saved.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="xtcommission">
      <term>Use Enhanced Commissions</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enable the enhanced commissions package. To learn more
        about this feature set, please see the <ulink
        url="https://www.xtuple.org/sites/default/files/prodguide/enhanced-commissions/index.html">Enhanced
        Commissions product guide</ulink>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Display Sales Order Line Items Tab by Default</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display the Sales Order window with the
        <guimenuitem>Line Items</guimenuitem> tab displayed initially.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Use Inside Sales Rep</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want the user entering a sales order to be
        recorded automatically as the inside sales rep. If enabled, a
        characteristic called <literal>INSIDEREP</literal> will be added to
        the sales order with the value being the username of the user who is
        entering the order. The inside rep information will be included in the
        Gross Margin Commissions report. If you don't select this option,
        users entering sales orders will not be identified as inside
        reps.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To establish customer pricing options, select the
  <guimenuitem>Pricing</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureSO_pricingTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Pricing</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When establishing customer pricing options, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Price Control</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select from the following price control options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>sales orders</primary>
                <secondary>discount defaults for</secondary>
              </indexterm>Allow Price Discounts</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Check this option to allow pricing discounts for select
              customers. This option instructs the system to verify whether
              any pricing discounts have been established for a customer,
              prior to calculating the line item price for of an item within a
              sales order. If this option is unchecked, then the system will
              apply the full list price for an item within a sales
              order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Disallow Override of Sales Price on Sales Order</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to prevent all users from overriding the sales
              price when entering sales order line items. This is a
              system-wide setting, affecting all users. Do not select this
              option if you want to selectively prevent users from overriding
              sales prices. Individual users may be granted the ability to
              override sales prices, use the <guimenu>Sales</guimenu> module's
              override price privilege.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Hide Misc. Charges on Sales Order screen</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to hide all fields related to miscellaneous charges
              on the <guimenuitem>Line Item</guimenuitem> tab of a Sales Order
              screen. If your site does not use misc. charges when entering
              sales orders, it may make sense to hide this functionality to
              avoid confusion.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item Precedence Over Product Category Pricing</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, item-specific price schedule pricing takes
              precedence over product category pricing. Leave unchecked if the
              lowest overall price should be selected.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use List Price Schedules</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to enable the use of list pricing schedules, also
              known as alternate list pricing. If not selected, standard list
              pricing will be used. To learn more about how alternate list
              pricing works, please see the <ulink
              url="https://xtupleuniversity.xtuple.com/library/articles/alternate-list-pricing">Alternate
              List Pricing article</ulink> at xTupleU.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry id="WholesaleMarkup">
            <term>Use Wholesale Price as Unit Cost for Markups</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, the item wholesale price is used as basis for
              markup pricing. Leave unchecked to use the standard or average
              cost against the item or item site cost.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use "Gross Margin " Method for Markups</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to calculate markup percentage up to 50% as unit
              cost divided by (1 / markup). The price will otherwise be
              calculated as the sum of the unit cost and (unit cost *
              markup).</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry id="configureSO_freightPricing">
      <term>Freight Pricing</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify how you want freight charges to be handled when shipping
        orders and sales credits:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use calculated Freight values by default</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, items issued to shipping will be checked
              against pricing schedules to determine the actual freight for a
              given shipment based on shipping quantities and weight rather
              than assuming all freight should be billed. If not selected, the
              freight amount on an order or sales credit will be billed on
              every shipment.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Include Package Weight in Freight Calculation</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include package weight in the freight
              calculations. If not selected, package weight will be
              excluded.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pricing on Line Item Edits</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the following as your preferred response when
        users change sales order line item quantities:</para>
        <note>
          <para>The sales order line item pricing options apply only when
          editing line item quantity.</para>
        </note>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Update Price</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, the system will automatically update the net
              unit price for the line item, adjusting to accommodate the
              newly-entered quantity.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Do not Update Price</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, the net unit price will not be changed when
              line item quantity is changed on <guibutton>EDIT</guibutton>—and
              users will not be prompted to consider changing the
              price.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Prompt before Updating</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, the system will ask users if they want to
              update the net unit price (YES/NO). If they answer YES because
              they do want to update the price, then they will have to
              manually make the price adjustment.</para>
              <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Ignore if Discounted</term>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select if you want price update warnings to be
                    ignored when line items being edited are already
                    discounted. Also, if sales order header changes cause
                    prices to be updated, any discounted line items will not
                    be updated.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Price Effective Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the following options for when item prices should
        be effective as of:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Current</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want item prices to be effective as of the
              current date.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Order</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want item prices to be effective as of the
              order date.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Scheduled</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want item prices to be effective as of the
              scheduled date.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To establish invoice and credit memo settings, select the
  <guimenuitem>Invoice</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureSO_invoice.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Invoice configuration </caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>When establishing invoice and credit memo settings, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Invoice Date Source</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the following invoice date options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Current Date</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, the invoice date on the invoice header will
              be the same date as the sales order date.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Shipped Date</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, the invoice date on the invoice header will
              be the same date as the sales order ship date.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Scheduled Date</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, the invoice date on the invoice header will
              be the same date as the sales order scheduled date.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Invoice Copies</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicate how you want invoice copies to print.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term># of Copies</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Indicate the number of copies you want to print.
              Information about the specified copies will display
              below.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Sales Credit Copies</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicate how you want sales credit copies to print.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term># of Copies</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Indicate the number of copies you want to print.
              Information about the specified copies will display
              below.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>default configuration for</secondary>
    </indexterm>To establish default settings to be used whenever new
  customers are entered, select the <guimenuitem>Customer
  Defaults</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureSO_customerDefault.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Defaults</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating new customer records, it can be useful to have a core
  set of default values already pre-defined. All these values can be changed
  when you are creating new customers. However, they provide you with a
  default starting point. The following settings you define here will be
  present whenever you create a new customer:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default customer type to be used whenever new
        customers are created.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Rep</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default sales representative to be used whenever new
        customers are created.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Via</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default ship via to be used whenever new customers are
        created.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Form</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default shipping form to be used whenever new
        customers are created.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Charges</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default shipping charge to be used whenever new
        customers are created.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Preferred Selling Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a preferred selling site to be used whenever new
        customers are created.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Terms</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the default billing terms to be used whenever new
        customers are created.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Balance Method</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a default procedure for handling cash receipts from
        customers. This notation is informational only.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Balance Forward</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to indicate you want to apply cash receipts to the
              customer's current balance due.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Open Item</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to indicate you want to apply cash receipts to
              specific customer open items.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Accepts Partial Shipments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate customers accept partial shipments by
        default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Accepts Backorders</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate customers accept backorders by
        default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Allow Free Form Ship-Tos</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate customers allow free-form ship-tos by
        default. This default appears on the Customer master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Limit</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the default credit limit to be used for all
        customers.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Rating</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the default credit rating to be used for all
        customers.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para role="standard"><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>return authorizations</primary>
      <secondary>configuration for</secondary>
    </indexterm>To define your system's return authorization configuration,
  select the <guimenuitem>Return</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <screenshot role="standard">
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/configureSO_returns.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Returns configuration</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para role="standard">When configuring return authorization settings, you
  are presented with the following options:</para>
  <para role="standard"><variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Enable Return Authorizations</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Select to enable the system's return authorizations
          capability. If not selected, users will be prevented from performing
          any tasks related to return authorizations—and related functionality
          will be hidden from view. For systems where return authorizations
          are enabled, this option will be hidden.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Post Return Authorization Changes to the Change Log</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Select to record changes made to return authorizations in the
          return authorization change log. If not selected, the return
          authorization changelog will not contain change information.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Default Disposition</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Specify one of the following default methods for handling
          return authorizations:</para>
          <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Credit</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select if, by default, you want to issue credit to
                customers for authorized line items and quantities. No return
                is required or expected. Return authorization line items will
                close when an associated credit memo is posted.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Return</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select if, by default, you want to authorize returns
                from customers. Return authorization items will close when an
                associated credit memo is posted, or when all items on a line
                have been returned, whichever comes last.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Replace</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select if, by default, you want to replace items
                returned by customers. Authorized quantities will be added as
                additional order quantity to an associated sales order line,
                which in turn should be reopened if closed. Return
                authorization items will close when all items on the line have
                been returned or all authorized items on the line have been
                shipped, whichever comes last. No money should be involved
                when invoicing replacement items.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Service</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select if, by default, you want to repair or service
                items returned by customers. Service or repair items will
                first be received by a return authorization. Then a new sales
                order with linked work order(s) will be created to track work
                and shipping on the repair or service. The new sales order
                will be on RMA hold until items have been received by the
                return authorization.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Substitute</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select if, by default, you want to authorize the
                substitution of items returned by customers. Under this
                option, when an original sales order is imported into the
                return authorization, the return authorization Line items will
                default to the return disposition. Any new line items added
                beyond the original ones will have a default disposition of
                ship.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
          </variablelist>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Credit/Ship</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Specify the default timetable for customer credits and/or
          returns:</para>
          <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Immediately</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select to issue credit or send returns to customers
                immediately by default.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Upon Receipt</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select to issue credit or send returns to customers only
                after you have received returned goods from them by
                default.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
          </variablelist>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Default Credit Method</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Specify one of the following default credit method
          options:</para>
          <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>None</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select if, by default, you do not issue credit for
                customer returns.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Credit Memo</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select if, by default, you credit customer returns with
                a credit memo to the customer's account. This option will
                result in the automatic creation of a sales credit
                memo.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Payment</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select if, by default, you credit customer returns by
                sending them a payment. This option will create a credit memo,
                then a misc. payment that applies to the credit memo.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Credit Card</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select if, by default, you credit customer returns with
                a refund on their credit card.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
          </variablelist>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Check Print on Save by Default</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Select if you want the <guilabel>Print on Save</guilabel>
          option to always be enabled when creating new return
          authorizations.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Close Return Authorization when Crediting</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>If selected, return authorization line items will be closed
          automatically when a return credit is created and posted.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist></para>
  <para>To enable and/or configure the Simple Sales Order screen, select the
  <guimenuitem>Simple S/O</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/configureSO_simpleSO.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Simple S/O configuration</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When enabling or configuring the Simple Sales Order screen, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Enable Simple S/O</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enable the Simple Sales Order screen. The simple sales
        order is an easy-to-use alternative interface for quickly processing
        non-complex sales orders. The screen is ideally suited for
        environments where complex order information is not required (e.g.,
        counter sales, retail, etc.). If enabled, the screen will be available
        from the <guimenuitem>Sales &gt; Sales Order</guimenuitem> menu. If
        disabled, the menu option will not appear.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cash Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a customer number to be used as the default cash-paying
        customer when entering simple sales orders. During order entry, you
        may easily override the default with either pre-existing other or new
        customer information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sale Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the sale type to be used for sales orders entered using
        the Simple Sales Order screen. The sale type selection impacts the
        sales account assignment for orders entered using this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Require Sufficient Inventory to Ship</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to ensure you have enough QOH in stock of a line item
        prior to shipping. If selected, this option will prevent you from
        shipping a line item if doing so would force QOH for the item site to
        fall below zero. Not selecting this option means shipping may drive
        QOH negative.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Print S/O Acknowledgement (Hold Only)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to automatically prompt for printing a sales order
        acknowledgement form when a simple sales order is held. If not
        selected, users won't be prompted to print the acknowledgement form
        when holding a simple sales order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Print Shipping Packing List</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to automatically prompt for printing a shipping packing
        list when payment for the simple sales order is posted. If not
        selected, users won't be prompted to print the packing list when
        posting payment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Print Invoice</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to automatically prompt for printing an invoice when
        payment for the simple sales order is posted. If not selected, users
        won't be prompted to print an invoice when posting payment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
