<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="copyPurchaseOrder">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>purchase orders</primary>
      <secondary>copying of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Copy Purchase Order</title>
  <para>To copy a purchase order, select the COPY button on the "Purchase
  Order History" display screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/copyPurchaseOrder.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Copy Purchase Order</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>The copy functionality can be used as a <indexterm
        significance="normal">
        <primary>purchase orders</primary>
        <secondary>templates for</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>purchase orders</primary>
        <secondary>handling repetitive</secondary>
      </indexterm>templating mechanism for repetitive Purchase Orders.
    Consider creating a template purchase order and then simply copy it whenever you need
    to send out a new one.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When copying purchase order history, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Purchase Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the purchase order Number for the purchase order you
        are copying.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the original order date for the purchase order you are
        copying.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vendor #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the vendor Number for the purchase order you are
        copying. The vendor name and phone number will also display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Original Line Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists the line items which originally appeared on the
        purchase order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Today's Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to use today's date as the order date for the purchase
        order copy. Due dates for purchase order line items will be adjusted
        automatically from today's date using item source Lead Times, if
        any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Schedule Purchase Order for</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a date to use as the order date for the purchase order
        copy. Due dates for purchase order line items will be adjusted
        automatically from the specified date using item source Lead Times, if
        any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use latest Item Sources and Prices</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to use the most current item source information,
        including up-to-date item source Prices. If not selected, the purchase
        order copy will use the item source information, including item source
        Prices, in effect at the time of the original purchase order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
