<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="costCategory">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>cost categories</primary>

      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Cost Category</title>

  <para>To create a new cost category, select the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton>
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/costCategory.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Create New Cost Category</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating a new cost category, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <note>
    <para>By default, the screen will limit your account number choices to
    only those accounts having the correct account type for the chosen
    context. However, privileged users may override this default behavior by
    manually entering any account number listed in the chart of
    accounts.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Category</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the cost category name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a brief description of the cost category.</para>

        <tip>
          <para>The account numbers assigned to cost categories should not all
          be the inventory account. Instead, they should be individual
          accounts selected specifically for each cost-tracking purpose. This
          will increase your visibility into your inventory costs and
          valuation.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Asset</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a general ledger (G/L) Account to distribute inventory
        assets to. This is an asset account. It will be debited when inventory
        is received and credited whenever inventory items are removed from
        inventory.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expense</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to be used for expensing purchase
        receipts for items having a control method of "None." This is an
        expense account. It will be debited when non-inventory purchase
        receipts are posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>WIP Asset</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to distribute work-in-process (WIP)
        assets to. This is an asset account. It will be credited and/or
        debited with labor, material, and <indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>overhead</primary>

            <secondary>linking to wip assets</secondary>
          </indexterm>overhead costs while a work order is in-process. The
        sense of the transaction record depends on the circumstances of the
        transaction.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Cost Variance</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to distribute inventory cost variances
        to. This is an asset account. It is used in several scenarios: 1) If
        there is a difference between new actual cost and old standard cost
        when posting actual costs to standard; 2) during work order processing
        if too many materials are issued to a work order, or if a work order
        is closed without the full quantity being posted. The sense of the
        transaction record depends on the circumstances of the
        transaction.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Transform Clearing</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to distribute transform transactions to.
        This is an asset account. It will be credited when a source item
        quantity is transformed, and debited for an equal amount when the
        target item quantity is received into inventory.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Purchase Price Variance</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to distribute purchase price variances
        to. This is an asset account. It will be credited or debited with the
        value of any variance that may arise when a voucher is posted. The
        sense of the transaction record depends on the circumstances of the
        transaction.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Adjustment</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to distribute inventory adjustments to.
        This is an expense account. It will be credited or debited with the
        value of any variance that may arise when a miscellaneous adjustment
        transaction or count tag transaction is posted against an item. The
        sense of the transaction record depends on the circumstances of the
        transaction.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Scrap</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to distribute inventory scrap to. This is
        an expense account. It will be credited when a scrap transaction is
        posted against an item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Manufacturing Scrap</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to distribute manufacturing scrap to.
        This is an expense account. It will be credited when work order
        material requirements are scrapped from a work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>P/O Liability Clearing</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to distribute purchase order liability
        clearing to. This is a liability account. It will be credited when a
        purchase order receipt is posted and debited when a voucher is
        posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Asset</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to distribute shipping assets to. This is
        an asset account. It will be debited with the standard cost of a sales
        order item when the item is issued to shipping and credited once the
        item has been shipped.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Item Freight Expense</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to distribute purchase order or transfer
        order line item freight expenses to. This is an expense account. It
        will be debited when purchase order or transfer order line items are
        received. The account may be debited or credited when correcting
        purchase order receipts.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Transfer Order Liability Clearing</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to distribute transfer order liability
        clearing to. This is a liability account. It is used for recognizing
        liability related to transportation costs related to transfer orders.
        It will be credited when transfer orders receipts having freight
        charges are posted. It should be debited when the freight (or other
        vendor) is paid by miscellaneous check.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term>Labor and Overhead Costs</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Overhead costs: Identify a G/L account to distribute labor and
        overhead costs to. This is a liability account. It will be debited
        and/or credited with labor and overhead costs when work orders are
        in-process or posted. The sense of the transaction record depends on
        the circumstances of the transaction.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
