<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="createPlannedOrdersByPlannerCode">
  <title>Run MRP by Planner Code</title>
  <para>When you run MRP by planner code, you are running the material
  requirements planning (MRP) system. This utility creates planned
  replenishment orders to meet existing sales order and work order demand.
  replenishment orders will be created whenever a planned availability for an
  item site falls below its Reorder Level. The quantity of the Replenishment
  order will be enough to restore planned availability back to the Reorder
  Level—or to the order Up To (OUT) Level, if the OUT Level is greater.</para>
  <note>
    <para>Running MRP by planner code may be used to generate planned orders
    for both parent-level manufactured items and also lower level purchased
    items. Only items designated as MRP items will be affected by an MRP run.
    Unposted purchase orders and purchase requests are considered as valid
    sources of supply when MRP is run.</para>
  </note>
  <para>Depending on the size of your database and the amount of demand in the
  system, running MRP can take some time to complete. To compensate for this,
  companies often schedule MRP runs so they run overnight, using xTuple
  Connect. If you are running MRP during regular business hours, you will see
  there is a progress indicator showing how far along the MRP job is. The
  progress screen also features a cancel option, which allows you to kill the
  MRP job if you feel it has gone on for too long.</para>
  <para>To run MRP by planner code, select the "Run MRP by Planner Code"
  option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/createPlannedOrdersByPlannerCode.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Run MRP by Planner Code</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>The system deletes any non-firmed planned orders when MRP is run. If
    demand for the deleted planned orders still exists, the orders will be
    replaced by new Replenishment orders having new planned order numbers.
    Order quantities will also be updated if demand levels have changed since
    MRP was last run.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When running MRP by planner code, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Planner Codes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create planned replenishment orders for all planner
        codes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify planner code you want to create planned replenishment
        orders for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a planner code pattern to select a range of planner codes.
        Refine your search using Regular Expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Sites</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create planned replenishment orders by planner code
        for all sites.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify site planned replenishment orders should be created
        for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cutoff Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify how far into the future the MRP run should look for
        demand. If you schedule an MRP or MPS job submitted to the xTuple
        Connect Batch Manager to run on a periodic basis—daily, weekly,
        monthly—the cutoff date used for the run will automatically be updated
        by the number of days in the specified reschedule interval (Day = +1,
        Week = +7, and Month = +30).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>firmed orders</primary>
          <secondary>deletion of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Delete Existing Firmed MRP Orders</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to delete existing Firmed orders. A
        firm planned order is a planned order that has been solidified in the
        schedule. By default, firm planned orders are not deleted when MRP is
        run. Selecting this option overrides that default behavior. If firm
        planned orders are deleted when MRP is run, they will automatically be
        replaced by soft (i.e., non-firmed) planned orders, assuming the
        demand for the requirements still exists.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Create MRP Exceptions</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If you are using the MRP Exceptions feature set for planning
        purposes, you should always select this option when running MRP. Not
        only will this option create MRP Exceptions for you—it will also force
        MRP to recognize those exceptions and adjust its calculations when
        creating planned orders. The end result will be planned orders that
        are netted against the known exceptions. Planner code options related
        to exceptions handling may also impact your results. If you do not
        select this option—and you are using the MRP Exceptions feature
        set—the netting effect will not be applied and you could end up with
        excess supply orders. Do not select this option if you are not using
        the MRP Exceptions feature set. For more information about MRP
        Exceptions, please see <xref linkend="dspMRPException" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>OK</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates planned replenishment orders by planner code, using the
        specified parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
