<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="createInvoices">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>invoices</primary>
      <secondary>creation of</secondary>
    </indexterm>New Invoice</title>
  <para>Invoices are created from sales orders that have been selected for
  billing. To create invoices for orders which have been selected for billing,
  choose the "Create Invoices" option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/postBillingSelections.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create Invoices</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating invoices, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Customer Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create invoices for all customer types.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify customer type whose invoices you want to create.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a customer type pattern to select a range of customer
        Types. Refine your search using Regular Expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Consolidate by Customer</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to cause all sales orders selected for billing to be
        consolidated on one invoice by customer. Keep in mind, though, that to
        be consolidated the orders must have matching criteria (e.g., Billing,
        Tax, sales Rep information). If the criteria do not match, then
        non-conforming orders will not be consolidated. (Separate invoices
        will be created for them instead.) If only a single order exists, at
        all or in a group, then it will be posted as a single invoice.
        Consolidated orders are given a combined header, and the line items
        are attached to the invoice in no particular order. Line items
        themselves are never consolidated (i.e., you can have two lines for
        the same item). In addition, invoice line items have a reference back
        to their original sales order item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CREATE INVOICES</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to create invoices for all orders selected
        for billing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
