<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="createCycleCountTags">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>cycle count tags</primary>
      <secondary>creating by site</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>cycle counts</primary>
      <secondary>creating tags for</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>physical inventory</primary>
      <secondary>creating cycle count tags</secondary>
    </indexterm>Create Cycle Count Tags by Site</title>
  <para>Cycle Count Tags are used to count inventory on a frequent basis, with
  the rate of frequency defined in the Item Site master. The following
  criteria are used to determine the order in which Cycle Count Tags will be
  created for a specified site(s):</para>
  <orderedlist continuation="restarts" inheritnum="ignore">
    <listitem>
      <para>The system scans the Item Site masters in the specified site(s),
      specifically targeting Cycle Count frequency settings.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>The frequency settings are then compared to the last counted dates
      for each item site to determine which item sites have last counted dates
      most out of sync with their count frequency rate; item sites whose last
      counted dates are most out of sync with their stated frequency rate will
      have Cycle Count Tags created for them first.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>After frequency and last counted date parameters have been
      considered, the item site's ABC Class is used—with A Class item sites
      having Cycle Count Tags created first.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Then, finally, Cycle Count Tags are created based on the item
      numbers for the item sites in ascending order (i.e., 1, 2, 3 ... A, B,
      C).</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>The total number of Cycle Count Tags to be created is determined
      beforehand.</para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <para>The difference between Cycle Count Tags and Count Tags is that Cycle
  Count Tags are generated dynamically, using the criteria listed above. Count
  Tags are generated manually, on demand.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>To monitor the frequency of item site Cycle Counts, view the
    <guilabel>Last Counted</guilabel> column in any of the item site Reports:
    by item, by class code, etc. The Last Counted date represents the date a
    Count Tag was last posted (not simply issued) for the item site.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To create Cycle Count Tags by site, select the <guimenuitem>Create
  Cycle Count Tags by Site</guimenuitem> option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/createCycleCountTags.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create Cycle Count Tags by Site</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating Cycle Count Tags by site, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Sites in</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which of the following codes you want to have Cycle
        Count Tags created for:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Class Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, you will be presented with class code
              options.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Planner Code</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, you will be presented with planner code
              options.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify site where Cycle Count will be conducted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Mark Created Count Tag as Priority</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to give priority status to Count Tag. Count Tags marked
        as having priority status are listed first in any prioritized lists.
        For example, priority Count Tags will appear at the top of the Count
        Tag Edit list; whereas, non-priority Count Tags will appear at the
        bottom of the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>freezing</primary>
          <secondary>of inventory</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>inventory</primary>
          <secondary>freezing during cycle counts</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>cycle counts</primary>
          <secondary>freezing inventory during</secondary>
        </indexterm>Freeze Inventory</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to freeze inventory. The quantity on hand (QOH) value is
        not updated when a transaction is posted against a frozen item site.
        Instead, inventory transactions are pooled and then posted later when
        the item site is unfrozen—or thawed. The QOH is updated when the item
        site is thawed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>When an item site is frozen, any site activity entered against that
    item site—including work orders—will use the QOH shown at the time of
    freezing.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ignore Zero Balance Item Sites</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to ignore item sites which have a QOH balance of zero. If
        selected, Count Tags will not be created for any item site having a
        QOH balance of zero.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Maximum Number of Tags to Create</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
        value up to a maximum of 1,000.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Only for Specified Location</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to create Count Tags for an individual site
        location. If selected, you will have the option to specify which site
        location you want to have Count Tags created for. This option enables
        you to count individual site locations separately, without having to
        post counts for an entire site all at once.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>cycle counters</primary>
          <secondary>creating instructions for</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>cycle counts</primary>
          <secondary>creating instructions for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Comments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        comments related to the Cycle Count. Use the
        <guilabel>Comments</guilabel> field to enter any instructions or other
        comments that need to reach and be read by the cycle counters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>CREATE TAGS</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates Cycle Count Tags. Cycle Count Tag numbers are generated
        automatically in an ordered sequence.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
