<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="createCountTagsByPlannerCode">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>count tags</primary>

      <secondary>creating by planner code</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>physical inventory</primary>

      <secondary>creating count tags</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>planner codes</primary>

      <secondary>count tags created by</secondary>
    </indexterm>Create Count Tags by Planner Code</title>

  <para>Count tags are used to spearhead inventory counts. They are created
  manually and on-demand, and they are not tied to any particular cycle or
  frequency, as cycle count tags are. To create count tags by planner code, go
  to <guimenuitem>Inventory &gt; Physical Inventory &gt; Create Count Tags
  &gt; by Planner Code</guimenuitem>. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/createCountTagsByPlannerCode.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Create Count Tags by Planner Code</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating count tags by planner code, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <tip>
    <para>By default, the system allows only one unposted count tag per item
    site. To view all unposted count tags in your system, see the count tag
    edit list.</para>
  </tip>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Planner Codes</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create count tags for all planner codes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify planner code you want to create count tags for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a planner code pattern to select a range of planner codes.
        Refine your search using regular expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify site the count tags are to be created for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Mark Created Count Tag as Priority</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to give priority status to count tag. Count tags marked
        as having priority status are listed first in any prioritized lists.
        For example, priority count tags will appear at the top of the count
        tag edit list; whereas, non-priority count tags will appear at the
        bottom of the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>freezing</primary>

          <secondary>of inventory</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>inventory</primary>

          <secondary>freezing at count tag creation</secondary>
        </indexterm>Freeze Inventory</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to freeze inventory. The quantity on hand (QOH) value is
        not updated when a transaction is posted against a frozen item site.
        Instead, inventory transactions are pooled and then posted later when
        the item site is unfrozen—or thawed. The QOH is later updated when the
        item site is thawed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>When an item site is frozen, any inventory transactions entered
    against that item site will not update the system-wide QOH until after the
    item site is thawed and its count tag posted. If an item site is frozen
    when a count tag is created, both the inventory count and the
    corresponding general ledger (G/L) transactions will use the count tag
    created (i.e., frozen) date when the count tag is posted.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ignore Zero Balance Item Sites</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to ignore item sites which have a QOH balance of zero. If
        selected, count tags will not be created for any item site having a
        QOH balance of zero.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Only for Specified Location</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to create count tags for an individual site
        location. If selected, you will have the option to specify which site
        location you want to have count tags created for. This option enables
        you to count individual site locations separately, without having to
        post counts for an entire site all at once.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>cycle counters</primary>

          <secondary>creating instructions for</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>cycle counts</primary>

          <secondary>creating instructions for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Notes</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        notes related to the count tag. Use the <guilabel>Notes</guilabel>
        field to enter any instructions or other notes that need to reach and
        be read by the inventory counters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>CREATE TAGS</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Creates count tags. Count tag numbers are generated
        automatically in an ordered sequence.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
