<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="creditMemo">
  <title id="Anchor94106"><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales credits</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm> New Sales Credit</title>
  <para>To create a sales credit, select the "New Sales Credit" option. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/creditMemo.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Sales Credit</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Credit #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Next available sales credit number will automatically display,
        unless your system requires you to enter sales credit numbers
        manually.</para>
        <para>Default values and input parameters for sales credit numbers are
        configurable at the system level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Apply To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Invoice Number of the Invoice you want to apply the
        sales credit to, using the lookup feature located to the right of the
        field. The list will include Invoices for the specified Customer. If a
        sales credit is applied to a specific Invoice, the sales credit may
        only credit items which appeared on the chosen Invoice. If for some
        reason the sales credit is applied to a closed Invoice, the sales
        credit will be listed as an unapplied sales credit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a date representing the date when you want the sales
        credit to be distributed. When a sales credit is posted, it is posted
        effective as of the credit date.</para>
        <para><note>
            <para>You are not required to apply a sales credit to a specific
            Invoice. If a sales credit is applied to an Invoice, any sales
            credit items will be sales credited to inventory when the sales
            credit is posted.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Status</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicates whether sales credit is posted or unposted.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>The quickest way to fill in the Sales Credit screen may be to
          select the Invoice you intend to credit using the "Apply To"
          feature. If you use this feature, most of the fields in the Sales
          Credit screen will automatically populate with the needed Customer
          information.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Rep.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the sales Representative associated with the order. By
        default, the Customer's designated sales Representative will appear in
        the field—except if you have selected an Invoice to apply the sales
        credit to. In that case, the sales Representative credited with the
        Invoice will be selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Commission</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the commission percentage recorded on the Customer
        master will be automatically entered in this field. If for some reason
        you select a non-default sales Representative at sales credit entry,
        the commission rate will not change. To adjust the commission rate,
        you must make the change manually.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax zones</primary>
          <secondary>for sales credits</secondary>
        </indexterm>Tax Zone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Tax Zone associated with the sales credit. The Tax
        Zone for the specified Ship-To Address will be entered here by
        default. Otherwise, the primary Tax Zone for the Customer will be
        entered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Reason Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the reason why an adjustment is being made to a
        Customer's account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales credits</primary>
          <secondary>hold options for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Place on Hold</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to place sales credit on hold. If a sales credit is
        placed on hold, it cannot be posted. You would place a sales credit on
        hold, for example, to allow time for producing and processing a Return
        Material Authorization (RMA) document. To remove a hold and allow
        posting of a sales credit, de-select this option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If your system is configured to use Projects, select a Project
        Number to associate with the sales credit.</para>
        <para role="xtprjaccnt">When you have the xTuple Project Accounting
        package installed—and you link a Project to the sales credit—the
        Project Number will be added as the final segment of affected G/L
        Account Numbers when the sales credit is posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sale Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Sale Type.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Zone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Shipping Zone.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales credits</primary>
          <secondary>customers associated with</secondary>
        </indexterm>Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Customer Number of the Customer you want to issue the
        sales credit to. The lookup feature located to the right of the field
        leads to a searchable Customers list. You may also access this list
        using the keyboard shortcut "CTRL + L". Once a Customer Number is
        entered, the Customer name and billing address will display. Select
        the "?" or "$" symbol to view Customer information for the specified
        Customer. If a Customer's credit is "In Good Standing," the button
        will feature a black question mark ("?") icon. If the icon turns to an
        orange dollar sign ("$"), the Customer's credit Status is "On Credit
        Warning." A red dollar sign ("$") indicates the Customer's credit
        Status is "On Credit Hold."</para>
        <note>
          <para>Sales credits may be entered for inactive Customers. The same
          does not hold true for sales orders.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales credits</primary>
          <secondary>billing information for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Bill-To Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer's Bill-To name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Customer's Bill-To Address. You may manually
        override the displayed Address information in the fields below—or use
        the lookup feature to select another Address. If a new Address is
        manually entered here, that Address will be added automatically to the
        master list of Addresses. For additional documentation related to
        creating Addresses, see <xref linkend="address" />.<note>
            <para>A sales credit that is applied to an Invoice will by default
            have the Address that appeared on the Invoice.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Copy to Ship-to -\&gt;</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to copy contents of billing address into Ship-To address
        field. This option is enabled if the Customer master for the specified
        Customer indicates that free-form Ship-To's are allowed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-From #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the number of the preferred Ship-To Address. Customers may
        maintain multiple Ship-To Addresses. If the Customer master for the
        specified Customer indicates that free-form Ship-To's are allowed,
        then any address may be entered. If free-form Ship-To's are not
        allowed, then the Ship-To Address must be entered using the browse
        button located to the right of the field. The lookup feature leads to
        a searchable Ship-To Addresses list.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>Make sure the Ship-To Address on the sales credit matches the
          Ship-To Address on the Customer's Pricing Schedule. If they don"t
          match, you won"t be able to issue credit for exclusively sold
          items.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales credits</primary>
          <secondary>ship-to details for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Ship-From Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name for the specified Ship-To.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the specified Ship-To Address. You may manually
        override the displayed Address information in the fields below—or use
        the lookup feature to select another Address. If a new Address is
        manually entered here, that Address will be added automatically to the
        master list of Addresses. For additional documentation related to
        creating Addresses, see <xref linkend="address" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. PO #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the Customer purchase order number associated with
        the Invoice being credited will display here. If no Customer purchase
        order number was entered at the time of the original sales order—or if
        the sales credit is not being applied to a specific Invoice—the field
        will remain blank. Enter or edit a Customer purchase order number as
        necessary.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales credits</primary>
      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create or modify sales credit line items, select the "Line
  Items" tab at the top of the "Sales Credit" screen. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/creditMemo_itemsTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Sales Credit Line Items</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating or modifying sales credit line items, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists sales order line item quantities that have been
        returned and selected for credit. line items are added to a sales
        credit using the NEW ITEM button.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>Before creating a new sales credit line item, be sure to
          specify an Invoice to apply the sales credit to. The "Apply To"
          feature is found on the Sales Credit header screen.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subtotal</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the subtotal for the sales credit line items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales credits</primary>
          <secondary>charges related to</secondary>
        </indexterm>Misc. Charge</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of the miscellaneous charge. Before entering a
        miscellaneous charge amount, you must first assign the charge to a
        sales Account and also enter a description of the charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description to identify the miscellaneous charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Credit Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a credit Account to assign the miscellaneous charge
        to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of freight charge to be added to the specified
        order. The freight charge may be entered during the creation or
        modification of a sales credit—or at the time of shipment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount of Tax to be charged on the sales
        credit. Sales Tax is calculated at the sales credit line item level.
        The Tax amount displayed here represents the total for all line item
        Tax amounts. To get a detailed view of the Tax calculation, click on
        the Tax link using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount of the sales credit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add Notes to a sales credit, select the "Notes" tab at the top of
  the "Sales Credit" screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/creditMemo_notesTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Sales Credit Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding Notes to a sales credit, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        Notes related to the sales credit. Notes entered on this screen will
        follow the sales credit through the billing process. For example, you
        may view notes associated with a posted sales credit within the
        Customer History report.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To associate documents with a sales credit, select the "Documents"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/creditMemo_documentsTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Sales Credit Documents</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/documents.xml" xpointer="documentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
  <xi:include href="creditMemoItem.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
