<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="creditMemoItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales credits</primary>
      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Sales Credit Item</title>
  <para>To create a new sales credit line item, select the
  <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/creditMemoItem.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create new Sales Credit Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new sales credit line item, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Credit #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the sales credit number for the current sales
        credit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the line number assigned to the sales credit
        item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicate the item type for the sales credit line item, by
        selecting one of the following options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The lookup feature located to the right of the field leads
              to a searchable list of inventory items. If the sales credit is
              being applied to a particular invoice—and your
              <guimenu>Sales</guimenu> module is configured to restrict sales
              credits to items appearing on their apply-to document—then the
              item list will show only items on the original invoice. The
              <guibutton>ITEM/ALIAS SEARCH</guibutton> button can also be used
              to help locate sales credit items. Once an item number is
              entered, the inventory unit of measure and item description will
              automatically appear. Additionally, you may also specify the
              item's receiving site. Commercial editions of xTuple allow items
              to be received into multiple sites.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Miscellaneous</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter a name and description for the miscellaneous,
              non-inventory item you are billing the customer for. The
              <guilabel>Name</guilabel> and <guilabel>Description</guilabel>
              fields are free-form, meaning they accept unlimited alphanumeric
              characters. You must also select a sales category. Sales
              categories are used to identify the general ledger (G/L)
              accounts to be used when non-inventory sales transactions take
              place.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Reason Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the reason why an adjustment is being made to a
        customer's account.</para>
        <para><note>
            <para>By default, the reason code on the sales credit header will
            be used at the line item level. However, you may change the reason
            code for individual line items.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Alternate Revenue Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify an alternate account to be used as the revenue account.
        This account will be used instead of the typical accounts pre-defined
        in the receivables assignments. For example, you might use this
        alternate account in the scenario where you are doing business with
        customers who are part of the same buyer's group (i.e., customer
        Group).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Returned</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the item returned for credit. If the sales
        credit was created from a return authorization, the quantity returned
        will be zero on the Sales Credit Item screen. Return authorization
        returns are handled separately, outside of the normal sales credit
        inventory handling process.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Update Inventory</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the quantity returned to be added back
              into inventory when you post the sales credit. If not selected,
              your inventory will not be updated.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. To Credit</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the item you plan to give the customer
        credit for. The quantity entered here may equal the quantity returned.
        However, you have the flexibility to credit the customer for a
        quantity different from the returned quantity. The quantity credited
        is multiplied by the net unit price to determine the amount of the
        credit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The unit of measure being returned and credited in. You may also
        select a global conversion ratio here. Global conversions have the
        label <literal>Global</literal> appended to them.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Shipped</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the quantity of the item shipped to date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount % from Sale</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a percentage to reduce the credited amount by. The
        discount will be deducted from the sale price, thereby reducing the
        amount of the credit by the specified percentage.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales credits</primary>
          <secondary>pricing of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Net Unit Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the net unit price to assign the quantity being
        credited. If the sales credit is being applied to a specific invoice,
        then the system will automatically enter the item's net unit price as
        it appeared on the referring invoice. If no invoice is being
        applied-to, then the system will choose the lower of the following two
        prices: A) The most-specific pricing schedule assignment or B) any
        sale in effect at the time of order entry. The specificity of pricing
        schedule assignments is determined in the following descending order:
        by customer ship-to address (most specific), by customer, by customer
        type, by customer type pattern, by all customers. The lookup feature
        located to the right of the field leads to a Price List screen.</para>
        <para>If your pricing schedule has multiple units of measure (UOM) on
        it (or if several pricing schedules share the same level of price
        specificity, but they have different UOMs) then the UOM which matches
        the selected UOM will be chosen—that is, as long as the quantity break
        does not exceed the quantity being priced. If no entry matches the UOM
        with a quantity break less than the quantity being priced, then the
        lowest value price for any UOM will be chosen. To make sure a specific
        UOM is always chosen at the desired level of price specificity, then
        your pricing schedules should include at least one UOM with a quantity
        break of 0.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>The system can be configured to prevent users from editing the
          net unit price. If your system is configured that way, the
          <guilabel>Net Unit Price</guilabel> field will not be
          editable.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pricing UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the item's price UOM. You may also select a global
        conversion ratio here. Global conversions have the label
        <literal>Global</literal> appended to them.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Extended Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the extended price. The extended price for a sales
        credit item is based on the quantity credited multiplied by the
        price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Unit Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the standard cost per unit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>List Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the item's list price per unit displays.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sale Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the sold price for the item at the time of sale.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales credits</primary>
          <secondary>discount pricing for</secondary>
        </indexterm>List Discount %</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The default customer discount (if any) will display here.
        Default customer discount percentages are defined in the Customer
        master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the tax type for the sales credit item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the amount of tax to be charged for the sales credit
        line item quantity. To get a detailed view of the tax calculation,
        click on the <guibutton>Tax</guibutton> link using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Click on the <guimenuitem>Notes</guimenuitem> tab to enter notes and
  you will be presented with the following screen:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/creditMemoItem_notes.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Create new Sales Credit Item Notes</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        notes related to the sales credit item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
