<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="currency">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>currencies</primary>
      <secondary>adding new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Currency</title>
  <para>To add a new currency to the master list of currencies, select the NEW
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/currency.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Currency</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Standard currency information for most countries is provided by
    default as part of the standard country list: <xref
    linkend="countries" />. Simply select this information by country when
    setting up multiple currencies.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When adding a new currency to the master list of currencies, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name to describe the currency.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Symbol</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a symbol to identify the currency. Use special keyboard
        characters to enter special currency symbols. For example, under
        Windows, you can create the symbol for Japanese Yen by using the
        following keys: ALT + 0165. If you change the symbol for your base
        currency, you must restart the application to ensure the change is
        populated throughout the system.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Abbreviation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter an abbreviation to identify the currency.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Base Currency</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify whether the currency is the base currency. The base
        currency is the currency used for all general ledger (G/L)
        transactions. Only one base currency may be defined per each database.
        Any transactions conducted in a foreign currency will be converted
        automatically to the base currency (using the prevailing Exchange
        Rate) before they are posted to the G/L.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Choose your base currency carefully. Once you indicate a given
    currency is the base currency, you will not be able to change that
    selection using the application. Consult your system administrator if this
    situation occurs.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SELECT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use this button to specify a country when creating a new
        currency definition. This button will only be enabled when creating
        new currency definitions. Otherwise it will be disabled. </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To select currency information by country, choose the SELECT button.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/currencySelect.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Select Currency by Country</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Make any changes to the currency information for a country on the
    Country master screen.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When selecting currency information by country, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Country</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the country you want to assign the currency to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Currency Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name of the currency for the specified
        country.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Symbol</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the symbol for the currency of the specified
        country.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Abbreviation</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the abbreviation for the currency of the specified
        country.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SELECT</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Choose this button to select the currency information for the
        specified country.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
