<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="currencies">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>currencies</primary>

      <secondary>master list of</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>multi-currency</primary>

      <secondary>currency definitions for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Currencies</title>

  <para>The system support for multi-currency begins with the definition of
  multiple currencies. In fact, the way to turn on multi-currency support is
  to define two or more currencies on the master list of currencies. Once two
  currencies are defined, you will see multi-currency support integrated
  throughout the application. If you prefer not to use multi-currency at your
  site, then simply define a base currency only—and no secondary
  currencies.</para>

  <caution>
    <para>You must define a base currency, even if you do not plan to use
    multi-currency. System administrators must ensure that a base currency is
    defined—and that it is defined accurately.</para>
  </caution>

  <para>The base currency is the currency used for all general ledger (G/L)
  transactions. Only one base currency may be defined per each database. Any
  transactions conducted in a foreign currency will be converted automatically
  to the base currency (using the prevailing exchange rate) before they are
  posted to the G/L.</para>

  <warning>
    <para>Once you post a transaction using multi-currency support, you cannot
    turn off multi-currency from that point forward. Either you implement
    multi-currency or you don't. There is no middle ground. System-level
    privileges are available to prevent users from accessing currency and
    exchange rate functionality.</para>
  </warning>

  <para>To access the master list of currencies, select the
  <guilabel>Currencies</guilabel> option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/currencies.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Currencies Master List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <tip>
    <para>Currency information for most countries can be found as part of the
    country set up. For more information, please see <xref
    linkend="countries"/>.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>The Currencies master list displays information on all currencies,
  including base currency indicator, currency name, currency symbol, and
  currency abbreviation. Beneath the list of currencies, you will find another
  list showing exchange rate comments. Whenever the exchange rate for a
  currency is updated, the change will be recorded here as a comment. You may
  also add your own manual comments, by currency.</para>

  <note>
    <para>To add comments, you must first select a currency from the list of
    currencies. Exchange rate comments are linked to the currency they relate
    to.</para>
  </note>

  <xi:include href="../widgets/comments.xml" xpointer="commentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

  <xi:include href="currency.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
