<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspCapacityBufferStatusByWorkCenter" role="manufacturing">
  <title>Capacity Buffer Status by Work Center</title>

  <para>The capacity buffer status display provides information on your
  current capacity buffer levels. Capacity buffers apply to work centers. The
  Capacity Buffer screen enables us to view the current load in relation to a
  definable number of days of capacity. Keep in mind that buffer status
  information will only be displayed on days when the constraint management
  system is run. If you find your displays show no information, this probably
  means constraint management has not been run.</para>

  <para>To view capacity buffer status by work center, select the
  <guimenuitem>Capacity Buffer Status by Work Center</guimenuitem> option. The
  following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspCapacityBufferStatusByWorkCenter.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Capacity Buffer Status by Work Center</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <note>
    <para>When the buffer status for a work center hits 66 or higher, the
    status number will become red. By highlighting lines which are "red hot,"
    the system is informing you which should be acted on immediately. The best
    remedy for red hot item sites is to expedite any associated work orders or
    purchase orders.</para>
  </note>

  <para>When displaying capacity buffer statuses by work center, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Work Centers</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which work centers you want to include in the
        display:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>All Work Centers</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to display capacity buffer statuses for all work
              centers.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Selected</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify work center whose inventory buffer status you want
              to display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Tooling</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to include tooling capacity information in
        the display. The following options are available:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>All Tooling</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include capacity information about all tooling
              items in the display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Selected Tooling</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify tooling item whose capacity information you want
              to include in the display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Sites</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display capacity buffer statuses for all sites.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify site whose capacity buffer statuses you want to
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Max Days Load</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the maximum number of days worth of work center load you
        want to view, using the arrows to the right of the field. This is
        required information. You must enter a value greater than 0 to
        generate buffer status information. The system uses the following
        equation to determine the capacity buffer status for a work
        center:</para>

        <informalexample>
          <para>(Total Setup + Total Run) / (Max Days Load x Daily Capacity) =
          Buffer (%)</para>
        </informalexample>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>By default, the display will sort work centers by buffer status in
    descending order. In other words, work centers with the highest buffer
    status will appear at the top of the list; work centers with the lowest
    buffer status will appear at the bottom.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Buffer Status by Work Center</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists capacity buffer status by work center, using the
        specified parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
