<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspCountTagEditList">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>count tags</primary>

      <secondary>edit list for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Count Tag Edit List</title>

  <para>The count tag edit list displays the unposted count tags currently
  available in your system. From this list, you can manage current count tags
  and their associated count slips. By default, the system allows only one
  unposted count tag per item site.</para>

  <tip>
    <para>The count tag edit list supports multiple-select, using the
    <guibutton>SHIFT</guibutton> and/or <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> keys. This
    is helpful when posting or deleting multiple count tags. This feature only
    works, however, when the <guilabel>Show Count Slips</guilabel> option is
    turned off.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>To display available count tags, select the <guimenuitem>Count Tag
  Edit List</guimenuitem> option. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspCountTagEditList.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Count Tag Edit List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When displaying the count tag edit list, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Sites by</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which of the following codes you want to have count tag
        displayed for:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Class Code</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, you will be presented with class code
              options.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Planner Code</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, you will be presented with planner code
              options.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
    <para>One way to manage count slips associated with a count tag is by
    using the right-click menu options available from the count tag edit
    list.</para>
  </tip>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>All Sites</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display count tags for all sites.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Selected</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify site whose count tags you want to display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>No Highlighting</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to not highlight count tags with variances.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Highlight Count Tag when Variance Value Exceeds</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to highlight count tags whose dollar amount variance
        exceeds the value entered. In addition to checking the box, you must
        also enter a value in the field. Once the value is entered, select the
        <guibutton>QUERY</guibutton> button. Count tags meeting your criteria
        will automatically be highlighted in red.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>Count tags showing both positive and negative variances will be
    highlighted. For example, if you enter "100" in the field
    <guilabel>Highlight Count Tag When Variance Value Exceeds</guilabel>, all
    dollar amount variances greater than $100 will be highlighted, but so too
    will negative variances exceeding -$100. The same principle holds true if
    a percentage value is entered.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Highlight Count Tag when Variance Exceeds %</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to highlight count tags whose variance exceeds a
        user-defined percentage. In addition to checking the box, you must
        also enter a percentage in the <guilabel>Percentage</guilabel> field.
        Once the percentage is entered, select the
        <guibutton>QUERY</guibutton> button. Count tags meeting your criteria
        will automatically be highlighted in red.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Search For</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>To search for a count tag in the edit list, begin typing in the
        <guilabel>Search</guilabel> field. As you type, the list will
        automatically scroll toward the count tag you are typing. You can also
        search for count tags manually by scrolling through the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Count Slips</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display count slips associated with count tags. Count
        slips will display in a nested manner beneath their associated count
        tag. Look for a plus sign (+) in the first column to determine if
        count slips are associated. Select the plus sign to reveal the count
        slips. To hide the count slips, select the minus sign (-).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Count Tags</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists count tag edit list, using the specified
        parameters. If the count quantity displays in blue type, this means
        the item has not been counted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
    <para>Count tags may be created to count an entire item site—or a specific
    site location within an item site.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>POST</guibutton></term>

      <listitem id="dspCountTagEditListPOST">
        <para>Highlight an individual count tag—or group of count tags using
        the <guibutton>SHIFT</guibutton> and/or <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton>
        keys—and then select this button to post the count tag(s). Posts count
        tag quantities to the quantity on hand (QOH) for the associated item
        site(s). If an item site was frozen when its count tag was created,
        then both the inventory count and the corresponding general ledger
        (G/L) transactions will use the count tag created (i.e., frozen) date
        when the count tag is posted. On the other hand, if the item site was
        not frozen, the inventory and G/L transactions will use the count tag
        posted date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>ENTER SLIP</guibutton></term>

      <listitem id="dspCountTagEditListENTERSLIP">
        <para>Select to enter a count slip.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
