<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspDetailedInventoryHistoryByLotSerial" role="standard">
  <title>Detailed Inventory History by Lot/Serial #</title>
  <para>Some users need to be able to track warranty periods of items from the
  purchase of raw materials to the sale of finished goods. Such traceability
  is possible by leveraging the Lot/Serial capability in xTuple ERP. Using
  Lot/Serial trace, users have access to backwards and forwards tracking
  through multiple levels of production—including the where used and warranty
  status of items.</para>
  <para>For example, if a defective internal medical device came back because
  of a defective spring, a user should be able to determine what Lot of
  springs went into the device—even if the spring was issued to a subassembly
  two levels down. Likewise, once the spring Lot is determined, the user
  should be able to search forward and determine all goods where that Lot of
  springs was used and shipped so all customers may be notified of the defect.
  If the spring was under warranty and is still eligible, the backward search
  should indicate so. To include multi-level trace information in your
  results, select the MORE button. The following options are available:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Forward</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view transaction activity of Lot/Serial goods through
        multiple levels showing where they were used. For example, we can see
        where a purchased item was used in a work order and subsequently
        shipped against a sales order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Backward</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view transaction activity of Lot/Serial goods though
        multiple levels showing what serialized items went into them. For
        example, we can look at a finished goods shipped to a customer and
        determine what purchased items went into the good.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view detailed inventory history by Lot/Serial number, select the
  "Detailed Inventory History by Lot/Serial #" option. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspDetailedInventoryHistoryByLotSerial.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Detailed Inventory History by Lot/Serial Number</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When displaying detailed inventory history by Lot/Serial number, you
  are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the item whose detailed inventory
        history by Lot/Serial number you want to display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Lot/Serial #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify one of the following Lot/Serial number selection
        criteria:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Selected</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the Lot/Serial number of the inventory whose
              detailed inventory history you want to display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Pattern</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter a Lot/Serial number pattern to select a range of
              product categorieLot/Serial numbers.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory History</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists detailed inventory history by Lot/Serial number,
        using the specified parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The system prefixes order numbers with letters indicating the order
    type. For example, work orders are prefixed with "WO", purchase orders
    with "PO", and sales orders with "SO". These letters are for display
    purposes only and are not considered part of the order number.</para>
  </note>
</section>
