<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspInventoryAvailabilityByCustomerType">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>inventory</primary>
      <secondary>availability by customer type</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales orders</primary>
      <secondary>inventory availability for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Inventory Availability by Customer Type</title>
  <para>If sales order reservations are enabled at your site, this screen may
  be considered a useful workbench for processing sales order reservations.
  While other screens support this functionality, the inventory availability
  by customer type report consolidates several useful functions in one
  location.</para>
  <para>To view inventory availability by customer type, go to
  <guimenuitem>Sales &gt; Reports &gt; </guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Availability
  by Customer Type</guimenuitem>. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspInventoryAvailabilityByCustomerType.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Inventory Availability by Customer Type</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When displaying inventory availability by customer type, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Customer Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display inventory availability for all customer
        types.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify customer type whose inventory availability you want to
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a customer type pattern to select a range of customer
        types. Refine your search using regular expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Only Show Shortages</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to only show inventory shortages in display. A shortage
        describes inventory quantity whose availability is negative.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Only Show Available to Ship</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include only inventory that is available to
        ship.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>reservations for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Use Reservation Netting</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to show sales order reservations (if any) for the sales
        order items included in the display. When selected, the <guilabel>This
        Availability</guilabel> column will dynamically change to
        <guilabel>This Reservation</guilabel> and the quantity reserved for
        each sales order item (if any) will be shown. This option will not be
        visible if <guilabel>Sales Order Reservations</guilabel> are not
        enabled at your site.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>To manipulate sales order reservations by line item, use the
          right-click options found on this screen.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show W/O Supply</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include current work orders for the sales order items
        shown in the display. If current work orders exist, they will appear
        nested below each relevant sales order item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Availability</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists inventory availability by customer type, using the
        specified parameters. If an available quantity value displays in the
        color orange, this means the actual or projected quantity on hand
        (QOH) is at or below the reorder level. If the color is red, the
        current or projected QOH is below zero.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The display features additional color-coding to help easily identify
    the sales order reservation status of individual orders and also line
    items. The following color conventions are used:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Green (line item level): Line item quantity is
        fully-reserved.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Green (Header level): Sales order has been added to the packing
        list batch.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Blue: Line item quantity is partially-reserved.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Black: Line item has no sales order reservations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </note>
</section>
