<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspInventoryBufferStatusByItemGroup" role="manufacturing">
  <title>Inventory Buffer Status by Item Group</title>
  <para>The inventory buffer status displays provide information on your
  current stock buffer levels. Stock buffers apply to make-to-stock items.
  Keep in mind that buffer status information will only be displayed on days
  when the constraint management system is run. If you find your displays show
  no information, this probably means constraint management has not been
  run.</para>
  <para>To view inventory buffer status by item group, go to
  <guimenuitem>Schedule &gt; Constrain Management &gt; Inventory &gt; by Item
  Group</guimenuitem>. The following screen will appear: </para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspInventoryBufferStatusByItemGroup.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Inventory Buffer Status by Item Group</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>When the buffer status for an item hits 66 or higher, the status
    number will become red. By highlighting items which are "red hot," the
    system is informing you which items should be acted on immediately. The
    best remedy for red hot item sites is to expedite any associated work
    orders or purchase orders.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When displaying inventory buffer statuses by item group, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Item Groups</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display inventory buffer statuses for all item
        groups.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify item group whose inventory buffer statuses you want to
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Group Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter an item group pattern to select a range of item groups.
        Refine your search using regular expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Sites</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display inventory buffer statuses for all
        sites.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify site whose inventory buffer statuses you want to
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Buffer Status</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Show buffer statuses using one of the following criteria:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Greater than zero</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to display only those item sites having a buffer
              status greater than zero.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>In Emergency Zone</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to display only those item sites whose buffer
              status is in the "emergency zone." The emergency zone is defined
              as a buffer status of 66 or greater.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>All</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to display buffer statuses for all item
              sites.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>By default, the display will sort item sites by buffer status in
    descending order. In other words, item sites with the highest buffer
    status will appear at the top of the list; item sites with the lowest
    buffer status will appear at the bottom.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Availability</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists inventory buffer statuses by item group, using the
        specified parameters. If planned availability displays in the color
        orange, this means the actual or projected quantity on hand (QOH) is
        at or below the reorder level. If the color is red, the current or
        projected QOH is below zero.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>When quantity appears in the <guilabel>On Order</guilabel> column,
    this refers to quantity that is on order through either a work order or
    purchase order. In the case of purchase orders, the quantity will always
    be represented in the inventory unit of measure (UOM)—regardless of the
    vendor UOM used on the purchase order.</para>
  </note>
</section>
