<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspItemCostsByClassCode">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>costing</primary>
      <secondary>for items by class code</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>class codes</primary>
      <secondary>item costs details for</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>item costs</primary>
      <secondary>by class code</secondary>
    </indexterm>Item Costs by Class Code</title>
  <para>To view item Costs by Class Code, select the "Item Costs by Class
  Code" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspItemCostsByClassCode.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Item Costs by Class Code</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When displaying item Costs by Class Code, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Class Codes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display item Costs for all Class Codes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify Class Code whose item Costs you want to display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a Class Code pattern to select a range of Class Codes.
        Refine your search using Regular Expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Only Show Zero Standard Cost Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include only items with zero Standard Cost in the
        display. The zero Standard Costs view can be helpful when trying to
        determine why no General Ledger (G/L) transactions are being generated
        when certain items are involved. Items must have Standard Costs
        associated with them if transactions involving them are to be recorded
        in the G/L. If an item has no Standard Cost, no G/L records for that
        item will be created.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Only Show Zero Last Actual Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include only items whose last Actual Cost equals zero.
        This option can help you quickly identify purchased items with costing
        problems. If the last Actual Cost for an item equals zero, the
        Standard Cost will inherit this zero cost when Actual Costs are
        posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Only Show Items where Actual and Standard are different</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include in the report only those items whose Actual
        and Standard Costs are not the same. In some cases, items whose Actual
        and Standard Costs appear to be the same may be included when this
        option is selected. This is caused by rounding discrepancies in the
        case where the Locale being used allows for greater cost precision
        than this screen supports. If this occurs, the item record will appear
        in a different color to indicate the difference occurs at a greater
        level of precision than can be viewed on the screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Inactive Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include inactive items in the display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which of the following item types you want to include in
        the display:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Purchased</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include purchased items in the display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Manufactured</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include Manufactured items in the
              display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Outside Service</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include Outside Service items in the
              display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Costing</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include Costing items in the display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Planning</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include Planning items in the display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>All Others</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include all other item types not otherwise
              listed in the display (e.g., Service items, etc.). </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists item Costs by Class Code, using the specified
        parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
