<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspJournals">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>journals</primary>

      <secondary>viewing transactions in</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>transactions</primary>

      <secondary>viewing in journals</secondary>
    </indexterm>Journals</title>

  <para>If your site is configured to post transactions to an intermediate
  journal instead of directly to the general ledger, this Journals screen will
  be visible to you. To learn more about this configuration option, please see
  <xref linkend="configureGL"/>. When journals are in use, all transactions
  and their full transaction detail are posted in real time to intermediate
  journals (sometimes also referred to as "day books"). From the journals,
  transactions are later posted to the general ledger—in summary form. In this
  way, transaction detail remains in the journals, with the summarized version
  of that detail residing in the general ledger.</para>

  <para>Here are some tips for using this screen:</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Use the right-click menu to drill down into the details of
      individual transactions.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>If your transaction records are displaying a "No" value in the
      <guilabel>Posted</guilabel> column, this means the transactions have not
      yet been posted to the general ledger. Until they are posted to the
      general ledger, journal transactions will not appear in the trial
      balance or other financial reports.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>You can post journals to the general ledger on a daily, monthly,
      or weekly basis. It's up to you how you want to implement this
      feature.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Keep in mind that the trial balance and other financial reports
      are based solely on general ledger transactions. This means that journal
      transactions are not included in financial reports—that is, until they
      are posted over to the general ledger. To learn more about posting
      journals to the general ledger, please see <xref
      linkend="postJournals"/>.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>When project accounting is enabled, there is a search parameter
      designed to show accounts with a project number as the last segment. If
      the <guilabel>Show Project Detail</guilabel> option is not used,
      balances will roll up into the parent account total.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para>The following screenshot shows the Journals screen:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspJournals.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Journals</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>The default filter on the Journals screen shows all transactions for
  the current day. You can build your own search criteria using the following
  options:</para>

  <xi:include href="../widgets/parameterwidget.xml" xpointer="parameterwidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
