<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspMPSDetail" role="manufacturing">
  <title>MPS Detail</title>

  <para>To view the master production schedule (MPS), select the
  <guimenuitem>MPS Detail</guimenuitem> option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspMPSDetail.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>MPS Detail</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When viewing the Master Production Schedule, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Sites</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display MPS detail for all sites.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify site whose MPS detail you want to display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Planner Codes</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display MPS detail for all planner codes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify planner code whose MPS detail you want to
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a planner code pattern to select a range of planner codes.
        Refine your search using regular expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Calendar</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select the calendar you want to use for the report. By default,
        the calendar defined at the system level will be used. Associated
        calendar periods will be displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
    <para>When setting up a planning calendar, be sure to include past due
    information in the first period of the calendar.</para>
  </tip>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name/Selected Periods</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select as many periods as you want to display. Selected periods
        correspond to calendar specified in the <guilabel>Calendar</guilabel>
        field. Select individual periods or groups of periods together. To
        select an individual period, highlight the period using your mouse
        button. The period is now selected. To select a sequence of periods,
        highlight the first in the sequence using your mouse button. Then,
        holding down the <guibutton>SHIFT</guibutton> key on your keyboard,
        highlight the last period in the sequence. The entire sequence is now
        selected. To select periods that are out of sequence (e.g., January,
        April, July, October), highlight the first period in the group. Then,
        holding down the <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key on your keyboard,
        highlight the next period you want to select. Continue highlighting
        periods with the <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key depressed until all
        desired periods are selected. The entire group is now selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Sites</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists item sites for items matching the specified
        parameters. When you have selected a calendar type and corresponding
        calendar period(s), highlight an item site to display MPS detail for
        the item site in the MPS Detail display below.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>MPS Detail</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists MPS detail for the item site you selected in the
        Item Sites display above. MPS detail will include the following rows:
        forecast (based on MPS reading of production plans); allocations
        (requirements from customer orders or work orders); orders (based on
        work orders or purchase orders); projected QOH (based on allocations
        and orders for specified future periods); planned orders
        (system-generated orders showing requirements needed to meet negative
        availability); availability (based on current allocations and orders);
        available to promise (uncommitted quantity available to support new
        sales orders).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>You will only be able to view allocations if allocations are showing
    a positive value in the period where you right-click your mouse.
    Similarly, you will only be able to view orders if orders are showing a
    positive value in the period where you right-click your mouse.</para>
  </note>
</section>
