<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspMRPDetail" role="standard">
  <title>MRP Detail</title>
  <para>To display a time-phased view of material requirements planning (MRP)
  detail, go to <guimenuitem>Schedule &gt; Reports &gt; MRP
  Detail</guimenuitem>. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspMRPDetail.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>MRP Detail</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>Only firm planned orders will be included in the MRP Detail display.
    If a planned order is not firmed, it will not be recognized. This
    limitation pertains also to MRP items which may be associated with MPS or
    planning items. While firm MPS orders may exist, planned orders for the
    underlying MRP items must be firmed (or released) before the MRP Detail
    display will recognize them.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When displaying MRP detail, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Sites</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display MRP detail for all sites.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify site whose MRP detail you want to display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Planner Codes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display MRP detail for all planner codes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify planner code whose MRP detail you want to
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a planner code pattern to select a range of planner codes.
        Refine your search using regular expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Calendar</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the calendar you want to use for the report. Associated
        calendar periods will be displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>When setting up a planning calendar, be sure to include dates that
    are past due in the first period of the calendar.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name/Selected Periods</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select as many periods as you want to display. Selected periods
        correspond to calendar specified in the <guilabel>Calendar</guilabel>
        field. Select individual periods or groups of periods together. To
        select an individual period, highlight the period using your mouse
        button. The period is now selected. To select a sequence of periods,
        highlight the first in the sequence using your mouse button. Then,
        holding down the <guibutton>SHIFT</guibutton> key on your keyboard,
        highlight the last period in the sequence. The entire sequence is now
        selected. To select periods that are out of sequence (e.g., January,
        April, July, October), highlight the first period in the group. Then,
        holding down the <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key on your keyboard,
        highlight the next period you want to select. Continue highlighting
        periods with the <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key depressed until all
        desired periods are selected. The entire group is now selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Sites</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists items matching the specified parameters. When you
        have selected a calendar type and corresponding calendar period(s),
        highlight an item to display MRP detail for the item in the MRP Detail
        display below.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>To refresh the MRP Detail display, double-click on the item site
    whose detail you want to refresh.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>MRP Detail</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists MRP detail for the item you selected in the Site
        Items display above.</para>
        <para>MRP detail will include the following rows: projected QOH (based
        on allocations and orders for specified future periods); allocations
        (demand from sales orders); orders (based on work orders or purchase
        orders); availability (based on current allocations and orders);
        firmed allocations (firmed planned requirements); firmed orders (firm
        planned orders); and firmed availability (based on availability and
        firm planned orders).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>You will only be able to view allocations if allocations are showing
    a positive value in the period where you right-click your mouse.
    Similarly, you will only be able to view orders if orders are showing a
    positive value in the period where you right-click your mouse.</para>
  </note>
</section>
