<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspPoItemsByBufferStatus" role="manufacturing">
  <title>P/O Items by Buffer Status</title>
  <para>The purchase order buffer status displays provide information on your
  current stock and time buffer levels for those items having current purchase
  orders. Stock buffers apply to make-to-stock items; whereas time buffers
  apply to items which are make-to-order. Keep in mind that buffer status
  information will only be displayed on days when the constraint management
  system is run. If you find your displays show no information, this probably
  means constraint management has not been run.</para>
  <para>To view purchase order item buffer statuses, go to
  <guimenuitem>Schedule &gt; Constrain Management &gt; Purchase
  Order</guimenuitem>. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspPoItemsByBufferStatus.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Purchase Order Items by Buffer Status</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>When the buffer status for an item hits 66 or higher, the status
    number will become red. By highlighting items which are red hot, the
    system is informing you which items should be acted on immediately. The
    best remedy for red hot item sites is to expedite any associated work
    orders or purchase orders.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When displaying purchase order item buffer statuses, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Sites</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display purchase order item buffer statuses for all
        sites.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify site whose purchase order item buffer statuses you want
        to display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Purchasing Agents</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display purchase order item buffer statuses for all
        purchasing agents.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify purchasing agent whose purchase order item buffer
        statuses you want to display. Users may be designated as purchasing
        agents at the system level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>By default, the display will sort purchase order items by buffer
    status in descending order. In other words, purchase order items with the
    highest buffer status will appear at the top of the list; purchase order
    items with the lowest buffer status will appear at the bottom.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>P/O Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists buffer statuses for open purchase order items,
        using the specified parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
