<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspPurchaseReqsByItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>purchase requests</primary>
      <secondary>by item</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>
      <secondary>purchase requests for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Purchase Requests by Item</title>
  <para>To view purchase requests by item or to create new manual Purchase
  Requests, select the "Purchase Requests by Item" option. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <note>
    <para>Purchase requests are considered to be a valid source of supply by
    the planning systems.</para>
  </note>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspPurchaseReqsByItem.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Purchase Requests by Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Use the NEW button to create a manual purchase request. Or use the
    right-click option on the Inventory availability and Planned Order
    screens.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When displaying purchase requests by item, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the item whose purchase requests you
        want to view. The lookup feature located to the right of the field
        leads to a searchable list of make and buy items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Purchase request quantities are based on the inventory Unit of
          Measure (UOM). However, some vendor item sources may specify an
          alternate UOM. If this is the case, the system will automatically
          convert the requirement to the vendor's UOM when the Purchase
          Request is released.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>All Sites</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display purchase requests by item for all
        sites.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify site whose purchase requests by item you want to
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Purchase Requests</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists purchase requests for the specified item, using
        the specified parameters. You may multi-select purchase requests in
        the list, but when doing so each request will be processed
        individually.</para>
        <note>
          <para>When a purchase request is released, the requested item will
          automatically populate a Purchase Order Item screen. If item sources
          have been defined for the item, then item source prices will be
          used—that is, unless the vendor price has been specifically
          overridden for purchase requests generated from sales orders.
          Project numbers may also be transferred from sales orders. In this
          way, sales orders and purchase order line items may be linked to the
          same project.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create a manual purchase request.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/purchaseRequest.xml" xpointer="purchaseRequest"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
