<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspQuotesByCustomer">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>quotes</primary>
      <secondary>looking up by customer</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>
      <secondary>looking up by quote</secondary>
    </indexterm>Quote Lookup by Customer</title>
  <para>To view quotes by customer, select the <guimenuitem>Quote Lookup by Customer</guimenuitem>
  option from the <guimenuitem>Reports</guimenuitem> menu. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspQuotesByCustomer.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Quote Lookup by Customer</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When displaying quotes by customer, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the customer number of the customer whose quotes you want
        to view. The lookup feature located to the right of the field leads to
        a searchable customers list. You may also access this list using the
        keyboard shortcut <guibutton>CTRL + L</guibutton>. Once a customer number is entered, the
        customer name and billing address will display. Select the <guibutton>?</guibutton> or <guibutton>$</guibutton>
        symbol to view customer information for the specified customer. If a customer's credit is good, the button will feature a black question mark (<guibutton>?</guibutton>) icon. If the customer is on credit warning, the icon will turn into an orange dollar sign (<guibutton>$</guibutton>). A red dollar sign (<guibutton>$</guibutton>) indicates the customer is on credit hold.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All P/O #s</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display all purchase order numbers for the specified
        customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the customer purchase order number you want to
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Converted</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include sales orders which were originally converted
        from quotes. Converted quotes will show as closed in the display. For
        this feature to work, your <guimenu>Sales</guimenu> module must be configured to show
        quotes after they have been converted to sales orders.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Starting Order Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Quotes entered on and after this date will be displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ending Order Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Quotes entered on and before this date will be displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Quotes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists quotes for the specified customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
