<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspQOH">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>quantity on hand</primary>
      <secondary>reporting by</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>QOH</primary>
      <see>quantity on hand</see>
    </indexterm>Quantities on Hand</title>
  <para>The Quantities on Hand screen provides up-to-date QOH information, as
  well as information about inventory values by item site. This is a
  particularly useful screen for anyone who manages physical inventory. From
  the right-click menu, you can transfer and adjust quantities—or enter Count
  Tags and miscellaneous physical counts. The columns in the screen also
  provide detailed item site information, including location details, reorder
  levels, and more.</para>
  <para>Here are some tips for using this screen:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Don't confuse QOH with availability. You may be showing a certain
      QOH, but because of order commitments the actual available quantity may
      be different.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>If the <guilabel>Show Inventory Value</guilabel> box is selected,
      the display will also show unit cost, value, and non-netable value.
      Totals for each column will be calculated at the bottom of the display.
      It is not currently possible to view inventory value at a point in time
      in the past.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>You can choose to see historical inventory values using the
      <guilabel>As-Of</guilabel> filter option. This option shows
      point-in-time inventory values by accounting Period. If you do not see
      the <guilabel>As-Of</guilabel> option, then you probably haven't enabled
      the feature. You can learn more about enabling the As-Of QOH feature
      here: <xref linkend="configureIM"/>.</para>
      <warning>
        <para>You should only enable As-Of QOH reporting during off hours, as
        this option may require extensive processing when it is run.</para>
      </warning>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>When a QOH value displays in the color orange, this means the
      actual or projected QOH is at or below the Reorder Level. When the color
      is red, the current or projected QOH is below zero.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>View ABC Class information by enabling the ABC Class column
      header.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>The following screenshot shows the Quantities on Hand screen:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspQOH.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Quantities on Hand</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The following options on this screen are a supplement to the choices
  available under the search filter:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show All Quantities</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to show all QOH in the display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Only Show Positive QOHs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to show only inventory with a positive QOH in the
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Only Show Negative QOHs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to show only inventory with a negative QOH in the
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Inventory Value</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include the inventory value of QOH by class code in
        the display. Once selected, specify one of the following costing
        options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use Posted Costs</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to show inventory value based on the costing method
              defined for the item site. Item sites may use the following
              costing methods, depending on the item type: standard, average,
              job (i.e., job items), and None (i.e., Reference items and any
              items having a control method = None).</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use Standard Costs</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to show inventory value based on standard
              costs.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Use Actual Costs</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to show inventory value based on actual
              costs.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The default filter on the Quantities on Hand screen shows quantities
  for all items. You can build your own search criteria using the following
  options:</para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/parameterwidget.xml" xpointer="parameterwidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
