<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspTimePhasedOpenARItems">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>open items</primary>

      <secondary>aging report for receivables</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>accounts receivable</primary>

      <secondary>aging report for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Receivables Aging</title>

  <para>The receivables aging report gives you the ability to view open
  receivables in a bucketed, time-phased perspective. An open item is
  recognized by the receivables aging report "as of" the item's document or
  distribution date, depending on your preference. In the case of invoices,
  the document date is the invoice date. The distribution date is the date the
  invoice shows up in the general ledger (G/L). For example, if you post an
  invoice on January 1, but the invoice date is February 15, then the "as of"
  document date will be February 15. This means, if you run the receivables
  aging report with an "as of" document date in January, the open item with an
  invoice date of February 15 will not appear in the report. In fact, it will
  not appear in the report until an "as of" document date of February 15 or
  later is specified. Conversely, using the distribution date option, the
  invoice would appear "as of" January 1.</para>

  <tip>
    <para>You can view the document date for an open item by right-clicking on
    a line in the Receivables Aging display. You can also find open item
    details on other screens—for example, Receivables Workbench, customer
    History, Open Items by customer, etc.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>The grouping of open items into time-phased buckets is driven by a
  document's due date. In other words, if a due date falls within 0-30 days of
  the "as of" date specified when the report is run, then the open item will
  appear in the first bucket. If the due date falls 31-60 days past the
  specified "as of" date, then the open item will appear in the second bucket.
  And so on. But again, keep in mind that the document date for an open
  receivable (e.g., invoice date) must be on or before the specified "as of"
  date for the item to be recognized by the report. To view open receivables
  from an aging perspective, select the <guimenuitem>Receivables
  Aging</guimenuitem> option. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspTimePhasedOpenARItems.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Receivables Aging</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When displaying aging open receivables, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select all or specific customers whose receivables information
        you want to display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>As of</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date you want the open receivables to be relative
        to. The report will include any receivable items which were open—that
        is, not yet paid—as of the specified date. This feature provides
        "point-in-time" open balance functionality. But again, keep in mind
        that the document date for an open receivable (e.g., invoice date)
        must be on or before the specified "as of" date for the item to be
        recognized by the report.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Custom Calendar</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to display open receivables using a custom
        calendar of your choosing.</para>

        <para>If selected, the screen will present a series of different
        options, including the option to select a calendar and associated
        periods.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date preference you want to use:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Document Date</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include open items as of their document
              date.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Distribution Date</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include open items as of their document
              date.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify your preference for the printed report. This option
        impacts the printed report <emphasis>only</emphasis> and will not
        change the information displayed on the screen.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Detailed Report</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want to print a detailed aging report. This
              option will not change the screen display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Summary Report</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want to print a summarized aging report.
              This option will not change the screen display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Receivables Open Items</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists aging open receivables, using the specified
        parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>open items</primary>

      <secondary>time-phased for receivables</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>accounts receivable</primary>

      <secondary>time-phased open items for</secondary>
    </indexterm>To view open receivables using a custom calendar, select the
  <guimenuitem>Use Custom Calendar</guimenuitem> option above. The following
  screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspTimePhasedOpenARItems_custom.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Custom Receivables Aging Calendar</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <note>
    <para>If a customer's open receivables balance exceeds their credit limit,
    the customer will automatically be placed on credit warning. In addition,
    any new or open sales orders for the customer will also be placed on
    credit hold.</para>
  </note>

  <para>When displaying open receivables using a custom calendar, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Calendar</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select the calendar you want to use for the report.</para>

        <para>Associated calendar periods will be displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name/Selected Periods</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select as many periods as you want to display. Selected periods
        correspond to calendar specified in the <guilabel>Calendar</guilabel>
        field. Select individual periods or groups of periods together. To
        select an individual period, highlight the period using your mouse
        button. The period is now selected. To select a sequence of periods,
        highlight the first in the sequence using your mouse button. Then,
        holding down the SHIFT key on your keyboard, highlight the last period
        in the sequence. The entire sequence is now selected. To select
        periods that are out of sequence (e.g., January, April, July,
        October), highlight the first period in the group. Then, holding down
        the CTRL key on your keyboard, highlight the next period you want to
        select. Continue highlighting periods with the CTRL key depressed
        until all desired periods are selected. The entire group is now
        selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Open Receivables</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists time-phased open receivables, using the specified
        parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
