<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspTrialBalances">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>trial balances</primary>

      <secondary>reporting on</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>financial reports</primary>

      <secondary>trial balances</secondary>
    </indexterm>View Trial Balances</title>

  <para>The Trial Balances screen provides a mechanism for viewing the
  detailed financial information which underlies xTuple financial reports. The
  sequence of events is as follows: transactions are posted to the general
  ledger, these transactions update the trial balance, and financial reports
  use the trial balance when calculating their results.</para>

  <para>Here are some tips for using this screen:</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Use the right-click menu to view the underlying G/L transactions
      which support the trial balance values.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>If G/L transactions are not posted, they will not appear in the
      trial balance. G/L transactions may be unposted if they were posted into
      a non-existent accounting period.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Trial balances will be automatically forward-updated unless your
      system is configured to manually forward-update trial balances. Ending
      balances cannot be forward-updated into future periods. For more
      information see <xref linkend="configureGL"/>.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Ending balances will display in orange type if either of the
      following conditions is true: 1) The ending balance has not been
      forward-updated, or 2) the ending balance has been forward-updated, but
      the account in question has no activity during the specified
      period.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>For fiscal year closings, the system will automatically reset the
      beginning balances for revenue and expense accounts to $0 at the start
      of a new fiscal year. However, for the year-end equity account, the
      beginning balance for the first period of the fiscal year will be equal
      to the ending balance for the previous year.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>A "CR" may display after the following columns: <guilabel>Beg.
      Bal.</guilabel>, <guilabel>Difference</guilabel>, and <guilabel>End.
      Bal</guilabel>. The "CR" indicates the balance is a credit balance. If
      no "CR" appears, then the balance is a debit balance.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>The trial balance query builder includes an option for displaying
      accounts having a zero balance. If not selected, zero-balance trial
      balances will be hidden—unless a specific account is specified, in which
      case the balance will be shown regardless of whether it is zero.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Also included is an option for showing accounts with a project
      number as the last segment. If the <guilabel>Show Project
      Detail</guilabel> option is not used, balances will roll up into the
      parent account total.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>If you are synchronizing the trial balances of multiple external
      companies, you may get a warning message if exchange rates covering the
      imported accounting periods were changed after the fact. For more
      information, please see <xref linkend="syncCompanies"/>.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>The option <guilabel>Exclude Child Accounts</guilabel> is
      available on the G/L Transactions screen whenever you are drilling down
      to view G/L transaction details. This option is used to show or hide the
      child transactions which may be associated with a G/L account when
      <guilabel>Project Accounting</guilabel> is enabled.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para>The following screenshot shows the Trial Balances screen:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspTrialBalances.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>View Trial Balances</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>The default filter on the Trial Balances screen shows all trial
  balances for the current accounting period. You can build your own search
  criteria using the following options:</para>

  <xi:include href="../widgets/parameterwidget.xml" xpointer="parameterwidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
