<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspTimePhasedSales">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales history</primary>
      <secondary>time-phased reporting</secondary>
    </indexterm> Time-Phased Sales History</title>
  <para>The Time-Phased Sales History screen provides a time-phased
  perspective on your historical sales activity. Here are some tips for using
  this screen:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>When selecting a calendar from the list, make sure to also select
      corresponding periods.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>The type of calendar and number of calendar periods you choose to
      display may have an impact on response time. The data may take longer to
      display, depending on the time frame requested.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Calendars are defined under the <guimenu>System</guimenu> module
      Setup screen.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Prices are normalized to the base currency using the currency
      exchange rate effective on the order date.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>To view the Time-Phased Sales History screen, go to <guimenuitem>Sales
  &gt; Analysis &gt; Time Phased Sales History</guimenuitem>. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspTimePhasedSales.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Time-Phased Sales History</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The following options on this screen are a supplement to the choices
  available under the search filter:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Group By</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify how you want the information grouped: by customer,
        product category, or item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Units</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the units you want to see the results sorted by: sales
        dollars, inventory, capacity, alternate capacity</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Calendar</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the calendar you want to use for the report. Associated
        calendar periods will be displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name/Selected Periods</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select as many periods as you want to display. Selected periods
        correspond to calendar specified in the <guilabel>Calendar</guilabel>
        field. Select individual periods or groups of periods together. To
        select an individual period, highlight the period using your mouse
        button. The period is now selected. To select a sequence of periods,
        highlight the first in the sequence using your mouse button. Then,
        holding down the <guibutton>SHIFT</guibutton> key on your keyboard,
        highlight the last period in the sequence. The entire sequence is now
        selected. To select periods that are out of sequence (e.g., January,
        April, July, October), highlight the first period in the group. Then,
        holding down the <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key on your keyboard,
        highlight the next period you want to select. Continue highlighting
        periods with the <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key depressed until all
        desired periods are selected. The entire group is now selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The default filter on the Time-Phased Sales screen shows all sales for
  the specified calendar period(s). You can build your own search criteria
  using the following options:</para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/parameterwidget.xml" xpointer="parameterwidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
