<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspVendorAPHistory">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>vendors</primary>
      <secondary>history for</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>accounts payable</primary>
      <secondary>vendor history and</secondary>
    </indexterm>Vendor History</title>
  <para>The Vendor History screen allows you to view transaction history with
  individual vendors. It also provides you the opportunity to void posted
  vouchers. To view vendor history, select the <guimenuitem>Vendor
  History</guimenuitem> option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspVendorAPHistory.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Vendor History</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>If you need to void a posted voucher, you can do this from the
    right-click menu. Voiding a voucher reverses all ledger transactions
    created by the original voucher. Only open vouchers may be voided.
    Vouchers with apply-to records cannot be voided. You will be given the
    option to specify a void date when voiding a voucher. Apply-to records
    will also be reversed on the void date you specify.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When displaying vendor history, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vendor #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the vendor number of the vendor whose history you want to
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Find Vend. Invoice#</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>To search for an invoice in the Vendor History display, begin
        typing an invoice number into this field. As you type, the list will
        automatically scroll toward the invoice number you are typing. You can
        also search for invoices manually by scrolling through the
        list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Start Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Vendor activity entered on and after this date will be
        displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>End Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Vendor activity entered on and before this date will be
        displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vendor History</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists vendor history, using the specified parameters.
        This display is a nested list, with a plus sign
        (<guibutton>+</guibutton>) located to the far left of the display next
        to each document that may be expanded to lower levels. By clicking
        your mouse on a plus sign, you reveal lower levels of information
        related to the document.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
