<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspWoOperationBufrStsByWorkCenter" role="manufacturing">
  <title>W/O Operation Buffer Status by Work Center</title>

  <para>The work order buffer status displays provide information on your
  current stock and time buffer levels for those items having current work
  orders. Stock buffers apply to make-to-stock items; whereas time buffers
  apply to items which are make-to-order. Keep in mind that buffer status
  information will only be displayed on days when the constraint management
  system is run. If you find your displays show no information, this probably
  means constraint management has not been run.</para>

  <para>To view work order operation buffer statuses by work center, go to
  <guimenuitem>Manufacture &gt; Reports &gt; Operation Buffer
  Status</guimenuitem>. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspWoOperationBufrStsByWorkCenter.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Work Order Operation Buffer Status by Work Center</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <note>
    <para>When the buffer status for an item hits 66% or higher, the status
    number will become red. By highlighting items which are red hot, the
    system is informing you which items should be acted on immediately. The
    best remedy for red hot item sites is to expedite any associated work
    orders or purchase orders. Records will display in yellow type when the
    buffer penetration is in the 33%-66% range.</para>
  </note>

  <para>When displaying work order operation buffer statuses by work center,
  you are presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Work Center</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify work center whose work order operation buffer statuses
        you want to display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays site code for site where work center is located.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>By default, the display will sort work orders by buffer status in
    descending order. In other words, work orders with the highest buffer
    status will appear at the top of the list; work orders with the lowest
    buffer status will appear at the bottom.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Only Show W/O Operations with Qty. Available</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to only show work order operations with quantity
        available in the display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Only Show W/O Operations with Matl. Issued</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to exclude work order operations whose used at materials
        are not fully issued.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Clock In/Out User</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select the name of the user whose operations you want to
        view.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Clock In/Out Employee</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select the name of the employee whose operations you want to
        view.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Operations</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists work order operation buffer statuses by work
        center, using the specified parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
