<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dspWoEffortByWorkOrder">
  <title>Production Time Clock by Work Order</title>

  <para>To view time clock information by work order, go to
  <guimenuitem>Manufacture &gt; Reports &gt; Production Time Clock &gt; by
  Work Order</guimenuitem>. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/dspWoEffortByWorkOrder.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Production Time Clock By Work Order</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When users post operations from the Shop Floor workbench, they have
  the option to post either standard or specified times—and the run time
  recorded will vary depending on the option chosen. The standard times are
  drawn from the routings item definitions. By contrast, the specified times
  are based on the users' clock in/out times (i.e., effort). The specified
  effort for an operation may be complicated by the fact that users can be
  clocked into more than one work order at a time. In this case, the users'
  effort will be spread across the various work orders they have clocked
  into.</para>

  <para>When displaying time clock information by work order, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Work Order #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the work order number of the work order whose time clock
        information you want to view.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays site code automatically when work order number is
        entered into <guilabel>Work Order #</guilabel> field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Status</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the current status of the work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Method</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Indicates work order method is either assembly or
        disassembly.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays item number automatically when work order number is
        entered into <guilabel>Work Order #</guilabel> field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Users</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists users who have clocked-in to the specified work
        order. If the totals row displays in red, this means the sum of total
        setup and run times does not equal the total effort.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
