<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="enterPoReturn">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>returns</primary>
      <secondary>entering at shipping</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>shipping</primary>
      <secondary>entering of returns</secondary>
    </indexterm>Purchase Order Return</title>
  <para>Purchase order returns are used in the event that purchase order items
  need to be returned to a vendor, as shown in the following
  screen:<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/enterPoReturn.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Enter Purchase Order Return</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Privileged users will be given the option to generate a Payables
    credit Memo to offset the amount of the return when the return is posted.
    For more information, please see <xref
    linkend="postPoReturnCreditMemo" />.</para>
    <para>This option is available when returning against closed purchase
    order line items. Closed purchase orders will be reopened automatically in
    this scenario to allow for future Receipts. If the option is not used—or
    if a line item is not closed at the time of a return—then the return may
    be processed normally from the "Uninvoiced Receipts and Returns" screen.
    </para>
  </tip>
  <para>When entering a purchase order return, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the order number of the order whose line item(s) you want
        to return.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Drop Ship</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If your system is configured to use drop shipping, this
        informational, read-only field will be displayed. It will be selected
        if the purchase order entered was a drop ship order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vendor Return Authority</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use this field to enter the vendor's return material
        authorization (RMA) code.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Print Return Report</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to print a return report when the return is
        posted. The report will be printed when you select the <guibutton>POST</guibutton>
        button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Return Address</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the address where the return should be sent. By default,
        the address used will be the same as the main vendor address found on
        the Vendor master. You may edit the address information before posting
        the return.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Purchase Order Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists purchase order line items available for
        return.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>POST</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a line item, then select this button to remove the
        returned line item quantity from inventory. For privileged users, an
        Payables credit Memo may be generated in the amount of the return when
        the return is posted. This option is available when returning against
        closed line items. If used, the line item will be automatically
        reopened to allow for future Receipts. Also, a return report will be
        printed if the "Print Return Report" option is selected.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>ENTER RETURN</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a line item, then select this button to initiate a
        return. Double-clicking on a purchase order line item will also bring
        you to the Return Item screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If an item you are returning is a <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>multiple location control</primary>
        <secondary>impact on receiving</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>receiving</primary>
        <secondary>MLC impact on</secondary>
      </indexterm>Multiple location control (MLC) item, you will be prompted
    to specify the Location you want to issue the stock from.</para>
  </note>
  <xi:include href="enterPoitemReturn.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
