<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="expenseCategory">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>expense categories</primary>

      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Expense Category</title>

  <para>To create a new expense category, select the
  <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/expenseCategory.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Create New Expense Category</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating a new expense category, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <tip>
    <para>The account numbers assigned to cost categories should not all be
    the inventory account. Instead, they should be individual accounts
    selected specifically for each cost-tracking purpose. This will increase
    your visibility into your inventory costs and valuation.</para>
  </tip>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Category</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the expense category name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a brief description of the expense category.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to show the expense category as active. Not selecting
        means the expense category will be considered inactive. To re-activate
        an expense category, simply select this option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expense</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a general ledger (G/L) account to distribute purchasing
        expenses to. This is an expense account. It will be debited when
        transactions using expense categories are posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Purchase Price Variance</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to distribute purchase price variances
        to. This is an asset account. It will be credited or debited with the
        value of any variance that may arise when a voucher is posted for
        non-inventory items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>P/O Liability Clearing</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to distribute purchase order liability
        clearing to. This is a liability account. It will be credited when
        non-inventory items are received, and debited when a voucher for these
        items is posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>PO Line Freight Expense</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to distribute freight expense to. This is
        an expense account. It will be debited when line freight expenses are
        posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
