<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="financialLayout">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>financial reports</primary>

      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm> <anchor id="Anchor14666" role="Cross-Ref"
  xreflabel="14666: Heading2: Create Financial Report"/>New Financial
  Report</title>

  <para>The financial reporting engine (FRE) enables you to design custom
  financial reports, which can then be previewed, printed, or exported in
  tab-delimited format. You are free to decide how much detail to include in
  these custom reports. For example, you can create highly-detailed financial
  reports or executive summaries.</para>

  <para>To create a new financial report, go to <guimenuitem>Accounting &gt;
  Financial Statements &gt; New Financial Report</guimenuitem>. The following
  screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/financialLayout.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Create new Financial Report</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating a new financial report, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name to identify the financial report.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a brief description of the financial report.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate whether the financial report is active or
        not. Inactive financial reports will be hidden on the master list of
        financial reports by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report Type</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the following standard statement formats to be the
        basis for your new financial report:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Income Statement</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to create an income statement. You might also
              consider building an income statement by making a copy of the
              system-defined income statement, using the system-defined report
              as a template. To make a copy of the system-defined income
              statement, simply use the <guibutton>COPY</guibutton> button on
              the master list of financial reports. Once copied, you can
              freely modify the report to suit your needs.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Balance Sheet</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to create a balance sheet. You might also consider
              building an income statement by making a copy of the
              system-defined balance sheet, using the system-defined report as
              a template. To make a copy of the system-defined balance sheet,
              simply use the <guibutton>COPY</guibutton> button on the master
              list of financial reports. Once copied, you can freely modify
              the report to suit your needs.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Cash Flow</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to create a cash flow statement. Because cash flow
              statements can vary so widely, there is no system-defined cash
              flow template.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term><emphasis>Ad Hoc</emphasis></term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to create an <emphasis>ad hoc</emphasis> report. An
              <emphasis>ad hoc</emphasis> report is completely free-form and
              user-defined. This format gives you the flexibility to create
              reports which do not fit neatly within the three standard report
              types. Any financial report created in the system prior to
              version 2.1.0 will be classified as an <emphasis>ad
              hoc</emphasis> report.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry role="xtprjaccnt">
            <term>Use in Projects</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>If the xTuple Project Accounting package is installed,
              select this option to make the financial report available to
              projects.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <xi:include href="financialLayoutIncStatement.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

  <xi:include href="financialLayoutBalSheet.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

  <xi:include href="financialLayoutCashFlow.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

  <xi:include href="financialLayoutAdHoc.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
