<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="financialLayoutCashFlow">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>financial reports</primary>

      <secondary>cash flow type</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>cash flow reports</primary>
    </indexterm> Cash Flow Report</title>

  <para>Because cash flow statements can vary so widely, there is no
  system-defined cash flow template. To create your own cash flow statement,
  select the <guilabel>Cash Flow</guilabel> report type. The following screen
  will appear:</para>

  <para role="xtprjaccnt"><note>
      <para>If the xTuple Project Accounting package is installed, you will
      have the option to make the cash flow report available to
      projects.</para>
    </note></para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/financialLayoutCashFlow.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Cash flow financial report</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>To create the row layouts for a cash flow report, you would follow the
  same basic steps as described in <xref linkend="financialLayoutAdHoc"/>. The
  only difference is you won't need to specify which balances to calculate
  (e.g., beginning, ending, etc.). Because the cash flow report is one of
  three standard statement formats, the system determines which calculations
  will be done.</para>

  <tip>
    <para>To build row layouts for the three standard report types—income
    statement, balance sheet, and cash flow—use the same techniques as when
    building <emphasis>ad hoc</emphasis> report row layouts. The only
    difference is you won't need to specify which balances to calculate (e.g.,
    beginning, ending, etc.). The system determines which calculations will be
    done for the standard statement formats.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>In addition to row layouts, you may also define column layouts for
  your cash flow report. Column layouts are used to specify the time buckets
  financial information will be sorted into. You specify a column layout to
  use when viewing or printing financial reports. You may define any number of
  column layouts. Each layout will be linked to either a pre-defined report
  definition or a custom report definition you create yourself.</para>

  <para>To create column layouts for a cash flow report, select the
  <guimenuitem>Column Layouts</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/financialLayoutCashFlowCols.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Cash flow report Column Layouts</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating column layouts for a cash flow report, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Column Layouts</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists column layouts defined for the cash flow
        report.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>ADD</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to add a column layout.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To create a new column layout, select the <guibutton>ADD</guibutton>
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/financialLayoutCashFlowColNew.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Add new Column Layout</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When adding a new column layout, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name to identify the column layout.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a brief description of the column layout.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report Template</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the report definition you want to associate with the
        column layout.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
    <para>When creating a column layout, you can choose from the following
    standard report templates:</para>

    <para>FinancialReport (used by all <emphasis>ad hoc</emphasis>
    reports)</para>

    <para>FinancialReportMonth</para>

    <para>FinancialReportMonthBudget</para>

    <para>FinancialReportMonthDbCr</para>

    <para>FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth</para>

    <para>FinancialReportMonthPriorQuarter</para>

    <para>FinancialReportMonthPriorYear</para>

    <para>FinancialReportMonthQuarter</para>

    <para>FinancialReportMonthYear</para>

    <para>FinancialReportQuarter</para>

    <para>FinancialReportQuarterBudget</para>

    <para>FinancialReportQuarterPriorQuarter</para>

    <para>FinancialReportYear</para>

    <para>FinancialReportYearBudget</para>

    <para>FinancialReportYearPriorYear</para>

    <para>FinancialTrend (used by non-ad-hoc trend reports)</para>

    <para>If for some reason these templates don't meet your needs, you can
    always use OpenRPT to a) modify them or b) create your own custom report
    templates.</para>
  </tip>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected Period</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select the time period(s) you want to have included in the
        column layout:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Month</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to have the current month included as one of the
              columns in the layout. The month used as the basis for the
              reporting is specified when the report is run. If selected, you
              will also have the option to include the prior month in the
              layout.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Quarter</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to have the current quarter included as one of the
              columns in the layout. The month used as the basis for the
              reporting is specified when the report is run. If selected, you
              will also have the option to include the prior quarter in the
              layout.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Year</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to have the current fiscal year-to-date included as
              one of the columns in the layout. The month used as the basis
              for the reporting is specified when the report is run. If
              selected, you will also have the option to include the prior
              fiscal year in the layout.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Show Debits and Credits</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to have debits and credits included as columns for
              each of the time periods (month, quarter, year) specified for
              the layout.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>% of Group Total</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to have the percentage of group total included as a
              column for each of the time periods (month, quarter, year)
              specified for the layout. This information will only be shown
              for groups and accounts whose row definition specifies Show % of
              Group Total.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>There is no relationship between the selected time periods in a
    column layout and the trend report options available when viewing a
    financial report. Trend reporting ignores column layouts.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Prior</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include prior time period information in the column
        layout by selecting from the following options:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Period: Will include information for the accounting period
            immediately prior to the period specified when the financial
            report is run. You must also select at least one of the
            time-period check boxes below (<guilabel>Full Month</guilabel> or
            <guilabel>Full Quarter</guilabel>) for prior information to be
            included.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Year: Will include information for the fiscal year
            immediately prior to the current year specified when the financial
            report is run. You must also select at least one of the
            time-period check boxes below (<guilabel>Full Month</guilabel>,
            <guilabel>Full Quarter</guilabel>, etc.) for prior information to
            be included.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Full Month: If selected, a full month's worth of information
            will be included when the report is run—depending on the prior
            time period specified above. If the <guilabel>Period</guilabel>
            option is specified, then the month immediately prior to the
            selected accounting period will be included. If the
            <guilabel>Year</guilabel> option is specified, then the selected
            month in the prior fiscal year will be included.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Full Quarter: If selected, a full quarter's worth of
            information will be included when the report is run—depending on
            the prior time period specified above. If the
            <guilabel>Period</guilabel> option is specified, then the quarter
            immediately prior to the selected accounting period's quarter will
            be included. If the <guilabel>Year</guilabel> option is specified,
            then the selected quarter in the prior fiscal year will be
            included.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Full Year: If selected, the full prior fiscal year's worth
            of information will be included when the report is run.</para>

            <tip>
              <para>The <guilabel>Full Year</guilabel> and <guilabel>Year To
              Date</guilabel> check boxes are not affected by the
              <guilabel>Period</guilabel> or <guilabel>Year</guilabel>
              selections.</para>
            </tip>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Year To Date: If selected, the current fiscal year to date's
            worth of information will be included when the report is
            run.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>% of Group Total: If selected, the percentage of the group
            total for the prior time period will be included when the report
            is run. This information will only be shown for groups and
            accounts whose row definition specifies Show % of Group
            Total.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Difference: If selected, the amount of difference between
            the selected accounting period and the prior time period will be
            included when the report is run.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>% of Difference: If selected, the percentage difference
            between the selected accounting period and the prior time period
            will be included when the report is run.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Budget</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include budget information in the column layout. If
        selected, the following additional options will be available:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>% of Group Total</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, the budget percentage of the group total will
              be included when the report is run. This information will only
              be shown for groups and accounts whose row definition specifies
              Show % of Group Total.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Difference</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, the amount of difference between the selected
              accounting period and the budget for the period will be included
              when the report is run.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>% of Difference</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>If selected, the percentage difference between the
              selected accounting period and the budget for the period will be
              included when the report is run.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To specify additional configuration options for the layout of your
  cash flow report, select the <guimenuitem>Options</guimenuitem> tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/financialLayoutCashFlowOpts.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Cash flow report Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When specifying additional configuration options for the layout of
  your cash flow report, you are presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Grand Total</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to include a grand total in the financial
        report.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Alternate Labels</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>You have the option to substitute alternate text for the
        following column headers or row labels when viewing or printing your
        financial report:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Alternate Debits</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify an alternate label to use as the header text for
              the debits column. If not specified, the default text will be
              used.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Alternate Credits</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify an alternate label to use as the header text for
              the credits column. If not specified, the default text will be
              used.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Alternate Budget</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify an alternate label to use as the header text for
              the budget column. If not specified, the default text will be
              used.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Alternate Grand Total</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify an alternate label to use as the text for the
              grand total row. If not specified, the default text will be
              used.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>Any notes you add to a financial report definition will appear at
    the bottom of the financial report when the financial report is
    printed.</para>
  </note>
</section>
