<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="financialLayoutIncStatement">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>financial reports</primary>

      <secondary>income statement type</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>income statement reports</primary>
    </indexterm>Income Statement Report</title>

  <para>The system ships with a basic income statement designed to generate
  financial reports using your revenue and expense account data. In this
  section, we will examine this basic income statement.</para>

  <note>
    <para>Because the basic income statement is a system-defined financial
    report, it may not be modified (except to make it active or inactive).
    However, you may copy the report and modify the copy. You can think of the
    basic income statement as a template for building other, similar financial
    reports.</para>

    <para role="xtprjaccnt">If the xTuple Project Accounting package is
    installed, the basic income statement will be available to
    projects.</para>
  </note>

  <para>To view the basic income statement, select it for editing from the
  master list of financial reports. A message will alert you that this is a
  system-defined report which may only be viewed, not edited. Select the
  <guibutton>OK</guibutton> button to reach the following screen:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/financialLayoutIncStatement.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Basic income statement system-defined</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>The <guimenuitem>Row Layout</guimenuitem> tab displays information on
  all the account groups and account numbers which make up the basic income
  statement. If this were a custom report you were creating, you would be able
  to add/remove account groups and account numbers to meet your specific
  needs.</para>

  <tip>
    <para>To build row layouts for the three standard report types—income
    statement, balance sheet, and cash flow—use the same techniques as when
    building <emphasis>ad hoc</emphasis> report row layouts. The only
    difference is you won't need to specify which balances to calculate (e.g.,
    beginning, ending, etc.). The system determines which calculations will be
    done for the standard statement formats.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>When viewing row layouts for the basic income statement, you are
  presented with the following columns:</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Group/Account Name</emphasis>: Lists the
      account groups and account types used in the report. The two main groups
      are <guilabel>REVENUE</guilabel> and <guilabel>EXPENSES</guilabel>. All
      accounts having <guilabel>Type=Revenue</guilabel> are included in the
      <guilabel>REVENUE</guilabel> group. And within the
      <guilabel>EXPENSES</guilabel> group all accounts having
      <guilabel>Type=Expense</guilabel> are included.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Sub./Summ.</emphasis>: Indicates whether
      group information will be presented as a subtotal or summary line when
      the report is run. In the basic income statement, all account groups are
      subtotaled.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Oper.</emphasis>: Specifies whether a group
      will be added to (<guibutton>+</guibutton>) or subtracted from
      (<guibutton>-</guibutton>) the group total. In the basic income
      statement, <guilabel>REVENUE</guilabel> is added to and
      <guilabel>EXPENSES</guilabel> are subtracted from the
      <guilabel>INCOME</guilabel> group.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <note>
    <para>Select the <guibutton>VIEW</guibutton> button to see the
    system-defined settings for each account group and account type used in
    the basic income statement. When creating your own reports, you may choose
    to either imitate or alter these default settings.</para>
  </note>

  <para>In addition to row layouts, you may also define column layouts for
  your financial reports. Column layouts are used to specify the time buckets
  financial information will be sorted into. You specify a column layout to
  use when viewing or printing financial reports. You may define any number of
  column layouts. Each layout will be linked to either a pre-defined report
  definition or a custom report definition you create yourself.</para>

  <para>On the basic income statement, select the <guimenuitem>Column
  Layouts</guimenuitem> tab to view all the time buckets available for the
  report. If this were a custom report you were creating, you would be able to
  add/remove column layouts to meet your specific needs.</para>

  <tip>
    <para>See <xref linkend="financialLayoutCashFlow"/> for specific examples
    describing the various column layout options.</para>
  </tip>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/financialLayoutIncStatementCols.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Basic income statement Column Layouts</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When viewing column layouts for the basic income statement, you are
  presented with the following column definitions—each of which defines a
  different time bucket available for viewing income statement
  information:</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Month</emphasis>: Displays data for the
      current month (i.e., accounting period). The month used as the basis for
      the reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses the
      <literal>FinancialReportMonth</literal> report definition.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Month, Budget</emphasis>: Displays data for
      the current month, compared to budget information for the current month.
      The month used as the basis for the reporting is specified when the
      report is run. Uses the <literal>FinancialReportMonthBudget</literal>
      report definition.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Month, Prior Month</emphasis>: Displays data
      for the current month, compared to the prior month. The month used as
      the basis for the reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses
      the <literal>FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth</literal> report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Month, Prior Year Month</emphasis>: Displays
      data for the current month, compared to the same month in the prior
      fiscal year. The month used as the basis for the reporting is specified
      when the report is run. Uses the
      <literal>FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth</literal> report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Month, QTD</emphasis>: Displays data for the
      current month, compared to the current quarter to-date. The month used
      as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses
      the <literal>FinancialReportMonthQuarter</literal> report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Month, YTD</emphasis>: Displays data for the
      current month, compared to the current fiscal year to-date. The month
      used as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report is run.
      Uses the <literal>FinancialReportMonthYear</literal> report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">QTD</emphasis>: Displays data for the
      current quarter to-date. The month used as the basis for the reporting
      is specified when the report is run. Uses the
      <literal>FinancialReportQuarter</literal> report definition.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">QTD, Budget</emphasis>: Displays data for
      the current quarter to-date, compared to budget information for the
      current quarter. The month used as the basis for the reporting is
      specified when the report is run. Uses the
      <literal>FinancialReportQuarterBudget</literal> report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">QTD, Prior Quarter</emphasis>: Displays data
      for the current quarter to-date, compared to the prior quarter. The
      month used as the basis for the reporting is specified when the report
      is run. Uses the <literal>FinancialReportQuarterPriorQuarter</literal>
      report definition.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">QTD, Prior Year Quarter</emphasis>: Displays
      data for the current quarter to-date, compared to the same quarter in
      the prior fiscal year. The month used as the basis for the reporting is
      specified when the report is run. Uses the
      <literal>FinancialReportQuarterPriorQuarter</literal> report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">YTD</emphasis>: Displays data for the
      current fiscal year to-date. The month used as the basis for the
      reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses the
      <literal>FinancialReportYear</literal> report definition.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">YTD, Budget</emphasis>: Displays data for
      the current fiscal year to-date, compared to budget information for the
      current fiscal year to-date. The month used as the basis for the
      reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses the
      <literal>FinancialReportYearBudget</literal> report definition.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">YTD, Prior Full Year</emphasis>: Displays
      data for the current fiscal year to-date, compared to information for
      the entire prior fiscal year. The month used as the basis for the
      reporting is specified when the report is run. Uses the
      <literal>FinancialReportYearPriorYear</literal> report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">YTD, Prior Year YTD</emphasis>: Displays
      data for the current fiscal year to-date, compared to the prior fiscal
      year to-date. The month used as the basis for the reporting is specified
      when the report is run. Uses the
      <literal>FinancialReportYearPriorYear</literal> report
      definition.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <note>
    <para>Select the <guibutton>VIEW</guibutton> button to see the
    system-defined settings for each account group and account type used in
    the basic income statement. When creating your own reports, you may choose
    to either imitate or alter these default settings.</para>
  </note>

  <tip>
    <para>When creating a column layout, you can choose from the following
    standard report templates:</para>

    <para>FinancialReport (used by all <emphasis>ad hoc</emphasis>
    reports)</para>

    <para>FinancialReportMonth</para>

    <para>FinancialReportMonthBudget</para>

    <para>FinancialReportMonthDbCr</para>

    <para>FinancialReportMonthPriorMonth</para>

    <para>FinancialReportMonthPriorQuarter</para>

    <para>FinancialReportMonthPriorYear</para>

    <para>FinancialReportMonthQuarter</para>

    <para>FinancialReportMonthYear</para>

    <para>FinancialReportQuarter</para>

    <para>FinancialReportQuarterBudget</para>

    <para>FinancialReportQuarterPriorQuarter</para>

    <para>FinancialReportYear</para>

    <para>FinancialReportYearBudget</para>

    <para>FinancialReportYearPriorYear</para>

    <para>FinancialTrend (used by non-ad-hoc trend reports)</para>

    <para>If for some reason these templates don't meet your needs, you can
    always use OpenRPT to a) modify them or b) create your own custom report
    templates.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>To view additional configuration options for the layout of the basic
  income statement, select the <guimenuitem>Options</guimenuitem> tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/financialLayoutIncStatementOpt.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Basic income statement Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>The layout for the basic income statement does not use any extra
  configuration options. However, if you were creating your own income
  statement layout, you could choose to a) include a grand total row and b)
  use alternate labels for budget and grand total rows when viewing and/or
  printing the financial report.</para>

  <note>
    <para>Any notes you add to a financial report definition will appear at
    the bottom of the financial report when the financial report is
    printed.</para>
  </note>
</section>
