<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="fixCountries">
  <title>Fix Countries</title>

  <para>The Fix Countries utility is designed to help you clean up country
  information in your database so your addresses will have valid country names
  associated with them. The utility is an extension package available for free
  from the <ulink url="http://www.xtuple.com/xchange">xTuple xChange</ulink>.
  The utility is especially useful for anyone seeking to enforce the use of
  valid country names. To learn more about the CRM configuration which
  enforces the use of valid country names, please see <xref
  linkend="configureCRM"/>.</para>

  <para>To access the utility, go to <guimenuitem>CRM &gt; Utilities &gt; Fix
  Countries before setting Strict Countries option</guimenuitem>. The
  following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/fixCountries.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Fix Countries Utility</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When fixing country information in your database, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>QUERY</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to query the database and return any records which
        contain invalid countries. The list of records found will be displayed
        below.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>FIX CASE DIFFERENCES</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to fix instances where the case of letters in a country
        name are non-conforming. For example, the utility will change all
        occurrences of "HOMELAND" or "HomeLand" to "Homeland."</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>REPLACE ABBREVIATIONS</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to replace country name abbreviations with a valid
        country name. For example, all occurrences of "HL" would be changed to
        "Homeland."</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>BULK REPLACE</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to replace all occurrences of an invalid country name
        with a valid country name that you choose.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>EDIT SELECTION</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a record and then select this button to manually fix
        the record. If a changed address remains on the list, you can delete
        duplicates from the master list of addresses.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>ADD COUNTRY</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select for the rare case when you need to add a new country to
        the list of countries. Adding new countries should be discouraged. To
        learn more about the list of available country names, please see <xref
        linkend="countries"/>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show closed records</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include historical data, such as closed sales orders
        and posted credit memos and invoices. These records will continue to
        print properly if you don't fix them, but if you edit the records you
        will have to change the country when strict country enforcement is
        turned on.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
