<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="invoiceItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>invoices</primary>

      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Invoice Item</title>

  <para>To add a new invoice line item, select the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton>
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/invoiceItem.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Create Invoice Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating a new invoice line item, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Invoice #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the invoice number specified in the Invoice
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the line item number for the current line item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Type</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Indicate the item type for the invoice line item, by selecting
        one of the following options:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>The lookup feature located to the right of the field leads
              to a searchable list of inventory items. The list will contain
              sold items available for purchase by the specified customer. The
              list of available items may vary from customer to customer,
              depending on how pricing schedules are implemented at your site.
              Once an item number is entered, the inventory unit of measure
              (UOM) and item description will automatically appear.
              Additionally, you may also specify the item's supplying site.
              Items may be supplied from multiple sites. Sites designated as
              sold from sites in the Item Site master for an item are
              considered <guilabel>Supplying Sites</guilabel> on this screen.
              By default, the item site with the highest ranking will be
              selected as the supplying site. If more than one item site share
              a ranking of <guilabel>1</guilabel>, the default supplying site
              will be selected in alphabetical order. Item sites are ranked
              using the ranking mechanism on the Item Site master.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Miscellaneous</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter a name and description for the miscellaneous,
              non-inventory item you are billing the customer for. The name
              and description fields are free-form, meaning they accept
              unlimited alphanumeric characters. You must also select a sales
              category. Sales categories are used to identify the general
              ledger (G/L) accounts to be used when non-inventory sales
              transactions take place.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Alternate Revenue Account</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify an alternate account to be used as the revenue account.
        This account will be used instead of the typical accounts pre-defined
        in the receivables assignments. For example, you might use this
        alternate account in the scenario where you are doing business with
        customers who are part of the same buyer's group (i.e., customer
        group).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer P/N</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>If applicable, enter a customer part number to further identify
        the item you are billing the customer for. In the case of inventory
        items, the customer part number will display automatically if you
        enter an item alias in the <guilabel>Item Number</guilabel> field. To
        enter an item alias, place the cursor in the <guilabel>Item
        Number</guilabel> field and then use the keyboard shortcut
        <guibutton>CTRL + A</guibutton>. After you have entered a valid item
        alias, hit the <guibutton>TAB</guibutton> key. A list of items that
        use the specified item alias will be displayed. Select the desired
        item from the list. The item alias will display as the customer part
        number. Item aliases are defined on the Item master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Ordered</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the item you are billing for. The quantity
        ordered for inventory items is measured in the item's inventory
        UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>The quantity ordered for inventory items is based on the inventory
    UOM. But the price is based on the price UOM. Whenever these two UOMs are
    not identical, the extended price for a line item will be based on the
    following formula:</para>

    <informalexample>
      <para><literal>(Qty. Ordered) x (Price/Inv. Ratio) x (Net Unit
      Price)</literal></para>
    </informalexample>

    <para>If for some reason the prices don't look correct, check the Item
    master for the line item in question. It may be that the inventory and
    price UOMs do not exist in a 1:1 relationship.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Billed</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the quantity of ordered items you are billing
        for.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Update Inventory</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the quantity billed to be removed from
              inventory when you post the invoice. If not selected, your
              inventory will not be updated.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. UOM</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the UOM to be used when selling the line item. Sold
        items may be assigned multiple selling UOMs. These alternate UOMs may
        be defined on the Item master. You may also select a global conversion
        ratio here. Global conversions have the label
        <literal>Global</literal> appended to them. If a line item has no
        selling UOM defined, then the inventory UOM will be used here by
        default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>invoices</primary>

          <secondary>line item pricing for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Net Unit Price</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the unit price for the invoice item. By default, the
        system will choose the lower of the following two prices: A) The
        most-specific pricing schedule assignment or B) any sale in effect at
        the time of order entry. The specificity of pricing schedule
        assignments is determined in the following descending order: by
        customer ship-to address (most specific), by customer, by customer
        type, by customer type pattern, by all customers. The lookup feature
        located to the right of the field leads to a Price List screen.</para>

        <note>
          <para>For inventory items having assigned pricing schedules, the net
          unit price will be automatically calculated using the information
          provided above. For miscellaneous items, the net unit price must be
          entered manually.</para>
        </note>

        <para>If your pricing schedule has multiple UOM on it (or if several
        pricing schedules share the same level of price specificity, but they
        have different UOMs) then the UOM which matches the selected UOM will
        be chosen—that is, as long as the quantity break does not exceed the
        quantity being priced. If no entry matches the UOM with a quantity
        break less than the quantity being priced, then the lowest value price
        for any UOM will be chosen. To make sure a specific UOM is always
        chosen at the desired level of price specificity, then your pricing
        schedules should include at least one UOM with a quantity break of
        zero.</para>

        <tip>
          <para>The system can be configured to prevent users from editing the
          net unit price. If your system is configured that way, the
          <guilabel>Net Unit Price</guilabel> field will not be
          editable.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pricing UOM</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The price UOM is the same as the selling UOM. If an item has
        selling UOMs defined, then the item may be sold and priced in these
        alternate UOMs. You may also select a global conversion ratio here.
        Global conversions have the label <literal>Global</literal> appended
        to them. If no selling UOMs are defined, then the inventory UOM will
        be used here by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Extended Price</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the extended price. The extended price for a line item
        is based on the quantity ordered multiplied by the net unit
        price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To view costing and tax information related to the invoice item,
  select the <guimenuitem>Detail</guimenuitem> tab. You will be presented with
  the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Unit Cost (Inv. UOM)</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the standard cost per unit in the item's inventory
        UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>List Price</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the item's list price per inventory UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Price</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the price (per inventory UOM) given to the specified
        customer for the specified item. Special customer prices can be set
        for individual customers or customer groups by using a pricing
        schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The following tax-related information is available:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Type</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the tax type for the invoice item. If the Item
              master does not have a tax type for the invoice's tax authority,
              then no tax will be charged.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Tax</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the amount of tax to be charged for the invoice
              line item quantity. To get a detailed view of the tax
              calculation, click on the <guibutton>Tax</guibutton> link using
              your mouse.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To add notes to an invoice line item, select the
  <guimenuitem>Notes</guimenuitem> tab at the bottom of the screen. If the
  invoice was created from a sales order, any sales order line item notes will
  be transferred to the invoice. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/invoiceItem_tab.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Invoice Item Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When entering invoice line item notes, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general notes related to the invoice item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
