<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="issueToShipping">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>shipping</primary>

      <secondary>issuing stock to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Issue to Shipping</title>

  <para>Once Sales Order (or Transfer Order) line items are ready to be
  shipped, they must be issued to Shipping. Shipping is a two-step process.
  Quantity is first issued to Shipping, and then it is shipped.</para>

  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>job items</primary>

      <secondary>posting production for</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>shipping</primary>

      <secondary>job items and</secondary>
    </indexterm>For Job items linked to Sales Order items, the act of issuing
  to Shipping serves a dual purpose. On the one hand, quantity is issued to
  Shipping. But at the same time, production for the linked Job item Work
  Order is also posted. Issuing to Shipping is the only way to post production
  for a Job item Work Order. If the Job item is Lot/Serial controlled, you
  will be prompted to assign Lot/Serial numbers when quantity is issued to
  Shipping.</para>

  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>kits</primary>

      <secondary>issuing to shipping</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>shipping</primary>

      <secondary>kits and</secondary>
    </indexterm>When Kit items appear on a Sales Order, the Kit components may
  be issued to Shipping. However, the parent Kit item may not be. The
  automatic "Select for Billing" option takes effect for Kit items when all
  Kit items are shipped.</para>

  <para>To issue Stock to Shipping, select the "Issue to Shipping" option. The
  following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/issueToShipping.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption id="issueToShippingStockToShipping">Issue to
        Shipping</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <tip>
    <para>Before a Sales Order can be shipped successfully, Sales Account and
    Receivables Assignments for the specified Customer must be in
    place.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>When issuing Stock to Shipping, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select the site you wish to issue from.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Transaction Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date you want the transaction to be posted to the
        General Ledger. The current day's date will display by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Order Number of the Order whose Stock you want to
        issue to Shipping. Sales Orders and Transfer Orders may be issued to
        Shipping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipment #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Shipment Number for the Order, if any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Require sufficient Inventory</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to ensure you have enough quantity on hand (QOH) of a
        line item prior to issuing to Shipping. If selected, this option will
        prevent you from issuing line item quantity to Shipping if doing so
        would force QOH for the item site to fall below zero. Not selecting
        this option means issuing Stock to Shipping may drive item site QOH
        negative.</para>

        <note>
          <para>If your site is configured to enable Sales Order Reservations,
          which, by definition, require sufficient inventory before items may
          be shipped, then the "Require sufficient Inventory" option will
          selected and disabled.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Items with Reservations</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Sales Order line items available for Shipping with
        expanded view of reserved items. If the Scheduled Date for an
        unshipped line item is in the future, the line will display in green
        text. If the Scheduled Date for an unshipped line item is not in the
        future, the line will display in red text. Once shipped, all line
        items revert to black text. To manually reserve or unreserve stock for
        an Order item, right click on reserved item quantity in the expanded
        view.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Issue Items Using Bar Code</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is an optional field which allows you to issue stock to
        Shipping using a Bar Code scanner. Enter a Bar Code for a Sales Order
        line item using a Bar Code scanner—or manually enter the Bar Code. The
        Bar Code for an item is stored on the Item master. Once the code is
        entered, specify a quantity and then select the FIND button to issue
        the line item quantity to shipping. You may also hit the ENTER key on
        your keyboard to select the FIND button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
    <para>Most scanners allow you to change a setting that automatically sends
    the ENTER command after a scan. This allows keyboard-free entry.</para>
  </tip>

  <note>
    <para>The issue to shipping window will accept a variety of xTuple
    formatted bar codes that print on standard paperwork including Sales Order
    header number, line number, work order number, and item number. These
    specially formatted bar codes allow xTuple to recognize the bar code input
    regardless of where the cursor is on the window. Bar codes, however, do
    not have the necessary prefix embedded in the code to explicitly tell the
    window it is a bar code, which is why xTuple requires the cursor to be
    focused on the bar code field if bar codes are being scanned.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty.</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the quantity of line items to be issued using a Bar
        Code. To issue the line item quantity to shipping, select the FIND
        button—or hit the ENTER key on your keyboard to select the FIND
        button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>If the "Require Reservations" setting is selected under Sales Order
    Setup, you will not be able to issue more than what is reserved.</para>
  </note>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SHIP</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to Ship the specified Sales Order, as described in <xref
        linkend="shipOrder"/>.</para>

        <note>
          <para>If an Order is marked "Ship Complete," you will be prevented
          from shipping the Order until all line item quantities are issued to
          Shipping.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>ISSUE STOCK</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a line item, then select this button to issue stock to
        Shipping. You may also double-click on a line item to reach the Issue
        Stock screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>If an item issued to Shipping is a <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>multiple location control</primary>

        <secondary>impact on shipping</secondary>
      </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
        <primary>shipping</primary>

        <secondary>MLC impact on</secondary>
      </indexterm>Multiple Location Control (MLC) item, you will be prompted
    to specify the Location you want to issue stock from.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ISSUE LINE</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a line item, then select this button to issue the
        balance of the Line to shipping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>RETURN STOCK</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a line item, then select this button to remove the
        line quantity from Shipping, returning the stock to inventory. This
        button will only be enabled only if there is line item quantity at
        Shipping. If the original line item you shipped was either Lot/Serial
        or Multiple Location Controlled, the system will automatically put the
        inventory back where it came from.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
    <para>If your site integrates UPS WorldShip with the system, you should
    process Orders in WorldShip after they have been issued to Shipping—but
    before they have been shipped.</para>
  </tip>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>ISSUE ALL</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to issue all line items to Shipping simultaneously. If
        some line items have insufficient quantity to ship, these will be
        prevented; however, all line items with sufficient quantity will be
        issued.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>FIND</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Compares the Bar Code entered in the "Issue Items Using Bar
        code" field with the Bar Codes for the listed Sales Order line items,
        then issues to Shipping the quantity specified in the "Qty." field.
        The FIND button may be selected using your mouse—or by hitting the
        ENTER key, which corresponds to the FIND button. Because the FIND
        button corresponds to the ENTER key, you can scan in a Bar Code and
        then hit ENTER to issue a quantity of one to Shipping. If you prefer,
        you can scan in a Bar Code and then specify a different quantity
        before hitting ENTER.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <xi:include href="issueLineToShipping.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
