<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="itemSite">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>item sites</primary>

      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Enter Item Site</title>

  <para>An item site identifies and defines the methods and controls used when
  maintaining a given item within a given site. To enter a new item site into
  your system, select the "Enter Item Site" option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemSite.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Create New Item Site</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating a new item site, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the item you want to create an item
        site for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>inventory unit of measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify site where the item site is located.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate the item site is active. Not selecting means
        the item site will be considered inactive. If inactive, the item site
        will not appear on lists of active item sites. To re-activate an item
        site, simply select this option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site can manufacture this item</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the item can be manufactured at the specified site.
        Planned work orders from the material requirements planning (MRP)
        system can only be created for item sites having this option selected.
        This option is not available for purchased or outside process items if
        job costing is selected.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Create Work Orders linked to Sales Orders</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to create work orders whenever sales orders demand
              quantities from the item site. This option pertains to
              manufactured items. If you select this option, you are
              indicating that you want work orders to be generated for the
              item in question whenever quantities are demanded by a sales
              order. To ensure the "Create Work Order" flag is always enabled
              on the Sales Order Line Item screen, set the "Stocked" option on
              the Item Site screen to "False." When the "Stocked" option is
              "True," the "Create Work Order" flag will be available but
              turned off by default on the Sales Order Line Item
              screen.</para>

              <note>
                <para>Work orders created, as specified above, to meet sales
                order demand will be created regardless of an item's
                availability—and also regardless of whether material
                requirements planning (MRP) is being run in parallel.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site can purchase this item</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want the item site to be used for purchasing the
        item. This option will be selected automatically (and cannot be
        changed) for purchased or outside process items when the job costing
        method is specified.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Create purchase requests for work order requirements</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to create purchase requests whenever work orders
              demand quantities from the item site. This option pertains to
              purchased and outside-process items. If you select this option,
              you are indicating that you want purchase requests to be
              automatically generated for the item in question whenever
              quantities are demanded by work orders.</para>

              <note>
                <para>Purchase requests created to meet work order or sales
                order demand will be created regardless of item
                availability—and also regardless of whether material
                requirements planning (MRP) is being run in parallel.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Create Purchase Requests for Sales Orders</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to create purchase requests whenever sales orders
              demand quantities from the item site. This option pertains to
              purchased and outside-process items. If you select this option,
              you are indicating that you want purchase requests to be
              automatically generated for the item in question whenever
              quantities are demanded by sales orders. This option and the
              "Create Purchase Orders linked to Sales Orders" option are
              mutually exclusive.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>drop shipping</primary>

                <secondary>item site settings for</secondary>
              </indexterm>Create Purchase Orders linked to Sales Orders</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to create purchase orders linked to sales orders.
              You must have at least one item source defined for the item to
              use this option. Linking purchase orders to sales order creates
              the basic foundation for drop shipment functionality. This
              option and the "Create Purchase Requests for sales orders"
              option are mutually exclusive. If your site is configured to use
              drop shipping, the following additional option will also be
              available:</para>

              <para role="standard"><variablelist>
                  <varlistentry>
                    <term>Drop ship Items by default</term>

                    <listitem>
                      <para>If selected, the "Drop Ship" flag will always be
                      turned ON when sales order line items are created for
                      drop ship items. Do not select this option if you want
                      users to manually select the "Drop Ship" flag when
                      entering sales orders. This option will only be visible
                      if your site is configured to use drop shipping.</para>
                    </listitem>
                  </varlistentry>
                </variablelist></para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sold from this Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select if item is sold from specified site. If selected, "Sold
        from" means that sales orders line items may request to Ship from the
        site. When adding sales order line items to a sales order, a "Sold
        from" site appears as the "Supplying" site.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>ranking</primary>

                <secondary>of item sites</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>sold ranking</primary>

                <secondary>for item sites</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>item sites</primary>

                <secondary>sold ranking of</secondary>
              </indexterm>Ranking</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter
              a value up to a maximum of 10. Value entered specifies the order
              in which item sites will be chosen during sales order and sales
              quote creation. If an item is located in more than one "Sold
              from" site, the item site with the highest ranking will be
              chosen first. If two item sites happen to share the same
              ranking, selection will be based on alphabetical order. The
              highest ranking an item site can have is one (1).</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Control</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The following control options are required for every item
        site:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>control methods</primary>

                <secondary>at item site level</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>item sites</primary>

                <secondary>control methods in</secondary>
              </indexterm>Control Method</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select a control method for the item site from the
              available options:</para>

              <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>None</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select if you don"t care to see inventory history
                    transactions for the item site.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Regular</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select to monitor inventory history transactions for
                    the item site using a Regular method. Regular means
                    without Lot number or Serial number control.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry role="standard">
                  <term>Lot #</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select to impose Lot number control methods on the
                    item site. Item sites using Lot number control are subject
                    to unique processing requirements whenever inventory is
                    received or distributed.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry role="standard">
                  <term>Serial #</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select to impose Serial number control methods on
                    the item site. Item sites using Serial number control are
                    subject to unique processing requirements whenever
                    inventory is received or distributed.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Planner Code</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the planner code you want to assign the item site
              to. Assigning a planner code to an item site makes it possible
              to group item sites by planner code for the purposes of
              Planning.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>item sites</primary>

                <secondary>cost categories in</secondary>
              </indexterm>Cost Category</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the cost category you want to associate with the
              item site. This requirement helps ensure that all inventory
              transactions involving an item site will be properly tracked and
              recorded in the general ledger.</para>

              <note>
                <para>If you ever need to change the cost category for an item
                site having quantity on hand (QOH), the inventory value will
                be transferred in the Ledger from the initial asset account to
                the new asset account.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Costing Method</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the item site costing method by selecting one of the
        available options:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>None</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>This cost method is automatically selected for the item
              site if the Control Method is "None" or the Item type is
              "Reference".</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Average</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Cost distributions are based on an average of all costs
              accumulated for the item site. The QOH of item sites defined
              with this cost method will not be allowed to go negative.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Standard</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Cost distributions are based on the standard cost posted
              for the item. This is the default costing method for all
              newly-created item sites.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry id="itemSiteJobItem">
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>job items</primary>

                <secondary>costing for</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>costing</primary>

                <secondary>for job items</secondary>
              </indexterm>Job</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Cost distributions are based on actual accumulation of
              costs on a work order. This cost method should be used for
              manufactured items which you want to handle as job items. job
              items are specifically for make-to-order or service (i.e.,
              repair) scenarios where simplified production is required. Job
              items cannot be maintained in inventory. Job items also have no
              concept of standard cost or cost variances. All costs for job
              items are actual. The work orders which create job items can
              only be created via a sales order. The costs for job item work
              orders are accumulated to WIP, and then transferred directly to
              cost of sales when the job is shipped. Production for a job item
              work order is posted when the linked sales order item is issued
              to shipping. BOM and routing items may be assigned to job items;
              however, they will not roll up to a standard cost for job items.
              Job items may be configured. This means you can add list prices
              to any job item characteristics. These characteristic prices are
              then added to the base price of sales order items when the
              characteristic is selected at sales order entry.</para>

              <note>
                <para>Job cost items must have a control method of Regular,
                Lot, or Serial.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Settings</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select from the following settings options:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Stocked</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the item is stocked at the specified site. This
              option is used in conjunction with the "Create Work Orders
              linked to Sales Orders" option on the Item Site screen. When the
              "Stocked" flag is set to "False," the "Create Work Order" flag
              on the Sales Order Line Item screen will be enabled by default.
              Conversely, when the "Stocked" flag is set to "True," the
              "Create Work Order" flag will be available but turned off by
              default on the Sales Order Line Item screen. This setting is
              also used to drive the constraint management system. As a
              result, to avoid inaccurate results when running that system, an
              item site must also have a Reorder Level defined to use this
              option.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Allow Automatic Updates</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to allow the ABC Class setting for the item site to
              be updated whenever the ABC Class update utility is run. Not
              selecting indicates the ABC Class for the item site should not
              be updated whenever the ABC Class update utility is run.</para>

              <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>ABC Class</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Specify the ABC classification for the specified
                    item.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Cycl. Cnt. Freq.</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Cnt. Freq.: Select a number using the arrow buttons, or
              manually enter a value up to a maximum of 999. A Cycle Count is
              a periodic issue of a Count Tag to count inventory quantity
              within an item site. The Cycle Count frequency defines the
              length of that period, measured in days.</para>

              <tip>
                <para>To monitor the frequency of item site Cycle Counts, view
                the "Last Counted" column in any of the item site Reports: by
                item, by class code, etc. The Last Counted date represents the
                date a Count Tag was last posted (not simply issued) for the
                item site.</para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>event fences</primary>

                <secondary>in item sites</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>item sites</primary>

                <secondary>event fences in</secondary>
              </indexterm>Event Fence</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter
              a value up to a maximum of 999. Specify the period of time,
              measured in days, within which relevant Event notifications
              should be issued. If an Event affecting the item site occurs
              within the Event Fence, then the system will issue a
              notification. Consider the case of a manufactured item whose
              Event Fence is set to five days. Assume that a work order
              exists for this item and that the scheduled start date for that
              work order is three days from the current date. If someone
              were to change the quantity of that work order, the Event
              "WoQtyChanged" would be triggered. And because the work order
              start date falls within the Event Fence for the item site, an
              Event notification would be issued.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Over-ride Work Order Item Cost Recognition Default</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The work order item cost recognition default is set globally at
        the system level. For more information, please see <xref
        linkend="configureWOCostDefaults"/>. However, it is possible to
        override the global default by specifying one of the following options
        at the item site level:</para>

        <para role="manufacturing"><tip>
            <para>The appropriate reporting selections must be made in the
            routing to ensure that labor and overhead costs
            associated with setup and run time operations are reported.</para>
          </tip></para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>To Date</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>When work orders for average cost or job items are
              shipped, all of the WIP costs accumulated to date will be
              charged to cost of sales.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Proportional</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>When work orders for average cost or job items are
              shipped, a value up to the proportional value of the total
              quantity shipped will be charged to cost of sales. For example,
              if three items are to be shipped on a job work order and all the
              material has been issued—and if only 1 of the 3 is shipped—then
              1/3 of the value charged to WIP at that point will be charged to
              cost of sales.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Automatic Lot/Serial Numbering</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>If you want lot/serial numbers to be automatically generated
        whenever inventory is received into the item site, then select a
        lot/serial sequence to associate with the item site. Automatically
        generated lot/serial numbers may be overridden manually, if necessary.
        items that require expiration or warranty information will still
        require that information to be entered on the Create Lot/Serial
        screen. For more information, please see <xref
        linkend="lotSerialSequences"/>.</para>

        <note>
          <para>If a user cancels, deletes, or over-writes an automatically
          assigned lot/serial number, the automatically incremented number
          will not be rolled back or reused. This is because there is no way
          to ensure number issuance integrity in an environment where multiple
          users are posting simultaneously—other than to issue new unused
          numbers during every transaction. The system will, however, check
          each number it attempts to issue. If it finds any existing matches
          already in the database for the given item, it will skip past them
          until it finds a previously unused number.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>Item sites have several location control choices. To view location
  control choices for an item site, select the "Locations" tab. The following
  screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemSite_RestrictedLocations.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Locations for Item Site</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When viewing location control choices for an item site, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Multiple Location Control</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the specified item is to be stored in multiple
        locations within a single site. Items designated as multiple location
        control (MLC) items require special processing whenever item
        quantities are distributed.</para>

        <tip>
          <para>Exercise caution when adjusting the multiple location control
          (MLC) setting for an item site. If you turn off MLC for an item site
          which was previously MLC, you will lose detailed inventory records
          for that item site. All quantity will be merged into one QOH value
          for the item site.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>default locations</primary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>locations</primary>

          <secondary>default</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item sites</primary>

          <secondary>setting default locations in</secondary>
        </indexterm>Use Default Location</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Default location: Select to designate one location within a site
        as the default location for the specified item. This option may be
        used for single location and multiple location control (MLC) items
        alike. You may find that inventory distributions for MLC items are
        greatly simplified if you designate a default location.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Location</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the site location to be used as the default
              location for each of the following:</para>

              <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Receive</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Used for production work order receipts, purchase
                    order receipts, return authorization receipts and
                    miscellaneous inventory receipts.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Stock</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Used for transaction types that do not fall under
                    the other default types (i.e., Receive and W/O
                    Issue).</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry>
                  <term>W/O Issue</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Used for work order material issues and
                    backflushing.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Auto</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>If this automatic distribution checkbox is checked against
              a particular default location, the Distribute Inventory window
              will distribute inventory automatically without providing an
              opportunity to override the default. This will effectively allow
              the posting of inventory transactions for multi-location items
              without having to make any distribution decisions.</para>

              <note>
                <para>This option is not available for items that are Serial
                or Lot controlled.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>User-Defined</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>This is a free-form field for describing storage areas
              with a site not specifically designated as site locations. A
              user-defined location is non-transactional, but may be used for
              reporting purposes.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Location Comment</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter any free-form comment related to the site location. This
        is additional information which may be placed on a pick list or a pack
        list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term>Disallow Blank WIP Locations</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to require the use of work-in-process (WIP) locations
        when posting work order operations for multiple location control (MLC)
        finished goods. WIP locations are an optional feature which may be
        defined on the routing for manufactured MLC items.
        The feature enables you to track finished goods inventory as it moves
        through the manufacturing process. If your site does not combine
        multiple location control with operations posting, then this option
        should be left unchecked.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>site locations</primary>

          <secondary>restricted</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item sites</primary>

          <secondary>restricted locations and</secondary>
        </indexterm>Restricted Locations</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays restricted locations associated with the site the item
        site is located in.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>TOGGLE</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a site location and then select this button to change
        the allowed status for the item. Any changes made on the item site
        master related to an item's allowed status will also be saved to the
        Site location master record.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To set the item site planning parameters, select the "Planning" tab.
  The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemSite_planningTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Item Site Planning</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>When setting the item site planning parameters, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>order parameters</primary>

          <secondary>enforcement of</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item sites</primary>

          <secondary>enforcing order parameters in</secondary>
        </indexterm>Enforce Order Parameters</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enforce order Parameters. If this option is selected,
        then material requirements planning (MRP) will follow the order
        Parameters defined below when generating planned replenishment orders.
        Parameters you define will be saved if this option is turned ON/OFF.
        If you want to enforce order Parameters on manual orders as well,
        select the "on Manual Orders" option.</para>

        <note>
          <para>Running material requirements planning (MRP) on your system
          consists entirely of running the Create planned replenishment orders
          screens—either by item or by planner code. As MRP runs, the planned
          replenishment orders are generated automatically.</para>
        </note>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Reorder Level</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>The Reorder Level specifies when a planned replenishment
              order should be created for an item site. If planned
              availability minus Safety Stock falls below the Reorder Level,
              then a replenishment order will be created when material
              requirements planning (MRP) is run. The Replenishment order
              quantity will be equal to the quantity required to return
              planned availability to either the Reorder Level or the order Up
              To quantity—whichever is greater.</para>

              <note>
                <para>Planned availability differs from QOH. The difference is
                that planned availability considers both QOH and also the
                time-phased demands placed on inventory by sales orders and
                work orders. MRP uses planned availability when calculating
                which item sites require planned replenishment orders.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Order Up To</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>The order Up To (OUT) Level indicates the level of planned
              availability an item site should be replenished up to when
              material requirements planning (MRP) is run. In cases where the
              Reorder Level for an item site exceeds the order up to level,
              MRP will replenish the item site up to the Reorder Level.</para>

              <tip>
                <para>Setting the order up to level to "0" removes any
                restrictions on maximum order quantities. Removing quantity
                restrictions can be an effective strategy to help ensure that
                all order demands are satisfied when MRP is run. Order demands
                may not be met if order up to levels are set below the demand
                threshold.</para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Minimum Order</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Value entered indicates the minimum quantity that may be
              entered for a planned replenishment order when MRP is run. If
              the "on Manual Orders" option is selected above,
              manually-created work orders will recognize the Minimum order
              value.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Maximum Order</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>This is a special setting which regulates the maximum
              quantity for planned replenishment orders when MRP is run. The
              setting does not apply to manual orders, but to planned orders
              only. When a maximum order quantity is specified, MRP will
              ignore order multiples and minimum order specifications—focusing
              instead solely on the maximum order setting. For example, if the
              maximum order quantity is set to 10 and there is demand for 17,
              then planned orders of 10 and 7 would be generated when MRP is
              run.</para>

              <tip>
                <para>Setting the maximum order quantity too low has been
                shown to slow performance when MRP is run. Unless you have
                special needs (i.e., crate packaging limits) which require you
                to set a low maximum order quantity, you should consider
                setting the maximum order value to "0".</para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Order Multiple</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Value entered indicates the quantity multiple that should
              be used for planned replenishment orders when MRP is run. If the
              "on Manual Orders" option is selected above, manually-created
              work orders will recognize the order Multiple value.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Enforce on Manual Orders</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to enforce order Parameters on manually-created
              work orders. If this option is selected, order Parameters will
              also be enforced whenever work orders are manually created. This
              option applies only to the following two parameters: Minimum
              order and order Multiple. The other order Parameters listed
              below do not apply to manually-created work orders. For manual
              purchase orders, the Minimum order and order Multiple parameters
              are determined on a vendor-by-vendor basis, using item source
              masters.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scheduling</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select from the available scheduling options and
        parameters:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry role="standard">
            <term>Planning System</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify which of the following planning systems you want
              the item site to be considered by. Keep in mind that the choice
              of planning system is exclusive. That is, MPS will not create
              planned orders for MRP items when it is run. Likewise, the MRP
              system will not create planned orders for MPS items when it is
              run.</para>

              <variablelist>
                <varlistentry role="standard">
                  <term>MRP</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select if you want the material requirements
                    Planning (MRP) system to create planned orders for the
                    Item when MRP is run.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
                  <term>MPS</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select if you want the Master production Scheduling
                    (MPS) system to create planned orders for the item when
                    MPS is run.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry role="standard">
                  <term>None</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select if you want MRP and MPS to ignore the
                    Item.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Safety Stock</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the quantity of Stock for the item you want to
              keep in inventory to protect against unplanned, unforeseeable
              trends in your order forecasts. When material requirements
              Planning (MRP) is run, the system considers the Safety Stock
              value when determining whether to create planned replenishment
              orders. If planned availability minus Safety Stock is below the
              Reorder Level, then planned orders will be created. If not below
              the Reorder Level, then no planned orders will be created. The
              system's calculation effectively creates a buffer inventory (if
              needed) to handle unexpected fluctuations in demand. If you do
              not want to use the Safety Stock functionality, set the Safety
              Stock value to "0".</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry role="standard">
            <term>Group MPS/MRP Orders Every</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the length of a period—measured in days—within
              which MPS or MRP planned orders will be grouped together (i.e,
              consolidated) to meet demand for the period. The minimum
              possible number of days is one. This functionality serves to
              limit the total number of planned orders, thereby simplifying
              order processing. For example, to consolidate demand for an item
              site into 30-day buckets, set the value to "30." When MRP is
              run, the system will automatically consolidate all demand
              falling within the 30-day horizon into a single planned purchase
              order or planned work order. The grouping of planned orders
              moves forward in time, meaning the system will create as many
              buckets as will fit within the cutoff date specified when MRP is
              run.</para>

              <para>The initial grouping of planned orders is handled
              differently than subsequent buckets. The following formula
              specifies how the date range for the initial group is
              determined:</para>

              <informalexample>
                <para>(First Group) Start Date = Current Date</para>

                <para>(First Group) Due Date = Current Date + Lead Time</para>

                <para>All subsequent groups are determined using the following
                calculations:</para>

                <informalexample>
                  <para>(Next Groups) Start Date = Current Date - Lead
                  Time</para>

                  <para>(Next Groups) Due Date = Group Start Date</para>

                  <variablelist>
                    <varlistentry>
                      <term>First Group</term>

                      <listitem>
                        <para>Select to tell MRP to use the item site lead
                        time for the date range of the first grouping.</para>
                      </listitem>
                    </varlistentry>
                  </variablelist>
                </informalexample>
              </informalexample>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Lead Time</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter
              a value up to a maximum of 999. Specifies the Lead Time for the
              specified item, measured in days. If the item is a manufactured
              item, then the Lead Time refers to the production Lead Time. If
              the item is a purchased item, then the Lead Time refers to the
              planning Lead Time. The procurement Lead Time for purchased
              items is determined on a vendor-by-vendor basis, using Item
              Source masters. Material requirements planning (MRP) will
              consider Lead Times when calculating planned order start dates
              when MRP is run.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
            <term>MPS Time Fence</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the length of the Demand Time Fence by using the
              arrow buttons or manually entering a value up to a maximum of
              999. The Demand Time Fence (also known as the demand fence) is
              used by the Master production Scheduling (MPS) system to
              evaluate when forecasted demand (i.e., from production Plans)
              should be used in place of actual demand (i.e., from sales
              orders)—and vice versa. Measured in days, the Demand Time Fence
              is the period of time extending from the current day to the
              number of days into the future as specified in this field. The
              Demand Time Fence option applies only to those items which
              currently appear on a released production Plan. If demand for
              these items falls within the Demand Time Fence period, then the
              Forecast will be ignored. If demand falls outside the Demand
              Time Fence, then the larger of actual or forecasted demand will
              be used. MPS responds to the demand it locates by creating firm
              planned orders for the required quantities.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry role="standard">
            <term>Create Planned Transfer Orders</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want the item site to have planned transfer
              orders created for it when the material requirements planning
              (MRP) system is run. If selected, MRP will only create planned
              transfer orders for the item site. Planned purchase orders or
              planned work orders will not be created.</para>

              <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Supplied from Site</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Specify which site you want planned transfer orders
                    to be supplied from when MRP is run. The site you select
                    must have a corresponding item site for the specified
                    item.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To add miscellaneous notes to an item site, select the "Notes" tab.
  The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemSite_notesTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Add Item Site Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        free-form notes related to the item site. Notes differ from comments
        in that comments are time/date and user stamped.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To associate comments with an item site, select the "Comments" tab.
  The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemSite_commentsTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Add Item Site Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <xi:include href="../widgets/comments.xml" xpointer="commentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

  <para role="standard">If the item site is Lot or Serial controlled, you will
  have access to several product expiration options. The "Expiration" tab will
  be disabled for non-lot/serial item sites. To view or modify expiration
  settings for the item site, select the "Expiration" tab. The following
  screen will appear:</para>

  <para role="standard"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemSite_expirationTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Expiration Settings for Item Site</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para role="standard">When viewing or modifying expiration settings for the
  item site, you are presented with the following options:</para>

  <para role="standard"><variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Perishable</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select if the item is Perishable. Materials received into a
          Perishable item site are required to have an expiration date,
          thereby increasing your ability to monitor the status of the
          goods.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Requires Warranty when Purchased</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select to require users to enter a warranty expiration date
          when they are receiving items into the item site. Effectively, this
          flag indicates the item site requires a purchased warranty.</para>

          <tip>
            <para>The purchased warranty should not be confused with the sold
            warranty, which is defined on the Item master.</para>
          </tip>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Auto Register Lot/Serial at Shipping</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Select to automatically create a registration for lot/serial
          items when they are issued to shipping. You can learn more about
          registrations in <xref linkend="lotSerialRegistration"/>.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist></para>

  <para role="manufacturing">In order to provide for visibility of tooling for
  Capacity Planning, the system provides the ability to define capacity
  information at the item site level that mirrors capacity data inputs for the
  work center on a scheduling tab. The "Schedule" tab is only be enabled for
  tooling items, and only available on the manufacturing edition of xTuple. To
  view capacity information for tooling items, select the "Schedule" tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>

  <para role="manufacturing"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemSite_itemsiteSched.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Item Site Schedule Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para role="manufacturing">When viewing capacity information for tooling
  items, you are presented with the following options:</para>

  <para role="manufacturing"><variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Department</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Specify the department the tooling item is associated
          with.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Capacity</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Specify the following capacity information:</para>

          <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Daily Capacity</term>

              <listitem>
                <para>Enter the daily capacity for the tooling item, measured
                in minutes.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
              <term>Efficiency Factor</term>

              <listitem>
                <para>Enter the efficiency factor for the tooling item,
                measured as a percentage.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
          </variablelist>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Average</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Specify the following averages:</para>

          <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Queue Days</term>

              <listitem>
                <para>Enter the tooling item's average number of queue
                days.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
              <term>Setup Time</term>

              <listitem>
                <para>Enter the setup time required for the tooling
                item.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
          </variablelist>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist></para>
</section>
