<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="item">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Enter New Item</title>
  <para>To enter a new item into your system, select the "Enter New Item"
  option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/item.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new item, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a number to uniquely identify the item. Duplicate item
        numbers will not be accepted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if item is active. Select this option if you intend to
        use the item within the application. If you don"t select this option,
        the item will be unavailable for use. To activate an inactive item,
        simply open the Item master and mark the item as active.</para>
        <note>
          <para>An inactive item may still be used in a sales order, work
          order, or purchase order if the item was de-activated after the
          order was created.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description #1</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The Item master features two description lines. The first line
        is typically used for entering the name used to describe the item. In
        printed reports or other printouts, the first line will appear on a
        separate line above the second line. However, the two lines will be
        concatenated (i.e., "joined together") when they are displayed
        on-screen within the application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description #2</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use the second description line to provide additional
        information about the item. The second line might include product,
        packaging, or any other descriptive information. In printed reports or
        other printouts, the second line will appear on a separate line below
        the first line. However, the two lines will be concatenated (i.e.,
        "joined together") when they are displayed on-screen within the
        application.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>Develop a logical, hierarchical numbering strategy before
          assigning numbers to your items. Using an hierarchical approach will
          greatly enhance your ability to display and search for information
          within the database. An hierarchical numbering scheme might look
          something like the following:</para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>MB-26-1</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>MB-26-2</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>MB-26-3</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          <para>In this case, similar items have been assigned sequential item
          numbers. By extension, similar categories of items may be identified
          by similar numbers.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item types</primary>
          <secondary>master list of</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>items</primary>
          <secondary>list of types</secondary>
        </indexterm>Item Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available item types:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>purchased</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>Purchased</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the item is an item you purchase. A purchase
              order is the normal supply order. However, you may enter a work
              order for this Item type.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry id="manufacturedItemType">
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>manufactured</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>job items</primary>
                <secondary>as manufactured items</secondary>
              </indexterm>Manufactured</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the item is an item you make. A work order is
              the normal supply order. However, you may also enter a purchase
              order for this Item type. Job items are considered to be
              manufactured items. Use the job costing option at the item site
              level to distinguish job items from regular manufactured items.
              For more information about the job costing option, please see
              <xref linkend="itemSiteJobItem" />.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>phantoms</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>Phantom</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>A transient subassembly containing component items
              commonly used together during a manufacturing process. Phantom
              items require a bill of materials, but not separate work orders.
              Since they are not stock items, material requirements planning
              (MRP) logic blows through phantom items and only plans for their
              component items. Phantom items should be used to simplify
              complex bills of materials.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>reference</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>Reference</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the item is an item you sell—but you neither
              manufacture nor purchase it. Services are an example of
              Reference item. The company sells consulting services, but it
              doesn't manufacture or purchase them. Reference items may be
              configured. This means you can add list prices to any Reference
              item characteristics. These characteristic prices are then added
              to the base price of sales order items when the characteristic
              is selected at sales order entry.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>costing</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>Costing</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>A kind of pseudo-item used solely to provide a costed
              value for a costing element. When a user-defined costing element
              is linked to a costing item, the costing element assumes the
              costs associated with the costing item. For more information,
              see <xref linkend="costingElements" />.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>tooling</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>Tooling</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>A material resource used in the manufacturing process that
              is returned upon completion of a work order—for example, a
              reusable mold, apparatus, fixture, or tool. It may be included
              on a bill of materials for an item, usually specifying a fixed
              quantity. Tooling items can be purchased, manufactured, or sold.
              A manufactured tool can have a routing, a BOM, and a work order. As
              with other material items, tools can be tracked as serialized
              items. The cost of a tooling item is not included in the overall
              cost of the parent item where it is used.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>outside processes</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>Outside Process</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the item is an external process or service that
              is performed by someone outside your company. Outside Process
              items are treated by the system in much the same way as
              purchased items are. For example, Outside Process items will be
              handled in the same way as purchased items are when material
              requirements planning (MRP) is run.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>planning</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>Planning</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>An item whose bill of materials (BOM) groups together
              other items so that a production Plan may be defined for the
              Planning item—and then exploded down to the lower level items
              during a Master production Scheduling (MPS) run. Planning items
              are frequently used to group together product families or
              product lines of MPS items. MPS items are typically top-level
              saleable items. By grouping together MPS items under a Planning
              item, the family may be forecasted through with a production
              Plan for the Planning item, thereby simplifying the planning
              process. The system automatically sets the Planning System as
              "MPS" by default when a Planning item is created.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>kits</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>Kit</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Kit items automatically explode their bill of material
              (BOM) components on to sales orders for shipping. When Kit items
              appear on sales orders and return authorizations, sub line
              numbers are generated for Kit components because Kit children
              are sub line items of the parent line item. Kit components are
              displayed as an indented tree on the sales order or return
              authorization—and they are view-only. Also, Kit components will
              appear on the pick list report. Kit components may be issued to
              shipping, whereas the parent Kit item may not be. The automatic
              "Select for Billing" option takes effect for kit items when all
              Kit items are shipped.</para>
              <note>
                <para>The cost of sales (COS) account for Kit items is
                directed to the sales account assignment mappings of the Kit's
                child items—unless your system is configured to have the Kit
                components inherit the same COS account used by the parent Kit
                item. You can read more about configuring your system for COS
                inheritance for Kit items here: <xref
                linkend="configureIM" />.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>breeder items</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>Breeder</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>A logical item from which Co-products and By-products are
              produced. An example use for a breeder item is the screening of
              raw gravel to produce different sizes of gravel. The breeder
              item's bill of materials (BOM) defines the inputs—in this case
              raw gravel—and the outputs are defined on its breeder BOM (i.e.,
              Small, Medium and Large gravel). A work order is created for the
              breeder item, but this item is never stocked or produced; again,
              it is a logical item. Instead, raw gravel is consumed by the
              breeder's work order, along with labor, and the resulting
              quantities of Co-products and By-products are recorded.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>co-products</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>Co-Product</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Co-products are items that you keep and which absorb
              costs. They are produced during a manufacturing process. See
              "Breeder" Item type above.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>by-products</primary>
                <secondary>as item type</secondary>
              </indexterm>By-Product</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>By-products are things that you throw away and incur costs
              doing so during a manufacturing process. See "Breeder" Item type
              above.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Maximum Desired Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is an optional field to be used for entering the maximum
        cost desired for the item. If used, you will be warned whenever
        entering purchase orders if the purchased cost exceeds the maximum
        desired cost value.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Class Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a class code to associate with the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>units of measure</primary>
          <secondary>at item level</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>pricing</primary>
          <secondary>item list price</secondary>
        </indexterm>Inventory UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the item's primary unit of measure—or enter a free-form
        UOM. The inventory (UOM) is the UOM in which inventory is maintained.
        All inventory transactions, sales transactions, and general ledger
        transactions reflect movement in inventory UOMs. The inventory UOM is
        also the base reference for all UOM conversion ratios.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Once transactions have been posted using an item's inventory
          UOM, you may no longer change the inventory UOM for the item.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pick List</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want the item to be included on pick lists when
        the item is used. Pick lists are printed lists showing the work order
        material requirements for a specified work order. You may decide not
        to include an item on pick lists if the item is insignificant or if it
        is not stored in a stock room but, for example, in a work center
        instead.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Fractional</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the item may be maintained in fractional quantities.
        If not selected, the system will assume the item is maintained in its
        inventory UOM, which is by definition a whole number. This means you
        may never use fractional quantities of the item (e.g., in
        manufacturing or purchasing) unless this option is selected.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>If you will ever use the item in fractional quantities, then
          the "Fractional" option must be selected. If it is not selected, the
          system will never let you use fractional quantities of the
          item.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Configured</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If the item is a Manufactured or Reference item, then you will
        have the option to configure the item for Assemble to order (ATO)
        scenarios. This option will be disabled for all other Item types. To
        learn more about product configuration, see our <ulink
        url="http://www.xtuple.org/AssembleToOrderConfigurator">ATO
        Configurator Topic</ulink>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight Class</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the freight class for the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bar Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Bar Code for the item.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Standard bar code formats supported by the system include the
          following: Code 3of9, Code 3of9 Extended, Code 128, UPC-A, UPC-E,
          EAN-8, EAN-13.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item is Sold</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the item is an item you sell. If not selected, the
        associated fields will be disabled.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Product Category</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the product category if the item is sold. All sold
              items must be assigned a product category.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>pricing</primary>
                <secondary>item list price</secondary>
              </indexterm>List Price</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the list price for the item, based on the selling
              UOM (i.e., "Per" UOM). List prices may also be created and
              modified in the item Pricing section of the <guimenu>Sales</guimenu> module.
              Changes made to the list price in either location will be
              updated system-wide.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>pricing</primary>
                <secondary>wholesale price</secondary>
              </indexterm>Wholesale Price</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the wholesale price for the item. The wholesale
              price may be used as the unit cost for markup purposes,
              depending on your pricing configuration. For more information,
              please see <xref linkend="WholesaleMarkup" />.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm>
                <primary>units of measure</primary>
                <secondary>selling specified</secondary>
              </indexterm>Unit Price UOM</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the selling unit of measure (UOM) for the item.
              The list price should be based on this selection. By default,
              the inventory UOM will be used here. You will not be able to
              select a different UOM until you first manually create a selling
              UOM using the options found under the <guimenuitem>UOM</guimenuitem> tab on the Item
              master.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>exclusive</primary>
                <secondary>item master control</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>items</primary>
                <secondary>exclusive for customers</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>customers</primary>
                <secondary>exclusive items for</secondary>
              </indexterm>Exclusive</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select if the item is sold exclusively. If a sold item is
              marked as Exclusive, it may only be sold to specified customers
              or customer types. To link Exclusive items to customers, you
              would first include the item on a pricing schedule—indicating
              relevant prices and quantity breaks. You would then assign the
              pricing schedule to specified customers or customer types, using
              the pricing schedule assignment functionality found in the item
              Pricing section of the <guimenu>Sales</guimenu> module.</para>
              <note>
                <para>Sold items can be configured as Exclusive by default at
                the system level.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Warranty</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If the item is sold with a warranty, specify the number of
              days the warranty extends for. The warranty period begins on the
              date the item is sold and ends on the specified number of days
              afterward. Setting this option to "0" days indicates the item
              does not come with a warranty.</para>
              <tip>
                <para>The sold warranty should not be confused with the
                purchased warranty, which is defined at the item site
                level.</para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Weight in LB</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter details related to the weight of the item, measured in
        pounds.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Product</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the pre-packaging weight of the product, in
              pounds.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Packaging</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the weight of the product packaging, in
              pounds.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Remarks</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter additional details related to the item.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Notes</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for
              entering notes related to the item. Any notes entered on this
              screen are for internal purposes only.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Extended Description</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Extended Description field is for entering descriptive
              item information, which may be printed on sales and/or
              purchasing documents. You would add the Extended Description to
              printed documents using the report writer. The report writer
              enables you to customize forms to include data stored in the
              database. To enter an Extended Description of an item, select
              the "Extended Description" option.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Comments</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>To view system-generated comments associated with an
              item—or to add new and edit comments of your own—select the
              "Comments" option.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>MATERIALS</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to open the bill of materials (BOM) for the specified
        item. If no BOM exists, you will have the option to create a new
        routing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term><guibutton>ROUTING</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to open the routing for the specified item. If no routing
        exists, you will have the option to create a new routing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>WORKBENCH</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to open the Item Availability Workbench for the specified
        item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Item characteristics are user-defined definitions of an item which may
  be used to provide additional layers of description to items. For example,
  item characteristics might be used to specify "Season" or "Primary Vendor".
  These constitute static descriptions which are not processed by the
  application, but are useful for informational purposes. For configured items
  (i.e., job or Reference items), characteristics are used to store pricing
  information for the options available on configured items. That pricing by
  characteristic is then passed to sales order line items when particular
  configurations are sold.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>Item characteristics can be associated with sales order, purchase
    order, and work order items.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To enter <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>characteristics</primary>
      <secondary>creating new for item</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>characteristics</primary>
      <secondary>items having</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>
      <secondary>characteristics for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Characteristics associated with an item, select the
  <guimenuitem>Characteristics</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/item_characteristicsTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Item Characteristics</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para id="configItemChar"><tip>
      <para>For configured items, an additional pricing field will be
      available on the item Characteristic screen. This pricing information
      will be passed to sales order line items when particular configurations
      are sold. The price for configured items may vary depending on the
      characteristics selected at sales order entry time.</para>
    </tip></para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/characteristic.xml"
              xpointer="characteristiclWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
  <para>For visibility into costs and bill of materials associated with
  items—and to perform routine cost and BOM maintenance—select the <guimenuitem>Cost</guimenuitem> tab.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/item_costTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Item Cost</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>You are presenting with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Elements</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this option to maintain item cost elements. For more
        information on maintaining item costs, please see <xref
        linkend="maintainItemCosts" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Materials</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this option to maintain the bill of materials. For more
        detailed information on maintaining bills of materials, please see
        <xref linkend="boms" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>In addition to the inventory unit of measure (UOM), which is defined
  on the Item master, you also have the option to convert UOMs for an item.
  The following alternate UOMs may be defined:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Alternate Capacity</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Capacity</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Material Issue</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Selling</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>Unless you define an alternate UOM, an item will always be stored and
  used in its inventory UOM. For example, you must define a selling UOM if you
  want to enable an item to be sold in a UOM other than the inventory UOM. To
  enter <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>units of measure</primary>
      <secondary>associating with items</secondary>
    </indexterm> Units of measure associated with an item, select the
  <guimenuitem>Conversions</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/item_tabUOM.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Item Conversions</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Conversions/Where Used</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists the UOM Conversions defined for the item (if any)
        and where these conversions are used. Global conversion ratios are
        defined in <xref linkend="uomConv" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>units of measure</primary>
      <secondary>alternates for items</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>
      <secondary>alternate uoms for</secondary>
    </indexterm>To define an alternate item UOM, select the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/itemUOM.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Unit of Measure Definition</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When defining an alternate item UOM, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <tip>
    <para>By default, the Available types list will be empty—until you specify
    either a source or per UOM. Once a source or per UOM is selected, the
    Available types list will be populated with the available options. An item
    may have multiple selling UOMs but only one of each of the other
    types.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Source UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default the inventory UOM will be displayed here. However,
        you may select an alternate UOM. If an alternate UOM is selected, then
        the per UOM will be the inventory UOM.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Value</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter a value for the source UOM to be used in the
              conversion ratio for the alternate item UOM.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Per UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default the inventory UOM will be displayed here. However,
        you may select an alternate UOM. If an alternate UOM is selected, then
        the Source UOM will be the inventory UOM.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Value</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter a value for the per UOM to be used in the conversion
              ratio for the alternate item UOM.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Fractional</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify whether this alternate item UOM may be maintained in
        fractional quantities. If not selected, transaction quantities using
        this alternate item UOM may not be maintained in fractional
        quantities.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify whether the conversion is active or not.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Available Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Once a source or per UOM has been specified, you may select one
        of the available UOM types. Once a UOM type has been used, you may not
        create a conversion ratio for it again—with the exception of the
        selling UOM, which may be defined multiple times for a single
        item.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>Double-clicking on an available UOM type will move it to the
          Selected types list.</para>
        </tip>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Alternate Capacity</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The Alt. Capacity UOM should be used to provide an
              alternate UOM for viewing inventory details. For example, a
              sales manager may be satisfied looking at a group of items
              normalized to their selling or inventory UOM, but a production
              Manager may need to look at the same items normalized to a
              production UOM—say, Cubic Feet (CuFt).</para>
              <note>
                <para>The Alternate Capacity UOM has no impact on bills of
                materials. It is used solely for Capacity Planning and sales
                analysis purposes.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Capacity</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>In Capacity Planning and sales Analysis reports, the
              Capacity UOM enables you to make apples-to-apples comparisons of
              items that use different inventory UOMs. For example, let's say
              that item A is a carton containing 24 item B"s—and that you sell
              both items. However, item A and item B use different inventory
              UOMs. item A is measured by the CASE (24), and item B is
              measured by EACH. By utilizing the Capacity UOM, you have the
              ability to track total load and total sales for item B—even
              though the inventory UOM for item A obscures the quantity of
              item B's contained therein. If, when you query the database, you
              request data to be displayed in Capacity UOMs, then the system
              will normalize the quantities of item A to EACH, allowing you to
              see the total quantity of item Bs.</para>
              <note>
                <para>The Capacity UOM has no impact on bills of materials. It
                is used solely for Capacity Planning and sales analysis
                purposes.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Material Issue</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The material issue UOM defines an alternate UOM for use
              when creating bill of materials (BOM) items. On the BOM item
              screen, you have the ability to select an issue UOM. This issue
              UOM is used whenever the specified component item is issued to a
              work order. If you define a material issue UOM on the Item
              master, then that UOM will be available for selection whenever
              the item is used in a BOM.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm>
                <primary>units of measure</primary>
                <secondary>selling specified</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm>
                <primary>items</primary>
                <secondary>selling UOM for</secondary>
              </indexterm>Selling</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If an item is sold, its list price will be based on the
              Selling UOM. While the Selling UOM may often mirror the
              inventory UOM, in some scenarios the two UOMs will be different.
              For example, cans of soda may be stocked in inventory as
              individual units (EACH), but sold by the case (CASE24). In this
              example, inventory transactions will be recorded using the
              inventory UOM (EACH), but all pricing—including list price and
              pricing schedules—will reflect the Selling UOM (CASE24). An item
              may also have multiple Selling UOMs, for example SIX-PACK,
              CASE24, PALLET, etc. You specify the Selling UOM you want to use
              at sales order entry time.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Lists the UOM types you have selected for the specified UOM
        conversion ratio. You may add multiple different UOM types for each
        conversion ratio. However, if a UOM type (except the Selling UOM) has
        already been used in another conversion ratio, you may not be able to
        select it.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>Double-clicking on a selected UOM type will remove it from the
          list, returning it to the Available types list.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view, add, or edit item sites associated with an item, select the
  <guimenuitem>Sites</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/item_itemsitesTab.png" remap="" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Item Sites for the Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Sites</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists item sites for the specified item. For more
        information, see <xref linkend="itemSite" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view the vendor item sources for an item select the <guimenuitem>Sources</guimenuitem>
  tab.</para>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="images/item_sourcesTab.png" remap="" />
    </imageobject>
    <caption>Sources for the Item</caption>
  </mediaobject>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sources</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays list of item sources and associated vendors. You may
        also add new item sources for an item on this screen. For additional
        documentation related to setting up item sources for an item, see
        <xref linkend="itemSource" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The tax policy for an item is determined by how its tax type settings
  are configured. To associate tax types with an item, select the <guimenuitem>Tax Types</guimenuitem>
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/item_taxtypesTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Item Tax Types</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>To mark an item as non-taxable, simply do not associate any tax
    types with the item.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists tax types for the specified item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new tax type definition, select the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemtax.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Tax Type</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new tax type definition, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax zones</primary>
          <secondary>for sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm>Tax Zone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the tax zone you want to associate with the specified
        tax type. Creating a relationship between a tax zone and a tax type
        enables you to determine how tax will be applied when processing
        transactions using the item. If you select the "Any" option, this
        means any defined tax zone is a possible match.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>Consider creating separate tax types for any groups or classes of
    items which are taxed at different rates.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the tax type you want to associate with the specified
        tax zone. Tax types provide a system for classifying goods and
        services into taxable categories. Creating a relationship between a
        tax zone and a tax type enables you to determine how tax will be
        applied when processing transactions using the item. If you select the
        "Any" option, this means any defined tax type is a possible
        match.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>item relationships</primary>
      <secondary>for cross-referencing</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>
      <secondary>relationships for</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>relationships</primary>
      <see>item aliases</see>
    </indexterm>Item Relationships are assigned to items as a means for
  cross-referencing internal and external item information. For example, a
  customer may refer to an item by a different item number than you do. To
  avoid confusion—and to simplify item lookups—you can create an item alias
  linking the customer's external Part number to your own internal item
  number. The item alias acts as an alternate identifier. In this way, items
  may be located using either internal or external item information. To
  associate an item alias with an item, select the <guimenuitem>Relationships</guimenuitem> tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/item_relationshipsTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Item Relationships</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When associating alias relationships with an item, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Alias</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists item alias numbers and related comments.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>Multiple item aliases can be assigned to a single item,
          allowing you to cross-reference an item using many different item
          numbers.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create an item alias, select the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemAlias.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Item Alias</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new item alias, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Item number entered into previous screen will be
        displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Alias Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is the alias number for the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Associated Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>You have the option to link a CRM account to the item alias. If
        linked, the alias will only be used on quotes and sales orders related
        to the specified customer. If no customer is specified, the alias will
        be displayed for all customers you sell the item to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item aliases</primary>
          <secondary>related to billing</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item aliases</primary>
          <secondary>related to shipping</secondary>
        </indexterm>Use an Alias Description on Billing and Shipping
      Paperwork</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include an item alias
        description on billing and shipping paperwork.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description of the item alias for inclusion on billing
        and shipping paperwork.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        comments related to the item alias. This field may be useful for
        explaining why an item alias was created (e.g., "customer XYZ, Inc.
        refers to this item alias whenever they place an order.").</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To associate item Substitutes with an item, select the "Substitutes"
  button. The following options will appear:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Substitutes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para><indexterm significance="normal">
            <primary>items</primary>
            <secondary>substitutes for</secondary>
          </indexterm>Display lists item Substitutes, including rank and item
        description.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>Multiple item Substitutes can be assigned to a single item,
          allowing you to cross-reference an item using many different item
          numbers.</para>
        </tip>
        <note>
          <para>There is a difference between item Substitutes and
          Substitutions defined in a bill of materials (BOM). The difference
          is that BOM-defined Substitutions may be implemented on the fly
          during work order processing—item Substitutes cannot be.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new item Substitute, select the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/itemSubstitute.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Item Substitute</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new item Substitute, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number (Root Item)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Item number entered into previous screen will be
        displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number (Substitution)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the Substitute item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Substitute/Parent UOM Ratio</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specifies the ratio between the root item's inventory UOM and
        the Substitute item's inventory UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>item substitutes</primary>
          <secondary>ranking of</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>ranking</primary>
          <secondary>of item substitutes</secondary>
        </indexterm>Ranking</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
        value up to a maximum of 9 to specify the rank of the item Substitute.
        The ranking determines the order in which the item Substitute will
        appear in the Substitute list accessed from the Maintain Work Order
        Materials screen. The item Substitute having the highest rank will
        appear at the top of list, and so on in descending order. You may
        assign the same ranking to multiple items, if this is
        appropriate.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para role="standard">To associate Transformation options for an item,
  select the "Transformations" button. The following options will
  appear:</para>
  <para role="standard"><variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Transformations</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>Display lists items which may be chosen as target items during
          Transformation transactions.</para>
          <note>
            <para>You may only transform an item if the source item is located
            in the same site as the target item.</para>
          </note>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist></para>
  <para>To <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>item documents</primary>
      <secondary>associate with items</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>documents</primary>
      <secondary>items associated with</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>
      <secondary>documents associated with</secondary>
    </indexterm>associate documents with an item, select the <guimenuitem>Documents</guimenuitem> tab.
  The following screen will appear:<mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/item_documentsTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Item Documents</para></caption>
    </mediaobject></para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/documents.xml" xpointer="documentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
