<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section>
  <title>Ledger Control</title>

  <para>The ledger control report is designed to help you validate your
  accounting during the month-end closing process. The report provides a
  summarized overview of the key ledger control points, comparing the
  difference between ledger and sub ledger amounts. This information can help
  you identify (at a high level) areas in the accounting system that require
  further investigation. To learn more about how to use the ledger control
  report as a starting point for further action, please see the <ulink
  url="https://xtupleuniversity.xtuple.com/library/articles/validating-your-ledger-accounts">Validating
  your ledger control accounts</ulink> article.</para>

  <para>To access the ledger control report, go to <guimenuitem>Accounting
  &gt; General Ledger &gt; Reports &gt; Ledger Control</guimenuitem>. The
  following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/ledgerControl.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Ledger Control report</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>As you can see in the screenshot, the report groups the ledger control
  points into six core categories:</para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Payables</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Uninvoiced receipts</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Receivables</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Inventory</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>WIP</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>Shipping assets</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para>Within each category, the report shows the difference between
  summarized ledger and sub ledger activity. The goal, of course, is to show a
  difference of $0 for each category. If the difference does not equal to $0,
  that means you have work to do analyzing the reason(s) for the difference
  and taking action to correct it. Keep in mind that these figures are
  summarized. In most, if not all, cases, the information shown is drawn from
  multiple accounts and document types.</para>
</section>
