<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="listPricingSchedule">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>list pricing schedules</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>List Pricing Schedule</title>
  <para>A single List Pricing Schedule may contain multiple items or Product
  Categories—and multiple Quantity Breaks. To create a new List Pricing
  Schedule, select the NEW button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/listPricingSchedule.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New List Pricing Schedule</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>When sales orders are entered, the system will search for Quantity
    Break matches between the sales order item and the relevant List Pricing
    Schedule. If duplicate Quantity Breaks are found, the lowest price for the
    given quantity will be used.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new List Pricing Schedule, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the name of the List Pricing Schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description to identify the List Pricing
        Schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Effective</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the date when the List Pricing Schedule becomes
        effective.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The effectivity and expiration dates for List Pricing
          Schedules correspond to the created date for sales orders. Changes
          to line item quantities or scheduled dates for already-created sales
          orders can also cause List Pricing Schedule effectivity to be
          recalculated as of the date the changes occur.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expires</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the date when the List Pricing Schedule expires.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Schedule</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists all sold items or product categories assigned to
        this List Pricing Schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Currency</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the currency.<note>
            <para>This field is only enabled when multiple currencies are
            used.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Calculate Net Price using Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the site to be used for calculating net price when
        average cost is used as the markup basis.<note>
            <para>List Pricing Schedules are not updated by site. The site
            indicated here is only used for calculating the net price.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="listPricingScheduleItem.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
