<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="listPricingSchedules">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>list pricing schedules</primary>

      <secondary>master list of</secondary>
    </indexterm>List Pricing Schedules</title>

  <para>A list pricing schedule is used to modify the standard list price for
  an item, creating an alternate list price. List pricing schedules may be
  assigned to individual customers or to groups of customers by customer type.
  To learn more about how alternate list pricing works, please see the <ulink
  url="https://xtupleuniversity.xtuple.com/library/articles/alternate-list-pricing">Alternate
  List Pricing article</ulink> at xTupleU.</para>

  <para>To access the master list of list pricing schedules, select the
  <guimenuitem>List Pricing Schedules</guimenuitem> option. The following
  screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/listPricingSchedules.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>List Pricing Schedules Master List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>At the top of the screen is a <guilabel>Search for</guilabel> field.
  To search for a list pricing schedule, begin typing in the search field. As
  you type, the list will automatically scroll toward the list pricing
  schedule you are typing. You can also search for list pricing schedules
  manually by scrolling through the list. The following filters can also be
  applied to your search:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Expired Pricing Schedules</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display expired list pricing schedules.</para>

        <note>
          <para>The effectivity and expiration dates for list pricing
          schedules correspond to the created date for sales orders. Changes
          to line item quantities or scheduled dates for already-created sales
          orders can also cause list pricing schedule effectivity to be
          recalculated as of the date the changes occur.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Future Pricing Schedules</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display future list pricing schedules.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Pricing Schedules</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists item pricing schedules.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>DELETE EXPIRED</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to delete expired list pricing schedules.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <xi:include href="listPricingSchedule.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
