<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="listPricingScheduleItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>list pricing schedules</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>List Pricing Schedule Item</title>
  <para>To create a new List Pricing Schedule item, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/listPricingScheduleItem.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>List Pricing Schedule for Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new List Pricing Schedule item, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which type of List Pricing Schedule item you want to
        create: Nominal, Discount, or Freight. The screen will present
        different options depending on which type option you select.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Select the "Nominal" option for simple quantity break pricing by item.
  When the "Nominal" option is selected, you will be presented with the
  following choices:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the item you want to add to the List
        Pricing Schedule. The lookup feature located to the right of the field
        leads to a searchable sold items list. Multiple sold items may be
        assigned to a single List Pricing Schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quantity breaks</primary>
          <secondary>in list pricing schedules</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>list pricing schedules</primary>
          <secondary>quantity breaks in</secondary>
        </indexterm>Qty. Break</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the lowest quantity of the specified item that must be
        purchased to receive the specified Price. The Quantity Break is
        measured in the inventory Unit of Measure. Multiple Quantity Breaks
        may be assigned to a single item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>list pricing schedules</primary>
          <secondary>pricing detail for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Price the specified item may be purchased for if the
        specified Quantity Break is met. The Price is measured in the Price
        Unit of Measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item List Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the List Price for the specified item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Unit of Measure (UOM) to be used when selling the
        line item. Sold items may be assigned multiple Selling UOMs. These
        alternate UOMs may be defined on the Item master. You may also select
        a global conversion ratio here. Global conversions have the label
        <literal>Global</literal> appended to them. If a line item has no
        Selling UOM defined, then the inventory UOM will be used here by
        default.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>When using a Selling UOM for the Quantity Break, you may not
          select an alternate Price UOM. The reason for this is that selling
          UOMs use the same UOM for both quantity and pricing.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Price UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Price Unit of Measure to be used with the specified
        Quantity Break UOM. If you select a Selling UOM for the Qty. UOM, you
        will not be able to select a Price UOM. For Selling UOMs, the Selling
        UOM and the Price UOM are the same.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Price/Inv. Ratio</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the ratio between the Price and inventory Units of
        Measure for the specified item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cost (Pricing UOM)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays Standard Cost and Actual Cost for the specified
        item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Margin</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The margin is determined by the following formula: Price - Cost
        / Price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>list pricing schedules</primary>
      <secondary>configured item pricing and</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>configuration</primary>
      <secondary>pricing for</secondary>
    </indexterm>If the specified item is a configured item, then the
  "Characteristics" tab will be available. Characteristics for configured
  items can carry their own List Prices. These Characteristic Prices may be
  added to the Base Price when configured items are sold. To define
  Characteristic pricing for configured items, select the "Characteristics"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/listPricingScheduleItem_configuredPrices.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Configured Item Pricing</caption>
    </mediaobject></para>
  <para>When defining Characteristic pricing for configured items, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Characteristic</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>List displays all the Characteristic Prices which have been
        associated with the List Pricing Schedule item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add a new Characteristic pricing item, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/characteristicPrice.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Characteristic Pricing</caption>
    </mediaobject></para>
  <para>When adding a new Characteristic pricing item, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Characteristic</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a Characteristic from the list of item Characteristics
        defined for the specified item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Value</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a Value from the list of Values defined for the specified
        item Characteristic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a new Price for the Characteristic and Value combination.
        This alternate Price will be used in place of the standard
        Characteristic List Price when the List Pricing Schedule is
        used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>List Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the default List Price for the item Characteristic. The
        List Price for Characteristics is added to the Base Price of Sales
        Order items when the Characteristic is specified at Sales Order entry
        time. List Pricing Schedules are designed to override standard List
        Prices.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Select the "Discount" option for fixed amount or percentage based
  discount pricing by item. For List Pricing Schedules, only discounting by
  item is available. Discounting by Product Category is not available for List
  Pricing Schedules. To enter discounts by item, select the "Item" option. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/listPricingScheduleItem_discountSelected_item.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Item Discounts</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When discounting by item, you will be presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the item you want to add to the List Pricing
        Schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quantity breaks</primary>
          <secondary>in list pricing schedules</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>list pricing schedules</primary>
          <secondary>quantity breaks in</secondary>
        </indexterm>Qty. Break (Inventory UOM)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the lowest quantity that must be purchased to receive the
        specified Discount.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>list pricing schedules</primary>
          <secondary>discount percentage for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Discount Percent (List Price)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Discount percentage off List Price to be used when the
        specified Quantity Break is reached.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount By Fixed Amount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the fixed amount you want to be discounted off the List
        Price. If a Discount percentage is also used, the fixed amount will be
        subtracted after the Discount percentage. However, the Price can never
        go below zero.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Select the "Markup" option to calculate the Price as a markup on the
  Wholesale Price.</para>
  <para><mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/listPricingScheduleItem_markupSelected.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Markup</caption>
    </mediaobject></para>
  <para>When the "Markup" option is selected, you will be presented with the
  following choices:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Markup By</term>
      <listitem>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select this option if the Markup depends on the item that
              is selected. You will be prompted for the item number.</para>
              <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Item Number</term>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Enter the item number this List Pricing Schedule
                    item will be applied to.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Product Category</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Markup by Product Category is not available for List
              Pricing Schedules.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Break (Inventory UOM)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the lowest quantity that must be purchased for the
        specified Markup to be applied.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Markup Percent (Inventory Cost)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Markup Percent that needs to be added to the inventory
        Cost.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Markup By Fixed Amount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Fixed Amount the inventory Cost will be increased
        by.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The inventory Cost will be increased with the sum of the Markup
    Percent and the Fixed Amount.</para>
  </note>
</section>
