<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="maintainBudget">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>budgets</primary>

      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>New Budget</title>

  <para>The Budget utility is designed to store budgetary information, by
  account number, in a table format. Once stored, this information may then be
  accessed and viewed using the financial report engine. The financial
  reporting engine specifically includes options for generating reports
  showing budget information. To access the Budget utility, go to
  <guimenuitem>Accounting &gt; Budget &gt; New Budget</guimenuitem>. The
  following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/maintainBudget.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Maintain Budget</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <note>
    <para>While all budget amounts entered in the generated table are stored
    in the database, the particular groupings of accounts and accounting
    periods are used only during the current session. If you want to
    re-generate a particular budget table, the accounts and accounting periods
    must be manually entered again.</para>
  </note>

  <para>When creating or maintaining budget information, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name to identify the budget.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a brief line to describe the budget.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>If your system is configured to use projects, select a project
        number to associate with the budget.</para>

        <para role="xtprjaccnt">When you have the xTuple Project Accounting
        package installed—and you link a project to the budget—the project
        number will be added as the final segment of all G/L account numbers
        used by the budget.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Table Parameters</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select from the following options to determine which accounts
        and accounting periods you want to enter budgetary information
        for:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Accounts</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select one or multiple accounts to include when generating
              a budget table.</para>

              <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term><guibutton>ADD</guibutton></term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select to add accounts from your chart of
                    accounts.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry>
                  <term><guibutton>REMOVE</guibutton></term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Highlight an account and then select this button to
                    remove the account from the list.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Accounting Periods</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Using your mouse in conjunction with the
              <guibutton>SHIFT</guibutton> and/or <guibutton>CRTL</guibutton>
              keys, select one or multiple accounting periods to include when
              generating the budget table.</para>

              <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term><guibutton>SELECT ALL</guibutton></term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select to include all accounting periods in the
                    table.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry>
                  <term><guibutton>INVERT</guibutton></term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Selecting this option will cause the inverse of any
                    selected accounting periods to be selected.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry>
                  <term><guibutton>UNSELECT ALL</guibutton></term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select to de-select all accounting periods.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry>
                  <term><guibutton>GENERATE TABLE</guibutton></term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select to generate the budget table using the
                    specified parameters.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Table</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter budget amounts in the fields provided. The table will
        consist of a grid, showing the specified account numbers listed down
        the left side—and the indicated accounting periods across the top.
        Simply click in a field to begin entering or editing budget
        information. The <guibutton>TAB</guibutton> key may be used to move
        from field to field. Any budget information you save in the table will
        be stored in the database for future reference. You may view budget
        information by account and accounting period using the financial
        reporting engine. You may also edit budget information by regenerating
        a budget table.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
