<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="miscVoucherMiscDistrib">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>vouchers</primary>
      <secondary>miscellaneous distributions for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Voucher Misc. Distribution</title>
  <para>In addition to line item specific distributions, you may also enter
  miscellaneous distributions to affect the voucher as a whole. To enter a
  miscellaneous distribution, select the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button
  from the main Voucher screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/miscVoucherMiscDistrib.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Miscellaneous Voucher Distribution</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When entering a miscellaneous voucher distribution, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to use a general ledger account for the
        distribution.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="xtprjaccnt">
      <term>Project</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to associate a project with the transaction.
        The project number will be added as the final segment of the G/L
        account number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expense Category</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to use an expense category for the
        distribution.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight Distribution</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to distribute line item freight charges to an
        already-posted voucher.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Original Voucher</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the number of the original voucher you want to
              distribute line item freight charges to.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Cost Element</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the costing element you want to distribute freight
              charges to. If you have defined a default cost element for
              freight under <guimenuitem>Products &gt; Setup &gt;
              Configure</guimenuitem>, then that element will be displayed
              here.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Method</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select one of the following methods to determine how you
              want the freight charges to be distributed among the original
              voucher's line items:</para>
              <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Quantity</term>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>The quantity to distribute for a given line will be
                    divided by the total quantity for all lines. This
                    fractional quantity is then multiplied by the amount
                    entered in the <guilabel>Freight</guilabel> field. The
                    corresponding result for each line is then distributed to
                    the specified costing element.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Value</term>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>The total value to distribute for a given line will
                    be divided by the total value for all lines. This
                    fractional value is then multiplied by the amount entered
                    in the <guilabel>Freight</guilabel> field. The
                    corresponding result for each line is distributed to the
                    specified costing element.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Weight</term>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>The product weight (as defined in the Item master)
                    will be multiplied by the quantity to distribute for a
                    given line. That total line item weight is then divided by
                    the total weight for all lines. This fractional weight is
                    then multiplied by the amount entered in the
                    <guilabel>Freight</guilabel> field. The corresponding
                    result for each line is distributed to the specified
                    costing element.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a tax code to use for the distribution. When using this
        option, the distribution amount will be charged to the general ledger
        account associated with the tax code. To have tax calculated
        automatically for the distribution, use the <guimenuitem>Tax
        Type</guimenuitem> option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a tax type to associate with the distribution. Tax will
        be calculated automatically if a tax assignment matches both the tax
        type and the specified tax zone.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Amount to Distribute</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the amount of the miscellaneous distribution. If there
        is a balance still to be distributed once all voucher items have been
        distributed, then that remaining amount will be entered here by
        default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discountable</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the voucher item is entitled to a terms discount. This
        option may be used on a line-by-line basis—all within one voucher. For
        example, purchased items may be discountable; however, freight charges
        may not be. When selecting a voucher for payment within the discount
        period, only discountable items will be discounted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general notes related to the voucher. These notes are for internal use
        only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
