<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="miscCheck">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>payments</primary>

      <secondary>creating miscellaneous</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>miscellaneous payments</primary>

      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Miscellaneous Payment</title>

  <para>For payments related to non-inventory goods or services, you have the
  ability to create miscellaneous payments. You can write payments to vendors,
  customers, or tax authorities. To create a miscellaneous payment, select the
  <guimenuitem>Miscellaneous Payment</guimenuitem> option. The following
  screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/miscCheck.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Miscellaneous Payment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating a miscellaneous payment, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Write Payment To</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which type of recipient you want to write the
        miscellaneous payment to. Your options will vary depending on which
        type you select.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Vendor</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want to write a payment to a vendor. Once
              selected, you must also specify the vendor.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Customer</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want to write a payment to a customer. Once
              selected, you must also specify the customer.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Tax Authority</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select if you want to write a payment to a tax authority.
              Once selected, you must also specify the tax authority.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Charge To:</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify how you want to handle the accounting for the
        miscellaneous payment. Your options will vary depending on the
        recipient type you choose.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Expense Category</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the expense category you want to distribute the
              payment to. This option is available for all recipient
              types.</para>

              <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Tax Zone</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Displays the tax zone associated with the specified
                    vendor or customer.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Tax Type</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select a tax type to indicate you want to calculate
                    tax for the payment. Tax will be calculated automatically
                    if a tax assignment matches both the tax type and the
                    specified tax zone. By not selecting a tax type, you can
                    avoid calculating tax.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Tax</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Displays the amount of calculated tax, if
                    any.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Apply to Credit Memo</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>This option is available only for payments to customers.
              If selected, you can choose a credit memo from the customer's
              open balance. Then, when the miscellaneous payment is posted,
              the open credit memo will automatically be closed. Use this
              feature for paying off and closing open customer
              balances.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Create Credit Memo</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>This option is available only for payments to vendors.
              Once the miscellaneous payment is posted, a credit memo in the
              payment amount will be created. This credit memo will offset
              your accounts payable for the specified vendor. You would use
              this option, for example, to handle prepayments made to
              vendors.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Create Debit Memo</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>This option is available only for payments to customers.
              You would use this in the case where you lent a customer money,
              with the expectation of billing them later.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date to appear on the miscellaneous payment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Amount</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the amount of the miscellaneous payment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Memo</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a memo line to be included on the bottom portion of the
        printed miscellaneous payment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bank Account</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the bank account you want to use for the miscellaneous
        payment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        notes related to the miscellaneous payment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CREATE</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the miscellaneous payment, using the specified
        parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
