<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="openVouchers">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>vouchers</primary>

      <secondary>list of unposted</secondary>
    </indexterm>Unposted Vouchers</title>

  <para>Vouchers may be posted individually or in groups using the Unposted
  Vouchers screen. After they are posted, open vouchers may later be voided
  using the right-click menu on the Vendor History screen. To display unposted
  vouchers, select the List Unposted Vouchers option. The following screen
  will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/openVouchers.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>List Unposted Vouchers</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <note>
    <para>Actual costs for purchased items will be automatically updated when
    vouchers are posted if there are differences between current actual costs
    and the vouchered costs for the items in question. Please keep in mind
    that actual costs only will be updated at posting. For new costs to be
    recognized as standard costs, actual costs must be posted to
    standard.</para>
  </note>

  <para>The Vouchers screen displays information on all unposted vouchers,
  including voucher number, purchase order number, vendor number/vendor name,
  vendor invoice number, and distribution date. Users with the appropriate
  privilege will also see the G/L distribution date column.</para>

  <tip>
    <para>You may select multiple vouchers for posting by highlighting them
    using your mouse—or a combination of your mouse and either the shift or
    ctrl keys.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW MISC.</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Opens screen for creating a new miscellaneous voucher.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
    <para>If you have a purchase order voucher that was corrupted by, for
    example, a sudden power outage, you can clear the record by running the
    Post Vouchers screen. In most cases, this action will remove the corrupted
    record and allow you to voucher the purchase order with a fresh
    voucher.</para>
  </tip>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>POST</term>

      <listitem id="openVouchersPOST">
        <para>Highlight one—or multiple—vouchers, then select this button to
        post the selected voucher(s). By default, vouchers post to the general
        ledger (G/L) on their distribution date. However, users with the
        appropriate privilege may change the G/L distribution date to an
        alternate date during the voucher posting process. If used, vouchers
        will post on the alternate date. The ability privileged users have to
        change the distribution date applies to the posting of both individual
        and also batches of vouchers from this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Print Journal</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to print the G/L series journal in addition to posting
        the vouchers.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
