<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="plannedSchedule">
  <title>New Production Plan</title>

  <para>Production plans are used for loading sales forecasts into the system.
  These forecasts are then accounted for when the master production scheduling
  (MPS) system is run. Firm planned orders may be created for items listed on
  production plans as the result of an MPS run. To create a new production
  plan, go to <guimenuitem>Schedule &gt; Production Plan &gt;
  New</guimenuitem>. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/plannedSchedule.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Create new Production Plan</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating a new production plan you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Schedule #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name to identify the production plan.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a brief description of the production plan.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the site where the forecasted quantity would be located.
        By specifying a site you indicate the specific item site which the MPS
        planning system should create planned orders for, if required.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Schedule Type</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the available production plan schedule
        types:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>mps</primary>

                <secondary>forecast reporting and</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>forecast</primary>

                <secondary>reporting for mps</secondary>
              </indexterm>Forecast Reporting</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Planning items having this schedule type are not taken
              into account by MPS. Instead, use this schedule type for
              reporting purposes only, such as the reporting found on the MPS
              Detail screen. Forecast reporting can be useful as a reference
              of progress against cumulative MPS schedules, usually in
              scenarios where demand is discontinuous or
              <emphasis>lumpy</emphasis>, but production schedules are
              continuous.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Forecast Netted to MPS</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Used for forecast reporting and netted as demand to
              existing supply by the MPS processor for items scheduled inside
              the demand time fence. Use where you desire supply to
              automatically be created to fulfill, but not exceed, the greater
              of forecasted and actual demand. Inside the demand time fence,
              MPS ignores the forecast and plans an amount based on actual
              demand net of projected availability. Outside of the demand time
              fence, MPS uses the larger of actual demand or the forecast and
              nets this against projected availability.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>mps</primary>

                <secondary>cumulative schedules and</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>cumulative schedules</primary>

                <secondary>explained</secondary>
              </indexterm>Cumulative MPS</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Cumulative schedules allow the forced accumulation of
              inventory in a discontinuous or lumpy demand situation where
              load leveling or continuous production is desired. With this
              setting, MPS may release more, but never less, than the quantity
              dictated in a cumulative MPS schedule. Inside the demand time
              fence, cumulative schedules are ignored—and only actual demand
              is considered. Outside the demand time fence, planned orders for
              cumulative schedules are created per the greater of schedule
              quantity or net actual demand. The system interprets
              <emphasis>net actual demand</emphasis> to mean that it will use,
              for a given period, the larger of A) cumulative schedule
              quantity or B) quantity required to accommodate time-phased
              availability (i.e., QOH + qty. on order - allocations).</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Status</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the current status of the production plan.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>Production plans may exist in either of the following two
    statuses:</para>

    <para>U = un-released</para>

    <para>R = released</para>

    <para>The master production scheduling (MPS) system will only consider
    production plans which have been released. Any un-released production
    plans will be ignored by MPS when it is run.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Start Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the first date when MPS items may be added to the
        production plan. Items having a planned date earlier than the date
        entered here may not be added to the production plan.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>End Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the last date when MPS items may be added to the
        production plan. Items having a planned date later than the date
        entered here may not be added to the production plan.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Planned Items</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the current list of planned items associated with the
        production plan.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>CHG. STATUS</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Use this button to toggle between the active and inactive status
        for the selected planned item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <xi:include href="plannedScheduleItem.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
