<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="postCostsByItem">
  <title><indexterm>
      <primary>actual costs</primary>
      <secondary>posting to standard by item</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm>
      <primary>items</primary>
      <secondary>posting actual costs to standard for</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm>
      <primary>costing</primary>
      <secondary>posting actual to standard</secondary>
    </indexterm>Post Actual Costs by Item</title>
  <para id="Para627665">When you post actual costs you are replacing your
  existing standard costs with your newer actual costs. The standard cost of
  an item is the cost used for posting general ledger transactions. Standard
  cost is distinguished from actual cost in the sense that standard cost is
  fixed, whereas actual cost is subject to fluctuations arising from material
  or production changes. For example, the actual costs for purchased items may
  be updated whenever vouchers are posted for those items. Because Standard
  and actual costs may diverge, posting actual costs to standard is the way
  you bring the two costs into alignment.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>Cost roll ups in xTuple are performed from the bottom up. In other
    words, to update the costs for a parent item you need to roll the costs
    for all the child items up into the parent item. For this reason, posting
    costs by class code is the generally preferred method. That way you can
    guarantee all the required costs are posted&mdash;and none are
    missed.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To post actual costs to standard cost individually by item, select the
  "Post Actual Costs by Item" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para id="Para519903"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/postCostsByItem.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Post Actual Costs by Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <warning>
    <para>If you are blending the average cost method with the standard cost
    method, your results may vary.</para>
  </warning>
  <para id="Para519911">When posting actual costs by item, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para519912">Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para id="Para">Enter the item number of the item whose actual costs
        you want to post.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para663275">UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para id="Para627831">For manufactured items, rolling up standard costs
    ensures that lower level costs are reflected in the cost for the parent
    item.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para519916"><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>standard costs</primary>
          <secondary>rolling up of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Roll Up Standard Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to roll up standard costs. When this option is specified,
        all selected costs will be added together to establish a revised total
        standard cost for the item. This revised total goes into effect after
        the POST button is selected. If all costs are selected, all costs will
        be rolled up. If a subset of all costs is selected, only the subset
        will be rolled up. If the Roll Up standard costs option is not
        specified, the selected cost postings will not be valid above their
        current level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para519918"><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>material costs</primary>
          <secondary>posting of</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>costing</primary>
          <secondary>posting of material costs</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>standard costs</primary>
          <secondary>material costs posted to</secondary>
        </indexterm>Post Material Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post material costs. Not selecting means material
        costs will not be posted to the standard cost for the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para519920">Post Lower Level Material Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post lower level material costs. Not selecting means
        lower level material costs will not be posted to the standard cost for
        the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term id="Para519922">Post Direct Labor Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post direct labor cost. Not selecting means the direct
        labor cost will not be posted to the standard cost for the
        item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term id="Para519924">Post Lower Level Direct Labor Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post lower level direct labor cost. Not selecting
        means the lower level direct labor cost will not be posted to the
        standard cost for the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para id="Para627883">You have the flexibility of updating all or only a
    subset of the listed costs. Updating a subset might be desirable if only
    material or user costs have changed, for example.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term id="Para519926">Post Overhead Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post overhead cost. Not selecting means the overhead
        cost will not be posted to the standard cost for the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term id="Para519928">Post Lower Level Overhead Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post lower level overhead cost. Not selecting means
        the lower level overhead cost will not be posted to the standard cost
        for the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term id="Para519930">Post Machine Overhead</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post machine overhead cost. This option is selected by
        default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term id="Para519932">Post Lower Machine Overhead</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post lower level machine overhead cost. This option is
        selected by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para519934"><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>user costs</primary>
          <secondary>posting of</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>costing</primary>
          <secondary>posting of user costs</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>standard costs</primary>
          <secondary>user costs posted to</secondary>
        </indexterm>Post User Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post user costs. Not selecting means user costs will
        not be posted to the standard cost for the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para519936">Post Lower Level User Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post lower level user costs. Not selecting means lower
        level user costs will not be posted to the standard cost for the
        item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para519938">The following buttons are unique to this
  screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para628086">POST</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Posts all selected actual costs by item to standard cost. If the
        option "Roll Up Standard Costs" has been selected, the total standard
        cost for the specified item will be updated.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para id="Para627441">Actual costs may also be posted to standard cost on
    an item-by-item basis using the right-click menu found on the Maintain
    Item Costs screen.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para627433">SELECT ALL COSTS</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Selects all costs for updating. Use this option to save time
        when selecting all costs for updating. The option "Roll Up Standard
        Costs" must be selected separately if you want to include a rolled up
        total for the parent item in the cost update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
