<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="postProduction">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>production</primary>

      <secondary>posting of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Post Production</title>

  <para>Work order progress can be posted in terms of materials used or
  operations completed. When you post production, you are using the
  materials-driven process for reporting progress. To post production for a
  work order, go to <guimenuitem>Manufacture &gt; Transactions &gt;
  Post</guimenuitem>. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/postProduction.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Post Production</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>When posting production for a work order, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Transaction Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date you want the transaction to be posted to the
        general ledger (G/L). The current day's date will display by
        default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Work Order #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the work order number of the work order whose production
        you want to post.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays site code automatically when work order number is
        entered into <guilabel>Work Order #</guilabel> field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays item number automatically when work order number is
        entered into <guilabel>Work Order #</guilabel> field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure (UOM).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Status</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays work order status automatically when work order number
        is entered into <guilabel>Work Order #</guilabel> field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Method</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Indicates whether selected work order is an assembly or
        disassembly work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Ordered</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display the quantity of the component item required per parent
        item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Received</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the quantity required to fulfill the specified work
        order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Balance Due</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the quantity issued in fulfillment of the specified
        work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. to Post</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the component items you want to
        post.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Backflush Materials</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate that the amount of materials indicated by the
        associated work order material requirement record will be issued to
        the selected work order for all pull or mixed component items. If
        there are any pull component items on the requirements list, this
        option will be selected and disabled (you must backflush pull items).
        If there are any mixed component items on the requirements list, this
        option will be selected and enabled (you can choose whether to
        backflush or not). If there are no pull or mixed component items on
        the requirements list, this option will not be selected and disabled
        (push items are not backflushed).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Backflush Operations</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate that the amount of time and labor indicated
        by the associated work order operation record will be issued to the
        selected work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Setup By</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the name of the user who performed the set up.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Run By</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the name of the user who performed the production
        run.</para>

        <note>
          <para>If the <guilabel>Backflush Operations</guilabel> option is not
          selected, the <guilabel>Setup</guilabel> and <guilabel>Run
          Time</guilabel> options will be disabled.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Close Work Order after Posting</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to close the work order after posting. If you are posting
        partial production and want to keep the work order open, you should
        not select this option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Production Notes</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        production posting notes related to the work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Immediate Transfer to Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to transfer work order production to specified site.
        Specify the site you want to transfer production to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scrap on Post</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to open the Scrap Work Order Material screen
        automatically when posting production.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>POST</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post production for the work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
