<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="postCostsByClassCode">
  <title><indexterm>
      <primary>actual costs</primary>
      <secondary>posting to standard by class code</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm>
      <primary>class codes</primary>
      <secondary>posting actual costs to standard for</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm>
      <primary>costing</primary>
      <secondary>posting actual to standard</secondary>
    </indexterm>Post Actual Costs by Class Code</title>
  <para id="Para519943">When you post actual costs you are replacing your
  existing standard costs with your newer actual costs. The standard cost of
  an item is the cost used for posting general ledger transactions. Standard
  cost is distinguished from actual cost in the sense that standard cost is
  fixed, whereas actual cost is subject to fluctuations arising from material
  or production changes. For example, the actual costs for purchased items may
  be updated whenever vouchers are posted for those items. Because standard
  and actual costs may diverge, posting actual costs to standard is the way
  you bring the two costs into alignment.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>For best performance and results, you should run this utility by all
    class codes?and don't select the "Roll Up" option. This will ensure your
    costs are updated properly for any items which cross class code
    lines.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To post actual costs by class code, select the "Post Actual Costs by
  Class Code" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para id="Para519947"><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/postCostsByClassCode.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Post Actual Costs by Class Code</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <warning>
    <para>If you are blending the average cost method with the standard cost
    method, your results may vary.</para>
  </warning>
  <para id="Para519949">When posting actual costs by class code, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para616958">All Class Codes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post actual costs for all class codes. Running the
        utility by all class codes is the preferred method. You should not use
        the "Roll Up" option when updating costs by all class codes, since
        that is redundant and can hurt performance.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para519950">Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify class code whose actual costs you want to post.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para593252">Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a class code pattern to select a range of class codes.
        Refine your search using Regular Expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para id="Para627992">For manufactured items, rolling up standard costs
    ensures that lower level costs are reflected in the cost for the parent
    item.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para627994"><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>standard costs</primary>
          <secondary>rolling up of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Roll Up Standard Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this option if you are updating a selected class code or
        class code pattern. Do not use this option if you are updating by all
        class codes, since that is redundant and can hurt performance. When
        this option is specified, all selected costs will be added together to
        establish a revised total standard cost for the item. This revised
        total goes into effect after the <guibutton>POST</guibutton> button is selected. If all costs
        are selected, all costs will be rolled up. If a subset of all costs is
        selected, only the subset will be rolled up. If the Roll Up Standard
        Costs option is not specified, the selected cost postings will not be
        valid above their current level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para627996"><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>material costs</primary>
          <secondary>posting of</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>costing</primary>
          <secondary>posting of material costs</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>standard costs</primary>
          <secondary>material costs posted to</secondary>
        </indexterm>Post Material Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post material costs. Not selecting means material
        costs will not be posted to the standard cost for the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para627998">Post Lower Level Material Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post lower level material costs. Not selecting means
        lower level material costs will not be posted to the standard cost for
        the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term id="Para628000">Post Direct Labor Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post direct labor cost. Not selecting means the direct
        labor cost will not be posted to the standard cost for the
        item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term id="Para628002">Post Lower Level Direct Labor Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post lower level direct labor cost. Not selecting
        means the lower level direct labor cost will not be posted to the
        standard cost for the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para id="Para628005">You have the flexibility of updating all or only a
    subset of the listed costs. Updating a subset might be desirable if only
    material or user costs have changed, for example.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term id="Para628007">Post Overhead Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post overhead cost. Not selecting means the overhead
        cost will not be posted to the standard cost for the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term id="Para628009">Post Lower Level Overhead Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post lower level overhead cost. Not selecting means
        the lower level overhead cost will not be posted to the standard cost
        for the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term id="Para628011">Post Machine Overhead</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post machine overhead cost. This option is selected by
        default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term id="Para628013">Post Lower Machine Overhead</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post lower level machine overhead cost. This option is
        selected by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para628015"><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>user costs</primary>
          <secondary>posting of</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>costing</primary>
          <secondary>posting of user costs</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>standard costs</primary>
          <secondary>user costs posted to</secondary>
        </indexterm>Post User Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post user costs. Not selecting means user costs will
        not be posted to the standard cost for the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para628017">Post Lower Level User Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post lower level user costs. Not selecting means lower
        level user costs will not be posted to the standard cost for the
        item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para id="Para628019">The following buttons are unique to this
  screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para628021"><guibutton>POST</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Posts all selected actual costs by item to standard cost. If the
        option "Roll Up Standard Costs" has been selected, the total standard
        cost for the specified item will be updated.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para id="Para628023">Actual costs may also be posted to standard cost on
    an item-by-item basis using the right-click menu found on the Maintain
    Item Costs screen.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term id="Para628024"><guibutton>SELECT ALL COSTS</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Selects all costs for updating. Use this option to save time
        when selecting all costs for updating. The option "Roll Up Standard
        Costs" must be selected separately if you want to include a rolled up
        total for the parent item in the cost update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
