<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="printStatementsByCustomerType">
  <title>Print Statements by Customer Type</title>

  <para>Customer statements show past due information for open receivables. To
  print customer statements by customer type, select the <guimenuitem>Print
  Statements by Customer Type</guimenuitem> option.</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/printStatementsByCustomerType.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Print Statements by Customer Type</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When printing customer statements by customer type, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>

  <para role="xtconnect"><tip>
      <para>If some customers have EDI profiles attached, you may encounter an
      EDI processing interface when printing particular customer
      statements.</para>
    </tip></para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Customer Types</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to print customer statements for all customer
        types.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the customer type you want to print customer statements
        for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a customer type pattern to select a range of customer
        types. Refine your search using regular expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>As of</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the point-in-time date you want the statement to be
        relative to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Grace Period</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
        value up to a maximum of 990. The grace period extends backwards in
        time from the current day, covering the number of days specified here.
        If the due dates for a customer's open receivables fall within the
        grace period, a statement will not be printed for that customer.
        Statements will only be printed for customers having overdue
        balances—that is, open receivables which fall outside the grace
        period.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Only Print Customers with Past Due Amounts</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you only want to print statements for customers who
        have past due amounts. If not selected, you will get statements for
        all customers.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
