<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="printWoTraveler">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>travelers</primary>
      <secondary>printing of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Print Traveler</title>
  <para>A traveler is a collection of printed documents which accompanies a
  work order. Traveler documents may include the pick list, routing, or
  packing list. To print a work order traveler, select the
  <guimenuitem>Manufacture &gt; Forms &gt; Print Traveler...</guimenuitem>
  option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/printWoTraveler.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Print W/O Traveler</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When printing a traveler, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Work Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the work order number of the work order you want to print
        a traveler for.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays site code automatically when work order number is
        entered into <guilabel>Work Order #</guilabel> field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays item number automatically when work order number is
        entered into <guilabel>Work Order #</guilabel> field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure (UOM).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Status</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays work order status automatically when work order number
        is entered into <guilabel>Work Order #</guilabel> field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Method</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicates work order method is either assembly or
        disassembly.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Release Work Order</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to release the work order. Selecting this option causes
        the work order status to change from exploded (E) to released
        (R).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Documents</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the documents you want to print.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Print Pick List</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to print a pick list. A pick list is a printed list
              showing the work order material requirements for a specified
              work order. Not selecting means a pick list will not be printed
              with the traveler.</para>
              <tip>
                <para>At least one of the document options must be selected
                for the <guibutton>PRINT</guibutton> button to be
                enabled.</para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
            <term>Print Routing</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to print a routing. A routing is a list showing the
              work order operations for a specified work order. Not selecting
              means a routing will not be printed with the traveler.</para>
              <note>
                <para>The routing pulls its information from the list of work
                order operations for the work order item, not from the item's
                routing.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Print Packing List</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to print a packing list. This option is only
              enabled when a work order is driven by a sales order. The option
              is not available for manually generated work orders. Not
              selecting means a packing list will not be printed with the
              traveler.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Print Work Order Label</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to print work order labels. If selected, the
              quantity of work order labels printed will equal the quantity of
              items ordered by the work order. Not selecting means work order
              labels will not be printed with the traveler.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>By default, the system will print work order labels in the same
    quantity as the quantity ordered by the work order. If you want to print
    fewer than the quantity ordered, use the <guimenuitem>Manufacture &gt;
    Forms &gt; Print Work Order Form...</guimenuitem> option.</para>
  </note>
</section>
