<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="printChecks">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>payment runs</primary>

      <secondary>printing of</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>payments</primary>

      <secondary>printing multiple</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>accounts payable</primary>

      <secondary>printing payments for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Print Payment Run</title>

  <para>To print a payment run, go to <guimenuitem>Accounting &gt; Accounts
  Payable &gt; Forms &gt; Print Payment Run</guimenuitem>. The following
  screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/printChecks.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Print Payment Run</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <tip>
    <para>If payments being printed contain reference lines which spill over
    and exceed one standard page, then consider using the report definition
    CheckMultiPage.xml. This payment form is designed to support multiple
    pages for one payment number.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>When printing a payment run, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bank Account</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the bank account associated with the payment run you
        want to print. Only bank accounts which require printing will have
        payments to print. If the specified bank account is configured to use
        electronic funds transfer (EFT), the <guibutton>CREATE EFT
        FILE</guibutton> button will be enabled on this screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Next Payment #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the first available payment number in the payment run
        for the specified bank account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term># of Payments to Print</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify how many payments should be printed in the payment run.
        Payment numbers increment in intervals of one (1) beginning with the
        first payment number displayed above. The maximum possible selection
        indicates the maximum number of payments in the payment run. Selecting
        a number less than the maximum will cause that number of payments to
        be printed, leaving the remaining number still to be printed.</para>

        <note>
          <para>Payments will automatically print by recipient type (vendor,
          tax authority, customer) then alphabetically by the recipients
          number.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Payments by Name</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to print payments in alphabetical order by vendor,
        customer, or tax authority name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>CREATE EFT FILE</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create an EFT file. This button will be enabled only
        for bank accounts which are configured to use EFT.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>payments</primary>

      <secondary>problems when printing</secondary>
    </indexterm>If for some reason you experience printing problems when
  printing a payment run, select the <guibutton>NO</guibutton> button from the
  following screen:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/printChecksSuccess.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Print Message</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>If you select the <guibutton>NO</guibutton> button at the end of
  printing a payment run, the following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/printChecksReview.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Review List of Printed Payments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>The Review Printed Payments screen lists all the payments which were
  included in the payment run.</para>

  <note>
    <para>The default action listed for all payments in a payment run is
    "printed." Each payment will be marked as printed when you select the
    <guibutton>COMPLETE</guibutton> button, unless you specify one of the
    other possible actions: void, replace, etc.</para>
  </note>

  <para>When reviewing the list of payments included in a payment run, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>COMPLETE</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to perform the specified action associated with each of
        the listed payments. This should be the last option selected at the
        conclusion of your payment run review. Selecting this option
        terminates the review process. If no action is specified for a
        payment, the status of the payment will remain as it was prior to
        printing the payment run.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>EDIT NUMBER</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to reprint a payment if the payment was reported as
        having been printed incorrectly. This option only works for payments
        whose printing has been specifically reported as unsuccessful.
        Successfully printed payments may not be reprinted. The ability to
        reprint badly printed payments is an <guimenu>Accounting</guimenu>
        module configuration. For more information, please see <xref
        linkend="reprintPayments"/>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>UNMARK</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a payment number and then select this option to remove
        any action associated with the payment. If no action is specified for
        a payment, the status of the payment will remain as it was prior to
        printing the payment run.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
    <para>You may select multiple payments for marking using the
    <guibutton>SHIFT</guibutton> or <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key and your
    mouse.</para>
  </tip>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>MARK AS PRINTED</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a payment number and then select this option to mark
        the payment as printed. By default, all payments in a payment run are
        marked as printed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>VOID</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a payment number and then select this option to mark
        the payment as voided. Before a payment can be replaced, it must first
        be voided.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>VOID &amp; REPLACE</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a payment number and then select this option to mark
        the payment as voided and then replace the payment with a new payment.
        Using this option, you can both void and replace a payment in one
        step.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>SELECT ALL</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Use this option to automatically select all payments for
        marking, or unmarking.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
