<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="printPackingList">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>packing lists</primary>
      <secondary>printing of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Print Packing List</title>
  <para>To print a packing list or sales order pick list, go to
  <guimenuitem>Sales &gt; Forms &gt; </guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Print Packing
  List</guimenuitem>. If the order has a shipment number, the packing list
  form should be used. If there is no shipment number—that is, if no line item
  quantity has been issued to shipping—then the sales order pick list form
  should be used. Both forms are defined under <guimenuitem>Sales &gt; Master
  Information &gt; Customer Form Assignments</guimenuitem>.</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/printPackingList.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Print Packing List</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When printing a packing list, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>All Sites</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include packing lists for all sites.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Selected</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the site you want to print packing lists
              for.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Form</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which type of packing list form you want to
        print:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Auto Select</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to have the system automatically determine which
              form should be used, based on the state of the order at the time
              the report is printed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Packing List</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to have the defined packing list form printed. This
              form will be used if an order has a shipment number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Pick List</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to have the sales order pick list form printed. If
              the order does not have a shipment number, this form will be
              used.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Reprint</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this option if you want to print a packing list which has
        already been printed. Once a packing list has been printed, you must
        use this option if you want to print it again.</para>
        <note>
          <para>A sales order pick list will be printed if the sales order
          does not yet have a shipment number associated with it—that is, if
          no line item quantity has been issued to shipping. If stock has been
          issued to shipping, then the packing list report definition will be
          used.</para>
          <para>The system includes two alternate sales order pick list report
          definitions:</para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>PickingListSOClosedLines.xml</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>PickingListNoClosedLines.xml</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          <para>The first includes already closed sales order line items in
          the report; the other excludes closed line items.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the order number of the order whose packing list you want
        to print. The order may be either a sales order or a transfer
        order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipment #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the shipment number you want to print a packing list
        for. Shipment numbers are assigned to orders when line item quantity
        is issued to shipping. A single order may have multiple shipments
        associated with it. If no stock has ever been issued to shipping for
        an order, then no shipment number will be associated with it.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the customer's name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Phone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the customer's phone number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Purchase Order Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the customer's purchase order number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the order date for the sales order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
