<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="purchaseOrder">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>purchase orders</primary>

      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Enter New Purchase Order</title>

  <para>To create a new purchase order, select the <guilabel>Enter New
  Purchase Order</guilabel> option. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrder.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Enter New Purchase Order</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When entering a new purchase order, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Next available purchase order number will automatically display,
        unless your system requires you to enter purchase order numbers
        manually. Default values and input parameters for purchase order
        numbers are configurable at the system level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays current day's date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Release Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the date the purchase order was released.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vendor #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the vendor number of the vendor you are issuing the
        purchase order to.</para>

        <note>
          <para>A valid vendor number must be entered in the <guilabel>Vendor
          #</guilabel> field before line items can be added to the purchase
          order. If no valid vendor number is entered, you will not be able to
          add line items to the purchase order.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Terms</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the billing terms for the order. Default billing terms
        for a vendor are defined on the vendor master. You may select
        alternate terms on the purchase order header.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax zones</primary>

          <secondary>for purchase orders</secondary>
        </indexterm>Tax Zone</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the tax zone associated with the purchase order. By
        default, the tax zone associated with the vendor will be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Status</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The status of the purchase order will display here.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Purchasing Agent</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the name of the agent assigned to the order. By default,
        the name of the logged-in user will be entered as purchasing
        agent—assuming that user is designated as a purchasing agent. If the
        user is not a purchasing agent, the first alphabetical name in the
        list of purchasing agents will be entered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Print on Save</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Check <guilabel>Print on Save</guilabel> to automatically print
        the purchase order when the <guibutton>SAVE</guibutton> button is
        pressed. If the vendor specified on the purchase order has an EDI
        profile attached, you may encounter an EDI processing interface when
        printing the purchase order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Order #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays information about linked sales orders. This field is
        only used if the purchase order was created from a sales order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Purchase Type</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a purchase type for reporting purposes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vendor Address</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the vendor address information:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Main Address</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the vendor's main address. You may manually
              override the displayed address information in the fields
              below—or use the lookup feature to select another address. If a
              new address is manually entered here, that address will be added
              automatically to the master list of addresses. For additional
              documentation related to creating addresses, see <xref
              linkend="address"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Primary Contact</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the vendor's primary contact. You may manually
              override the displayed contact information in the fields
              below—or use the lookup feature to select another contact. If a
              new contact is manually entered here, that contact will be added
              automatically to the master list of contacts. For additional
              documentation related to creating addresses, see <xref
              linkend="contact"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship To</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the ship-to address information:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry role="standard">
            <term>Receiving Site</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the site where materials from the purchase order
              will be received. By default, all active sites are available for
              selection as receiving sites.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry role="standard">
            <term>Drop Ship</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>If the purchase order was created as a drop ship order
              from a sales order, this option will be selected. This option is
              only available for drop ship purchase orders linked to sales
              orders.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Name</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>The name that is associated with the ship-to address. A
              purchase order created from a drop ship sales order item will
              have the ship-to address name displayed in this field.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Ship-To Address</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays either the site address for the specified
              receiving site or, for drop ship orders, the customer ship-to
              address from the linked sales order. You may manually override
              the displayed address information in the fields below—or use the
              lookup feature to select another address. If a new address is
              manually entered here, that address will be added automatically
              to the master list of addresses. For additional documentation
              related to creating addresses, see <xref
              linkend="contact"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Shipping Contact</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays either the contact information for the specified
              receiving site or, for drop ship orders, the contact for the
              customer ship-to address on the linked sales order. You may
              manually override the displayed contact information in the
              fields below—or use the lookup feature to select another
              contact. If a new contact is manually entered here, that contact
              will be added automatically to the master list of contacts. For
              additional documentation related to creating addresses, see
              <xref linkend="contact"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>F.O.B.</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the free on board (F.O.B.) location for the shipping
        site.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Via</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the preferred ship via method for this vendor. By default,
        the ship via entered on the vendor master will populate this
        field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>purchase orders</primary>

      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create or modify purchase order line items, select the
  <guimenuitem>Line Items</guimenuitem> tab at the top of the Purchase Order
  screen. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrder_lineItems.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Purchase Order Line Items</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating or modifying purchase order line items, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Items</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists line items for this purchase order. A valid vendor
        number must be entered in the <guilabel>Vendor #</guilabel> field
        before line items can be added to the order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total Quantity</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total of all line item quantities on the
        order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total Weight (LB)</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total weight for all line item quantities on the
        order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subtotal</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the subtotal for the purchase order line items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Freight</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of any miscellaneous freight charges to be
        added to the order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>freight</primary>

          <secondary>on purchase orders</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>purchase orders</primary>

          <secondary>freight charges on</secondary>
        </indexterm>Total P/O Freight</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount of freight charges. The amount
        displayed includes the sum of all line item freight and miscellaneous
        freight charges.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the calculated tax amount, if applicable.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total value of the purchase order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>MOVE UP</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a purchase order line item and then select this button
        to move the line item up the list of line items. Sequence numbers are
        automatically adjusted to reflect the change in position.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>MOVE DOWN</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a purchase order line item and then select this button
        to move the line item down the list of line items. Sequence numbers
        are automatically adjusted to reflect the change in position.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>Purchase order characteristics are user-defined definitions which may
  be used to provide additional layers of description about purchase orders.
  These descriptions are static and not processed by the system, but are
  useful for informational purposes. To enter characteristics associated with
  a purchase order, select the <guimenuitem>Characteristics</guimenuitem> tab.
  The following screen will appear:</para>

  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrder_characteristics.png"/>
    </imageobject>

    <caption><para>Purchase Order Characteristics</para></caption>
  </mediaobject>

  <xi:include href="../widgets/characteristic.xml"
              xpointer="characteristiclWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

  <para>To add notes to a purchase order, select the
  <guimenuitem>Notes</guimenuitem> tab at the top of the Purchase Order
  screen. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrder_notesPage.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Add Notes to Purchase Order</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When adding notes to a purchase order, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        notes related to the purchase order. If the vendor has order notes
        associated with their vendor record, those order notes will be
        displayed here.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To add comments to a purchase order—or to view system-generated
  comments—select the <guimenuitem>Comments</guimenuitem> tab at the top of
  the Purchase Order screen. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrder_TabPage.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Add Comments to Purchase Order</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <xi:include href="../widgets/comments.xml" xpointer="commentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

  <para>If you want to speed up your data entry of purchase order line items,
  you can use the quick entry interface. This screen allows you to enter
  multiple line items in one session. It also simplifies the process by
  presenting only the minimum required fields. To enter line items using the
  quick entry interface, select the <guimenuitem>Quick Entry</guimenuitem> tab
  at the top of the Purchase Order screen. The following screen will
  appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrder_quickEntry.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Purchase Order Quick Entry</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <tip>
    <para>To get started entering line items, place your cursor in the
    <guilabel>Item</guilabel> field. You can then move from field-to-field
    using the tab key on your keyboard.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>When entering purchase order line items using the quick entry
  interface, you are presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter an inventory item number. This field is used for entering
        items stored in inventory. Use the <guilabel>Vend. Item #</guilabel>
        field for entering non-inventory items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Supplying Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select a supplying site from the list of available options. By
        default, the user's preferred site will be presented first.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vend. Item #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Use this field for entering non-inventory item numbers. If not
        used to handle non-inventory items, this field will display vendor
        item numbers for inventory items which have item sources
        defined.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vend Description</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the vendor description for the item being ordered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expense Cat.</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the expense category you want your non-inventory quantity
        to be assigned to. Use this option for non-inventory line items
        only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty.</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity you want to purchase.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Unit Price</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the unit price for the line item. If an item source is
        defined, this information may fill in automatically.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ext. Price</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the extended price. This is a calculated field and is
        shaded to indicate that it may not be edited.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the freight amount, if any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Due Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the due date. If an item source is defined, this
        information may fill in automatically. For drop ship orders, the due
        date for purchase order items will be the same as the linked sales
        order's scheduled date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>SAVE QUICK ENTRIES</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to save all the line items entered using the quick entry
        interface.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE QUICK ENTRY</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a line item and then select this button to remove the
        item from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To view the documents associated with a purchase order, select the
  <guimenuitem>Documents</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:<mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrder_documents.png"/>
      </imageobject>

      <caption><para>Purchase Order Documents</para></caption>
    </mediaobject></para>

  <xi:include href="../widgets/documents.xml" xpointer="documentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

  <para>To view email associated with a purchase order, select the
  <guimenuitem>Email</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>

  <xi:include href="../widgets/emailWidget.xml" xpointer="emailWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

  <xi:include href="purchaseOrderItem.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
