<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="purchaseOrderItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>purchase orders</primary>

      <secondary>creating items for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Purchase Order Item</title>

  <para>To create a new purchase order line item, select the
  <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrderItem.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Create New Purchase Order Line Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating a new purchase order line item, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>

  <note>
    <para>If the line item was created from a linked sales order, the details
    will be updated whenever the sales order is updated.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Number</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the purchase order number specified in the New Purchase
        Order screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The application automatically assigns line numbers to purchase
        order line items. Numbering begins at one ("1") and increases
        automatically in increments of one.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Refresh Order</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate you want the purchase order header to be
        refreshed immediately in the background. When the header is refreshed
        immediately, you will be able to see the rows of line items being
        added to the order. However, this feature can impact performance when
        entering purchase order line items. If you are experiencing
        performance issues, you should not select this option. The purchase
        order will be refreshed when you close the purchase order line Item
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Item</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>If the item being purchased is an inventory item, select this
        option and specify the following:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item Number</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the item number of the item you want to add to the
              purchase order. You may also enter manufactured items that you
              normally make, but you occasionally buy?as long as the item site
              for the manufactured item also indicates it may be
              purchased.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry role="standard">
            <term>Site</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the site where the item is supplied at. For
              purchased Items to be included on a purchase order, their item
              site record must indicate they are purchased for the
              site.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry role="distribution">
            <term>ITEM/ALIAS SEARCH</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Advanced item search (AIS) is a feature designed
              specifically with distribution in mind. This feature allows
              distributors and end users to quickly search for both items and
              item aliases?as well as current inventory levels?filtering every
              keystroke. From this screen you also have the ability to create
              an item alias.</para>

              <note>
                <para>When using the AIS, you must enter at least three
                characters (i.e., numbers, letters or a combination of both)
                before any search results will be returned. This is for speed
                of performance reasons.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry role="distribution">
            <term>VENDOR CATALOG</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to use the External Vendor Catalog screen to view
              items as they appear within the various vendor catalogs you are
              subscribed to.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Non-Inventory Item</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>If the item being purchased is a non-inventory item, select this
        option and specify the following:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Expense Category</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select an expense category to assign the non-inventory
              item to.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Ordered</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the specified item to be ordered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Received</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays quantity received from quantity ordered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Unit of measure (UOM) item is being ordered in.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Type</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select a tax type.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Unit Price</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the unit price for the specified item—or use the
        lookup—feature to look up pricing information, including pricing
        related to quantity breaks.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Extended Price</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the extended price. The extended price for a line item
        is based on the quantity ordered multiplied by the unit price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Item Freight</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of freight charges for the entire line item
        quantity. The system automatically calculates the per unit freight
        charge by dividing the line item freight amount by the line item
        quantity. This per unit freight charge is needed when receiving or
        vouchering quantities less than the original quantity ordered. Line
        item freight is distinguished from miscellaneous freight, which
        applies to the purchase order as a whole.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the calculated tax amount.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Due Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify date when order is expected to be received. For drop
        ship orders, the due date for purchase order items will be the same as
        the linked sales order's scheduled date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>If your system is configured to use projects, select a project
        number to associate with the purchase order line item. If the purchase
        order line item is being created from a purchase request driven by
        sales order demand—and the parent sales order had a project number
        associated with it—then the project number from the parent sales order
        will automatically be entered here. In this way, sales orders and
        purchase order line items may be linked to the same project.</para>

        <para role="xtprjaccnt">When you have the xTuple project accounting
        package installed—and you link a project to the purchase order line
        item—transactions related to the purchase order line item will include
        the project number as the final segment of affected G/L account
        numbers. Account numbers related to the following transactions will
        include project number as the final segment: post receipt, correct
        receipt, and post purchase order return. If there are cost variances
        when vouchering, the purchase variance account will also inherit the
        project number segment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vendor Source Information</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>If item source information exists for an inventory item, that
        information will display automatically here. For non-inventory items,
        you should specify an item number and item description.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Vend. Item Number</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the item number the vendor assigns to the specified
              item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Vendor Item Description</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the description the vendor uses to describe to the
              specified item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Min. Order Qty</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>For inventory items only, displays the minimum order
              quantity for the specified item and the specified vendor.
              Minimum order quantities are established in the item source
              master.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Order Qty. Mult.</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>For inventory items only, displays the order multiple for
              the specified item and the specified vendor. Order multiples are
              established in the item source master.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Vendor UOM:</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>For inventory items only, displays the UOM used by the
              vendor for the specified item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Inv./Vendor UOM Ratio:</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>For inventory items only, displays the ratio between
              inventory and vendor UOM.</para>

              <note>
                <para>The inv./vendor UOM ratio specifies the ratio between
                inventory and vendor UOM. For example, if you store an item in
                single units, but a vendor sells you the item in cases of 12,
                then the ratio would be 12—or 12:1. When an inv./vend. ratio
                is specified, the system allows you to purchase items using
                the vendor's UOM; however, when the items are received, the
                system will automatically convert the inventory to your
                inventory UOM.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Earliest Avail. Due Date</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>For inventory items only, displays the earliest due date
              for the specified item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Contract</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the standard contract quantity for the item
              source, if it exists.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To add manufacturer information to the purchase order item, select the
  <guimenuitem>Manufacturer</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>

  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrderItem_manufTab.png"/>
      </imageobject>

      <caption>Purchase Order Item Manufacturer Information</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>

  <para>When entering manufacturer information to a purchase order item, you
  are presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The name of the manufacturer who creates the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The item number the manufacturer uses to identify the
        component.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The description the manufacturer uses to describe the
        item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To add miscellaneous remarks to the purchase order item, select the
  <guimenuitem>Remarks</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrderItem_remarksTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Purchase Order Item Remarks</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>When entering miscellaneous remarks to a purchase order item,
  you are presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        notes related to the purchase order line item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>To view system-generated comments associated with an item—or to
        add new comments of your own—select the <guimenuitem>Comments</guimenuitem> option.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>If an item has characteristics associated with it, you have the option
  of linking those characteristics to a purchase order item. In the case where
  sales order demand generates a purchase request, item characteristics and
  values inherited from the sales order will already be linked to the purchase
  order. Ultimately, characteristics associated with a purchase order item may
  be printed on the purchase order report.</para>

  <tip>
    <para>You can link characteristics and values to an item by using the item
    master. Once entered, these characteristics and values will be available
    to users entering purchase order items.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>To specify or edit characteristics for a purchase order item, select
  the <guimenuitem>Characteristics</guimenuitem> tab at the bottom of the
  screen. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrderItem_itemchar.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Purchase Order Line Item Characteristics</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <xi:include href="../widgets/characteristic.xml"
              xpointer="characteristiclWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

  <para role="standard">When ordering purchased items, you have the option to
  specify which revision of the item's bill of materials (BOM) and routing
  you want to buy. By default, the active revision will be
  used. To specify revision information for a purchase order item, select the
  <guimenuitem>Revision</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>

  <screenshot role="standard">
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrderItem_revision.png"/>
      </imageobject>

      <caption>Line Item Revisions</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>

  <para role="standard"><note>
      <para>You may create purchase order items for pending revisions. For
      purchase order purposes, a pending revision is considered to be the same
      as an inactive revision. The revision status of a pending revision will
      not be changed if a purchase order item is created for it.</para>
    </note></para>

  <para role="standard">When specifying revision information for a purchase
  order item, you are presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Bill of Materials</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the BOM revision you want to use for the purchase order
        item. By default, the active revision will be used.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Revision</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select from the list of existing available revisions. The
              status of the revision will also be displayed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term>Routing</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the routing revision you want to use for the purchase order
        item. By default, the active revision will be used.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Revision</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select from the list of existing available revisions. The
              status of the revision will also be displayed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To view demand information for purchase order items linked to sales
  orders or work orders, select the <guimenuitem>Demand</guimenuitem> tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>

  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/purchaseOrderItem_demandTab.png"/>
      </imageobject>

      <caption>Line Item Demand Source</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Demand</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays information about the sales order or the work order the
        purchase order item is linked to. If the purchase order item is not
        linked, the <guimenuitem>Demand</guimenuitem> tab will be
        disabled.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
