<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="quote">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>quotes</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales quotes</primary>
      <see>quotes</see>
    </indexterm> New quote</title>
  <para>A quote is a statement issued to a customer or prospect indicating
  pricing and sales terms for specified quantities of sold items. Quotes are
  often precursors to sales orders. To create a quote, go to
  <guimenuitem>Sales &gt; Quote &gt; New</guimenuitem>. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/quote.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create new Quote</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Be sure to close all sales order windows before exiting the system.
    This will prevent the creation of orphaned sales order records.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new quote, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Next available quote number will automatically display, unless
        your system requires you to enter quote numbers manually. Default
        values and input parameters for quote numbers are configurable in the
        <guimenu>System</guimenu> module.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays current day's date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scheduled Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the order's earliest scheduled date. The scheduled date
        corresponds to the earliest scheduled date for an included quote item.
        If there are no existing line items, the date entered here will become
        the default schedule date for the first one. If line items do exist
        and the date is changed, you will be asked whether you want all
        editable lines to change. If the change affects pricing, you will be
        asked whether you want prices to be updated as well. If hidden, this
        field can be viewed by selecting the <guibutton>MORE</guibutton>
        button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>pack dates</primary>
          <secondary>for quotes</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>pack dates for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Pack Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The pack date is the same date as the ship date. Because the
        field can be edited, you have the ability to change the pack date and
        make it different from the ship date. This field can be viewed by
        selecting the <guibutton>MORE</guibutton> button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Print on Save</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to automatically print the quote when it is saved.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the customer number of the customer (or prospect) to be
        billed for the sale. The lookup feature located to the right of the
        field leads to a searchable customers list. The lookup feature will be
        disabled if the quote is entered for a prospect. You may also access
        the customer list using the keyboard shortcut <guibutton>CTRL +
        L</guibutton>. Once a customer number is entered, the customer name
        and billing address will display. Select the <guibutton>?</guibutton>
        or <guibutton>$</guibutton> symbol to view customer information for
        the specified customer. If a customer's credit is good, the button
        will feature a black question mark (<guibutton>?</guibutton>) icon. If
        the customer is on credit warning, the icon will turn into an orange
        dollar sign (<guibutton>$</guibutton>). A red dollar sign
        (<guibutton>$</guibutton>) indicates the customer is on credit hold.
        You may also create a new customer record by selecting the
        <guibutton>+</guibutton> button.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>A valid customer number must be entered in the
          <guilabel>Customer #</guilabel> field before line items can be added
          to a quote. If no valid customer number is entered, you will not be
          able to add line items to the quote. Additionally, quotes may only
          be entered for active customers.</para>
        </tip>
        <note>
          <para>Quotes may not be entered for customers who are on credit
          warning or credit hold. Only users with special privileges may
          override these credit settings.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The customer name is displayed in an editable text field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the number of the preferred ship-to address. Customers may
        maintain multiple ship-to addresses. If the Customer master for the
        specified customer indicates that free-form ship-to's are allowed,
        then any address may be entered. If free-form ship-to's are not
        allowed, then the ship-to address must be entered using the browse
        button located to the right of the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The ship-to name is displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. PO #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a customer purchase order number, as needed.</para>
        <note>
          <para>You will be required to enter a customer purchase order number
          for customers who require them. If required, duplicate numbers will
          only be allowed if the customer uses blanket purchase orders. All
          customer requirements are specified on the Customer master.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the shipping site associated with the quote. The site
        selected here acts as the default free-on-board (FOB) location. A site
        may be designated as a shipping site on the Site master. This field
        can be viewed upon selecting the <guibutton>MORE</guibutton>
        button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sale Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the sale type. Sales account assignments by sales type
        are available.</para>
        <note>
          <para>If the sales order setup setting <guilabel>Display Sales Order
          Line Items Tab by Default</guilabel> is checked, the
          <guimenuitem>Line Items</guimenuitem> tab will be displayed on the
          opening window for quote entry.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>setting terms for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Terms</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the billing terms associated with the order. By default,
        the customer's standard billing terms will appear in the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales representatives</primary>
          <secondary>commissions for</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>commissions on</secondary>
        </indexterm>Sales Rep.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the sales representative—or outside rep, in the
        Distribution edition—associated with the quote. Sales representatives
        are linked to a customer on the Customer master—either by a default
        setting or through the assignment of ship-to addresses. Each ship-to
        address may have a different sales representative associated with it.
        Consequently, the name of the sales representative appearing on the
        quote header will be the same as specified for the ship-to address
        being used. If you are using the enhanced commissions package, the
        sales rep information is moved to a separate tab.</para>
        <note>
          <para>When creating a new quote, only active sales reps will be
          available for selection. For future changes to an existing quote,
          all sales reps (active and inactive) will be listed to ensure that
          the original sales rep will still appear.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Commission</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the commission percentage recorded on the Customer
        master will be automatically entered in this field. If for some reason
        you select a non-default sales representative at order entry, the
        commission rate will not change. To adjust the commission rate, you
        must make the change manually. This field can be viewed by selecting
        the <guibutton>MORE</guibutton> button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax zones</primary>
          <secondary>for quotes</secondary>
        </indexterm>Tax Zone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the tax zone associated with the quote. The tax zone for
        the specified ship-to address will be entered here by default.
        Otherwise, the primary tax zone for the customer will be entered. This
        field can be viewed upon selecting the <guibutton>MORE</guibutton>
        button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>F.O.B.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter free-on-board terms for the order. By default, FOB. Terms
        entered on the Shipping Site master will appear in this field. The
        default terms may be changed during order entry—and also at later
        stages during the billing cycle.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Via</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The preferred ship via method for the customer will appear in
        the field. You may change the default ship via using the list. You may
        also enter a free-form ship via simply by typing the name of the ship
        via into the field.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>The system supports up-to-date shipment tracking with links to
          the websites of many leading shipping companies (i.e., ship
          vias).</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Zone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the shipping zone. Sales account assignments by shipping
        zone are available.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Quote Status</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the current status of the quote. There are two possible
        values: open and converted. Quotes get the converted status after they
        have been converted to sales orders. If your <guimenu>Sales</guimenu>
        module is configured to show quotes after they have been converted,
        you may view historical quotes from the Customer workbench. Converted
        quotes will not be visible on the list of open quotes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expire</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the date when the quote expires, if any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>billing information for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Bill-To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the customer billing information below:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Address</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the customer's bill-to address. You may manually
              override the displayed address information in the fields
              below—or use the lookup feature to select another address. If a
              new address is manually entered here, that address will be added
              automatically to the master list of addresses. For additional
              documentation related to creating addresses, see <xref
              linkend="address" />.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Billing Contact</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the customer's billing contact. You may manually
              override the displayed contact information in the fields
              below—or use the lookup feature to select another contact. If a
              new contact is manually entered here, that contact will be added
              automatically to the master list of contacts. For additional
              documentation related to creating addresses, see <xref
              linkend="contact" />.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Copy to Ship-to -&gt;</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to copy contents of billing address into
        <guilabel>Ship-To Address</guilabel> field. This option is enabled if
        the Customer master for the specified customer indicates that
        free-form ship-tos are allowed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>ship-to details for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Ship-To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify shipping details below:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Address</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the specified ship-to address. You may manually
              override the displayed address information in the fields
              below—or use the lookup feature to select another address. If a
              new address is manually entered here, that address will be added
              automatically to the master list of addresses. For additional
              documentation related to creating addresses, see <xref
              linkend="contact" />.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Shipping contact</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the shipping contact for the ship-to address. You
              may manually override the displayed contact information in the
              fields below—or use the lookup feature to select another
              contact. If a new contact is manually entered here, that contact
              will be added automatically to the master list of contacts. For
              additional documentation related to creating addresses, see
              <xref linkend="contact" />.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>CLEAR</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to refresh the Quote screen so that you can enter a new
        quote. Using the <guibutton>CLEAR</guibutton> button does not erase or
        in any way change the information on the quote you are
        clearing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>MORE</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display extra information related to the sales order.
        To hide the extra information, simply select the
        <guibutton>MORE</guibutton> button again.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>quotes</primary>
      <secondary>creating line items for</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create or modify quote line items, select the
  <guimenuitem>Line Items</guimenuitem> tab at the top of the New Quote
  screen. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/quote_lineItems.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Line Items tab</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>The system will allow you to enter quotes for items which do not
    have item sites. However, item sites must be defined before a quote can be
    converted to a sales order.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating or modifying quote line items, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists line items for this quote. A valid customer number
        must be entered in the <guilabel>Customer #</guilabel> field before
        line items can be added to the order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description to identify the miscellaneous charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Sales Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a sales account to assign the miscellaneous charge
        to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight Weight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the combined weight of all quote line items. Freight
        weight represents the sum of an item's product weight and packaging
        weight, both of which are defined on the Item master. The per unit
        freight weight multiplied by the quantity per gives you the line item
        freight weight. The sum of all line item freight weights is the
        combined weight for the quote.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Margin</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total profit margin for the quote. The profit
        margin is based on the following formula:</para>
        <para>Quote Subtotal - Total Standard Costs for all Line Items</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Margin %</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the profit margin percentage for the order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subtotal</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the subtotal for the quote line items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of any miscellaneous charge. Examples of
        miscellaneous charges include palletization costs, co-op refund, etc.
        Before entering a miscellaneous charge amount, you must first assign
        the charge to a sales account and also enter a description of the
        charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If you do not use miscellaneous charges at your site, you can hide
    these fields so they are not visible when entering sales orders. To do so,
    simply select the <guilabel>Hide Misc. Charges</guilabel> option in the
    <guimenu>System</guimenu>-level configuration.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>freight</primary>
          <secondary>on sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>freight charges on</secondary>
        </indexterm>Freight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of freight charge to be added to the specified
        order. Freight charges may be entered during the creation or
        modification of a quote—or at the time of shipment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the amount of tax that will be added to the sales
        order, as defined by the specified tax code. To get a detailed view of
        the tax calculation, click on the <guibutton>Tax</guibutton> link
        using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount of the quote.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Any quote line item may be shipped—even if the item or item
          site in question becomes inactive after the quote has been
          created.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="distribution">
      <term>Quick Item Entry</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Distribution edition users will have the option to enter line
        items quickly on this screen, without having to first open the Sales
        Order Item screen:</para>
        <para><variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Item Number</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Enter the item number of the item you want to sell. The
                item list will contain sold items available for sale to the
                specified customer. The list of available items may vary from
                customer to customer, depending on how pricing schedules are
                implemented at your site. Once an item number is entered, the
                inventory unit of measure and item description will
                automatically appear.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Site</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Specify the site the sales order item is sold from.
                Items may be supplied to sales orders from multiple item
                sites. After an item number is entered above, the system
                checks for available item sites for the item. Any item sites
                having the <guilabel>Sold from</guilabel> flag set on them
                will be selectable from this site list. By default, the item
                site having the highest ranking will be selected as the first
                available site. If more than one item site share a ranking of
                "1," the sites will be sorted in alphabetical order. Item site
                rankings are set on the Item Site master.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Qty. Ordered</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Enter the quantity of the specified item being ordered.
                The quantity will be set to "1" by default.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Scheduled Date</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>The scheduled date is the date when the line item
                quantity should be shipped. The user who enters the line item
                is responsible for determining the scheduled date. After
                entering the scheduled date, hit the
                <guibutton>TAB</guibutton> key on your keyboard to display
                values in the remaining display only fields.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Net Unit Price</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Displays the unit price for the sales order item. By
                default, the system will choose the lower of the following two
                prices: A) The most-specific pricing schedule assignment or B)
                any sale in effect at the time of order entry. The specificity
                of pricing schedule assignments is determined in the following
                descending order: By customer ship-to address (most specific),
                by customer, by customer type, by customer type pattern, by
                all customers. The lookup feature located to the right of the
                field leads to a Price List screen.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>ADD ITEM</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select to add another line item to the order.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
          </variablelist></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To define or maintain relationships for quotes, select the
  <guimenuitem>Relationships</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/quote_relationshipsTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Relationships tab</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When defining relationships for quotes, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If your site is configured to use projects, select a project
        number to associate with the quote. If a sales order is created from a
        converted quote—and the quote had a project number associated with
        it—then the project number from the originating quote will
        automatically be entered here. Once a project number is associated
        with a sales order, any work orders or purchase orders created by the
        sales order demand will automatically be linked to the same project
        number as the sales order. In this way, sales orders, work orders, and
        purchase orders may be linked to the same project.</para>
        <para role="xtprjaccnt">If you have the xTuple Project Accounting
        package installed—and you link a project to the quote—transactions
        related to the sales order will include the project number as the
        final segment of affected G/L account numbers. Account numbers related
        to the following transactions will include the project number as the
        final segment: issue to shipping, return stock, ship shipment, recall
        shipment, and post invoice.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>If your site is configured to create projects automatically
          whenever new sales orders or quotes are entered, the projects
          generated in this way will assume the number of the sales order or
          quote which caused their creation.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Opportunity</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select an opportunity to associate with the quote, using the
        lookup feature located to the right of the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Quote characteristics are user-defined definitions which may be used
  to provide additional layers of description about quotes. These descriptions
  are static and not processed by the system, but are useful for informational
  purposes. To enter characteristics associated with a quote, select the
  <guimenuitem>Characteristics</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="images/quote_characteristics.png" />
    </imageobject>
    <caption><para>Characteristics tab</para></caption>
  </mediaobject>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/characteristic.xml"
              xpointer="characteristiclWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
  <para>To add comments related to a quote, select the
  <guimenuitem>Comments</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/quote_comments.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Comments tab</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/comments.xml" xpointer="commentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
  <para>Order notes added to a quote are used for internal purposes only. To
  add order notes to a quote, select the <guimenuitem>Order
  Notes</guimenuitem> tab at the top of the New Quote screen. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/quote_notes.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Notes tab</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding order notes to a quote, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general notes related to the quote. These notes are for internal use
        only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        shipping notes related to the quote. These notes are for internal use
        only. Shipping notes are drawn from the Customer master—specifically
        from the <guimenuitem>Shipping Notes</guimenuitem> tab on the Ship-To
        Address master. The notes may vary depending on the ship-to address
        specified for the quote. These notes provide a mechanism for
        transferring shipping information from the Customer master to the
        quote.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To associate documents with a quote, select the
  <guimenuitem>Documents</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/quote_documents.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Documents tab</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/documents.xml" xpointer="documentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
  <para>To view email associated with a quote, select the
  <guimenuitem>Email</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/emailWidget.xml" xpointer="emailWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
  <xi:include href="quoteItem.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
