<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="quoteItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>quotes</primary>
      <secondary>creating line items for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Quote Item</title>
  <para>To create a new quote line item, select the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton>
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/quoteItem.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create new Quote Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new quote line item, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the order number specified in the header screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the line item number for the current line item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Refresh Order</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate you want the quote header to be refreshed
        immediately in the background. When the header is refreshed
        immediately, you will be able to see the rows of line items being
        added to the order. However, this feature can impact performance when
        entering quote line items. If you are experiencing performance issues,
        you should not select this option. The quote will be refreshed when
        you close the Quote Line Item screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the item you want to sell. The item
        list will contain sold items available for purchase by the specified
        customer. The list of available items may vary from customer to
        customer, depending on how pricing schedules are implemented at your
        site. Once an item number is entered, the inventory unit of measure
        and item description will automatically appear.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer P/N</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the customer part number (i.e., item alias) that
        corresponds to the item number entered in the <guilabel>Item
        Number</guilabel> field. If the alias is associated with a particular
        customer account, then the alias will only be displayed for sales
        orders and quotes entered for that customer. Item aliases are defined
        on the Item master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Substitute for</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Optional selection used solely for gathering information related
        to line item substitutions. This feature can be used, for example, to
        gather information about inventory shortages or customer first
        preferences. There is no impact on the system of using this feature.
        Its function is simply to store information in the database, where it
        may be accessed for reporting purposes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sites</primary>
          <secondary>sold from for quotes</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>selling sites for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the site the quote item is sold from. Items may be
        supplied to quotes from multiple item sites. After an item number is
        entered above, the system checks for available item sites for the
        item. Any item sites having the <guilabel>Sold From</guilabel> flag
        set on them will be selectable from this site list. By default, the
        item site having the highest ranking will be selected as the first
        available site. If more than one item site share a ranking of "1," the
        sites will be sorted in alphabetical order. Item site rankings are set
        on the Item Site master.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>If a preferred selling site is specified for the customer,
          then that site will be selected here by default. If the preferred
          selling site is not selected—and you think it should be—verify that
          the Item Site master for the line item in question is marked as a
          <guilabel>Sold From</guilabel> site.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="distribution">
      <term>ADV. ITEM SEARCH</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Advanced item search (AIS) is a feature designed specifically
        with distribution in mind. This feature allows distributors and end
        users to quickly search for both items and item aliases—as well as
        current inventory levels—filtering every keystroke. From this screen
        you also have the ability to create an item alias.</para>
        <note>
          <para>When using the AIS, you must enter at least three characters
          (i.e., numbers, letters or a combination of both) before any search
          results will be returned. This is for speed of performance
          reasons.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="distribution">
      <term>VENDOR CATALOG</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to use the External Vendor Catalog screen to view items
        as they appear within the various vendor catalogs you are subscribed
        to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="distribution">
      <term>VIEW IMAGE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view an item image, if available.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="distribution">
      <term>VIEW SPEC</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view a specification sheet for the item, if
        available.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Ordered</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the specified item being ordered.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The quantity ordered is based on the quantity unit of
          measure.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selling UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the unit of measure (UOM) to be used when selling the
        line item. Sold items may be assigned multiple selling UOMs. These
        alternate UOMs may be defined on the Item master. If a line item has
        no selling UOM defined, then the inventory UOM will be used here by
        default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Shipped</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the line item quantity shipped (if any) to date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust Discount %</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify here and apply any discount for specified customer for
        this quote. This is a discount off the regular customer price,
        obtained either from the Customer master or a pricing schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>line item pricing for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Net Unit Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the unit price for the quote item. By default, the
        system will choose the lower of the following two prices: A) The
        most-specific pricing schedule assignment or B) any sale in effect at
        the time of order entry. The specificity of pricing schedule
        assignments is determined in the following descending order: By
        customer ship-to address (most specific), by customer, by customer
        type, by customer type pattern, by all customers. The lookup feature
        located to the right of the field leads to a Price List screen.</para>
        <para>If your pricing schedule has multiple UOMs on it (or if several
        pricing schedules share the same level of price specificity, but they
        have different UOMs) then the UOM which matches the selected UOM will
        be chosen—that is, as long as the quantity break does not exceed the
        quantity being priced. If no entry matches the UOM with a quantity
        break less than the quantity being priced, then the lowest value price
        for any UOM will be chosen. To make sure a specific UOM is always
        chosen at the desired level of price specificity, then your pricing
        schedules should include at least one UOM with a quantity break of
        0.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>The system can be configured to prevent users from editing the
          net unit price. If your system is configured that way, the
          <guilabel>Net Unit Price</guilabel> field will not be editable. The
          unit cost and unit cost markup % values on the
          <guimenuitem>Details</guimenuitem> tab can also be configured to be
          editable with permission settings. These values, if changed, will
          adjust the net unit price.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Price UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The price unit of measure is the same as the selling UOM. If an
        item has selling UOMs defined, then the item may be sold and priced in
        these alternate UOMs. If no selling UOMs are defined, then the
        inventory UOM will be used here by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Extended Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the extended price. The extended price for a line item
        is based on the quantity ordered multiplied by the net unit
        price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scheduled Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The scheduled date is the date when the line item should be
        shipped. The user who enters the line item is responsible for
        determining the scheduled date. After entering the scheduled date, hit
        the <guibutton>TAB</guibutton> key on your keyboard to display values
        in the remaining display only fields.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The line item having the earliest scheduled date will
          determine the ship date for the sales order.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Promised Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the date when you promised delivery of the line item. This
        is an optional field. It will only be displayed on the screen if your
        system is configured to enable promise dates.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>When entering quotes you have the ability to view current supply
  considerations, including item availability and dependencies. You may also
  create replenishment orders (if they are needed) and change work order
  materials and operations.</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>availability of items for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Show Availability</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display availability information for the quote item in
        the following categories. If the feature is turned on, the
        availability totals will display only after a scheduled date has been
        entered for the line item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select option to view inventory availability. The display lists
        item availability for dependencies.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Available QOH</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the current available quantity on hand (QOH)
              value.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Allocated</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the quantity allocated to current sales orders
              and/or work orders in the system. An item is considered
              allocated to a sales order if a sales order line item exists for
              the item—and that line item has not yet been issued to shipping.
              An item is considered allocated to a work order if the item is a
              material requirement—and the material has not yet been issued to
              the work order. Once a sales order line item is saved, the
              <guilabel>Allocated</guilabel> value will increase by the
              quantity ordered.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Unallocated</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the QOH remaining after allocations have been
              accounted for, as in:</para>
              <para>QOH - Allocated Qty. = Unallocated Qty.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>On Order</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If the quote item is a manufactured item, the quantity
              ordered by current work orders will be displayed. If the quote
              item is a purchased item, the quantity ordered by current
              purchase orders will be displayed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Available</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the available quantity. Available quantity is
              determined using the following formula: Unallocated Qty. + On
              Order Qty. = Available Qty.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry role="standard">
            <term>Reserved</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the item quantity already reserved.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry role="standard">
            <term>Reservable</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the available item quantity remaining to be
              reserved.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Lead Time</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the item site lead time for the specified line
              item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>As Of</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Show availability using one of the following
              criteria:</para>
              <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Scheduled Date</term>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select to show projected availability based on the
                    scheduled date.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Lead Time</term>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select to show projected availability based on the
                    lead time specified in the Item Site master.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Show Dependencies as Indented BOM</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays component items associated with sold manufactured
              items in a nested list with a plus (<guibutton>+</guibutton>)
              sign located to the far left of the screen next to each line
              that may be expanded to lower levels. By clicking your mouse on
              a plus sign, you reveal lower levels of information related to
              the line item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Supply Order</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If you wish to maintain work order materials and operations for
        a manufactured item, select the <guilabel>Supply Order</guilabel>
        option on the <guimenuitem>Supply</guimenuitem> tab. The following
        will be displayed:<mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderItem_availabilitySupply.png"/>
            </imageobject>
            <caption><para>Supply Order information for manufactured
            item</para></caption>
          </mediaobject><note>
            <para>Supply orders are created as soon as a valid item, order
            quantity, and scheduled date are entered.</para>
          </note></para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>quotes</primary>
                <secondary>work orders generated by</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>work orders</primary>
                <secondary>generated by quotes</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>purchase requests</primary>
                <secondary>generated by quotes</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>quotes</primary>
                <secondary>purchase requests generated by</secondary>
              </indexterm>Create Work Order</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If the line item is a manufactured item, select this
              option to automatically create a work order for the specified
              quantity. For make-to-order manufactured items, this option will
              be selected automatically—as long as the item site's
              <guilabel>Stocked</guilabel> flag is set to "False." The work
              order will be created once you save the quote line item. Work
              orders created automatically from a quote will assume the same
              order number as the quote—even if that order number has already
              been used by a previous work order.</para>
              <para>For purchased items, the following two different options
              may appear, depending on how the item site for the item is set
              up: <guilabel>Create Purchase Request</guilabel> or
              <guilabel>Create Purchase Order</guilabel>. In either case, you
              will be given the option to override any item source price(s)
              which are in place. Also, linked purchase orders will be updated
              when quote details are changed. If your site is configured to
              use drop shipping, an additional <guilabel>Drop Ship</guilabel>
              flag will also be shown for linked purchase orders. The drop
              ship function will search for an existing purchase order linked
              to the quote with a matching ship-to address and add the line
              item to that order—or create a new order if none exists. Drop
              ship purchase orders inherit the ship-to address and contact
              information from the quote. Item sources must be defined for
              drop ship items—including each component of a kit item.</para>
              <tip>
                <para>This option will not be selected by default if the
                relevant item site has the <guilabel>Stocked</guilabel>
                setting selected.</para>
              </tip>
              <note>
                <para>When changing an existing quote line item, you will be
                asked for confirmation before the work order is
                rescheduled.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The number of the newly created work order is displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the line item number for the work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Status</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The work order status is displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The quantity ordered by the quote line item will display here.
        If the line item is a purchased item, purchase quantity information
        will appear instead. Whenever quote line item quantity is changed, the
        change will also be reflected in any linked work orders, purchase
        orders, or purchase requests.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Due Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The scheduled date of the quote line item will display here. If
        the line item is a purchased item, the purchasing due dates will
        appear instead.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sites</primary>
          <secondary>for make-to-order</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>quotes</primary>
          <secondary>supplying sites and</secondary>
        </indexterm>Supplying Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the site a corresponding work order would be supplied
        from. Work orders may only be created for manufactured items having a
        supplying site. Sites designated as <guilabel>Supplied from
        Site</guilabel> in the Item Site master for an item are considered
        supplying sites. If no supplying site exists for an item, a work order
        may not be created for the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>W/O Materials and Operations</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists an exploded view of the materials and operations
        for the work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>NEW MATL.</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to add materials to the BOM for the work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>NEW OPER.</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to add operations to the routing for this order
        item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>EDIT</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The materials and operations can be changed from this screen
        while placing the order. To do this, click the
        <guibutton>EDIT</guibutton> button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>DELETE</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>To remove materials or operations from the work order, highlight
        the line in the exploded work order view and click the
        <guibutton>DELETE</guibutton> button. Repeat for every line that needs
        to be removed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Rollup Prices</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If this option is selected, the price will be based on the price
        of all materials and operations. These material and operations prices
        can be edited from the Quote Item screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following will be displayed when the item is a purchased
  item:</para>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderItem_availabilitySupply2.png"/>
    </imageobject>
    <caption><para>Supply Order information for bought item</para></caption>
  </mediaobject>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Override Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If your site has enabled the <guilabel>Allow Inventory Receipt
        Cost Override</guilabel> option in the Inventory setup, then you will
        be able to override the default unit price here. This option applies
        only to average cost items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Drop Ship</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this option if the item should be automatically shipped
        when the purchase order receipt is posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To see a list of item sources, select the <guilabel>Item
  Sources</guilabel> option on the <guimenuitem>Supply</guimenuitem> tab.
  Available item sources will be displayed:</para>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderItem_availabilityItemSources.png"/>
    </imageobject>
    <caption><para>Available Item Sources</para></caption>
  </mediaobject>
  <para>To display a list of substitutes for the selected item or site with
  availability information, select the <guilabel>Substitutes</guilabel> option
  on the <guimenuitem>Supply</guimenuitem> tab. The following will be
  displayed:</para>
  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderItem_availabilitySubstitutes.png"/>
    </imageobject>
    <caption><para>Available Substitutes</para></caption>
  </mediaobject>
  <note>
    <para>Substitutes are defined on the Item master. Right-click on an item
    in the list and select <guimenuitem>Substitute</guimenuitem> to set the
    selected item as a line item substitute. The original line item will be
    moved to the <guilabel>Substitute For</guilabel> field.</para>
  </note>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>PREVIOUS</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view previous line items associated with the
        quote.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>NEW</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create a new quote line item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view the customer's sales history, select the
  <guimenuitem>History</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/quoteItem_history.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer History information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When viewing customer history, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Costs History</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display historical costing information for the item
        inside a specified date range. Purchased costs for the item will be
        shown, if the item has ever been received on a purchase order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales History</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display historical sales information for the item
        inside a specified date range. Invoices for the item will be shown, if
        the item has ever been sold previously.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>If an item has characteristics associated with it, you have the option
  of linking those characteristics to a sales order line item. And, in the
  case where sales order demand automatically generates either a purchase
  request or a work order, the characteristics defined here will be inherited
  by those subsequent orders.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>For configured items, an additional pricing field will be available
    on the Item Characteristic screen. This pricing information will be passed
    to sales order line items when particular configurations are sold. The
    price for configured items may vary depending on the characteristics
    selected at sales order entry time.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To associate characteristics with a quote line item, select the
  <guimenuitem>Characteristics</guimenuitem> tab at the bottom of the screen,
  as shown below:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/quoteItem_itemCharacteristicsTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Quote line item Characteristics</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/characteristic.xml"
              xpointer="characteristiclWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
  <para>To view costs or adjust tax information for a quote line item, select
  the <guimenuitem>Detail</guimenuitem> tab at the bottom of the screen, as
  shown below:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/quoteItem_costs.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Quote line item Detail</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When viewing costs or adjusting tax information for a quote line item,
  you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Unit Cost</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Depending on configuration settings, the unit cost displays the
        wholesale price, or the standard or average inventory cost.<note>
            <para>This value can be changed if the user has the necessary
            permissions. A change in this value will result in a new net unit
            price.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>List Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the sales list price per unit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the price given to the specified customer. Special
        customer prices can be set for individual customers or customer groups
        by using a pricing schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>discount percentages for</secondary>
        </indexterm>List Price Discount %</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the percentage discount off the list price. Indicates
        the difference between the list price for an item and the net unit
        price as a percentage. This is the margin between the net unit price
        and the list price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Unit Cost Markup %</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the effective markup which is based on the unit cost
        and net unit price values.<note>
            <para>Like the unit cost, this value can be changed by a user with
            sufficient permissions and such a change will adjust net unit
            price.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Margin</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the difference between extended price and extended
        cost.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The following tax options are available, should you need to
        override the tax selection settings for the line item:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Tax Type</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the tax type for the sales order item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Tax</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the amount of tax to be charged for the sales
              order line item quantity. To get a detailed view of the tax
              calculation, click on the <guibutton>Tax</guibutton> link using
              your mouse.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To enter notes related to a quote line item, select the
  <guimenuitem>Notes</guimenuitem> tab at the bottom of the screen, as shown
  below:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/quoteItem_notesTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Quote line item Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding notes related to a quote line item, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general notes related to the quote line item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If a quote item is marked to create a work order, the production
    notes for the created work order will contain the quote number, the
    customer name, and any additional quote line item notes.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To add comments related to a quote line item, select the
  <guimenuitem>Comments</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/quoteItem_commentsTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Quote line item Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>Whenever quote line items are created or their quantities are
    changed, the system will automatically generate a comment, which will
    appear in the list of line item comments.</para>
  </note>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/comments.xml" xpointer="commentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
  <xi:include href="priceListQuote.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
