<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="relocateInventory" role="standard">
  <title>Relocate Inventory</title>
  <para>To relocate inventory from one location to another, select the
  "Relocate Inventory" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/relocateInventory.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Relocate Inventory</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When relocating inventory from one location to another, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Transaction Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date you want the transaction to be posted to the
        general ledger. The current day's date will display by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the inventory you are
        relocating.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify site where inventory is located.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Set Target Location as Default on Move</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to change the default location for the item site to the
        target location once the <guibutton>MOVE</guibutton> button is selected. Performing this
        action means the target location will become the new default location
        for the item site. This option will only be available if your site is
        configured to allow on-the-fly changes to the default location. To
        learn more about this configuration option, see <xref
        linkend="configureIM" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Source</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists source locations for the specified item. Select
        the source location inventory is to be transferred from.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Target</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists target locations for the specified item. Select
        the target location inventory is to be transferred to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. to Move</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the specified item you want to move from
        the source location to the target location.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        comments related to the inventory relocation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>MOVE</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Moves specified quantity of inventory from source location to
        target location. Additional steps will be necessary if the specified
        item is stored in multiple locations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
