<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="reprintCreditMemos">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales credits</primary>
      <secondary>re-printing of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Re-Print Sales Credits</title>
  <para>To print a sales credit that was previously printed, go to
  <guimenuitem>Sales &gt; Billing &gt; Forms &gt;</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>
  Re-Print Sales Credits</guimenuitem>. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/reprintCreditMemos.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Re-Print Sales Credits</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When re-printing a sales credit, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <para role="xtconnect"><note>
      <para>If the customer specified on a sales credit has an EDI profile
      attached, you may encounter an EDI processing interface when printing
      it.</para>
    </note></para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Select Documents to reprint</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists previously printed sales credits. To select a
        sequence of sales credits, highlight the first in the sequence using
        your mouse button. Then, holding down the <guibutton>SHIFT</guibutton>
        key on your keyboard, highlight the last sales credit in the sequence.
        The entire sequence is now selected. To select sales credits that are
        out of sequence, highlight the first sales credit in the group. Then,
        holding down the <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key on your keyboard,
        highlight the next sales credit you want to select. Continue
        highlighting sales credits with the <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key
        depressed until all desired sales credits are selected. The entire
        group is now ready for re-printing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Copies</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify details for the sales credit copies you want to
        print.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term># of Copies</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the number of copies you want to print. To add a
              watermark or show/hide prices on the printed form, double-click
              on a copy line.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/watermarks.xml" xpointer="watermarksWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
