<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="reprintInvoices">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>invoices</primary>

      <secondary>re-printing of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Re-Print Invoices</title>

  <para>To print an invoice that was previously printed, select the
  <guimenuitem>Re-Print Invoices</guimenuitem> option. The following screen
  will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/reprintInvoices.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Re-Print Invoices</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When re-printing an invoice, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>

  <para role="xtconnect"><note>
      <para>If the customer specified on a credit memo has an EDI profile
      attached, you may encounter an EDI processing interface when printing
      it.</para>
    </note></para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Search for Invoice Number</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter an invoice number or regular expression. This field may be
        used independently or in conjunction with the date fields.</para>

        <tip>
          <para>The <guilabel>Invoice Number</guilabel> field supports pattern
          matching with regular expressions.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Only include Invoices with Balance</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include only those invoices having an open balance due
        in the display. If not selected, all invoices in the specified date
        range will be shown.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Start Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Invoices posted on and after this date will be displayed, unless
        the list is intentionally limited by information entered in the
        <guilabel>Search for Invoice Number</guilabel> field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>End Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Invoices posted on and before this date will be displayed,
        unless the list is intentionally limited by information entered in the
        <guilabel>Search for Invoice Number</guilabel> field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Select Documents to reprint</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists previously printed invoices. Highlight the
        individual invoice or group of invoices you want to re-print using
        your mouse button. To select a sequence of invoices, highlight the
        first in the sequence using your mouse button. Then, holding down the
        <guibutton>SHIFT</guibutton> key on your keyboard, highlight the last invoice in the
        sequence. The entire sequence is now selected. To select invoices that
        are out of sequence, highlight the first invoice in the group. Then,
        holding down the <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key on your keyboard, highlight the next invoice
        you want to select. Continue highlighting invoices with the <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key
        depressed until all desired invoices are selected. The entire group is
        now ready for re-printing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Copies</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify details for the invoice copies you want to print:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term># of Copies</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the number of copies you want to print. To add a
              watermark or show/hide prices on the printed form, double-click
              on a copy line.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <xi:include href="../widgets/watermarks.xml" xpointer="watermarksWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
