<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="returnAuthorizationItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>return authorizations</primary>
      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Return Authorization Item</title>
  <para>To add a new return authorization line item, select the
  <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/returnAuthorizationItem.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create new Return Authorization Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new return authorization line item, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Auth #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the return authorization number specified on the return
        authorization header.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the line item number for the current line item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Original Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the original sales order number if the line item has
        been imported into the return authorization. Importing return
        authorization line items from an original sales order is optional
        only. When line items are imported, the original quantities and
        pricing information are imported also.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Line #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the original sales order line item number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>New Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the order number for the new sales order created in
        support of the return authorization, if applicable. New sales orders
        will be automatically created for return authorizations having the
        following dispositions: replace, service, ship.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Line #</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the line item number for the new sales
              order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Disposition</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Line item dispositions are defaulted conditionally based on the
        return authorization's header-level disposition setting. However, you
        may manually over-ride the line level disposition when creating or
        return authorization line items provided you do so before a quantity
        has been authorized. The following options are available:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Credit</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to authorize the issuing of credit for the
              specified item quantity at the specified price. No return is
              required or expected.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Return</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to authorize the return of the specified item
              quantity at the specified price.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Replace</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to authorize the replacement of the specified item
              quantity.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Service</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to authorize the servicing of an item for the
              specified quantity. This disposition is valid only for job
              items. Price controls will be disabled for this disposition. A
              new sales order with linked work order(s) will be created to
              track work and shipping on the repair or service. The billing
              for service or repair work should be handled on the new sales
              order. Service or repair items should first be received by the
              return authorization. If the job item is lot/serial controlled,
              you will be prompted to assign lot/serial numbers when the
              receipt is posted. This assignment of lot/serial numbers can be
              simplified if you link authorized line items with existing
              lot/serial numbers at the line item level. For more information,
              please see <xref linkend="returnAuthItemLotSerial" />.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Ship</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to authorize a shipment of a specified quantity on
              a new sales order. The price controls will be disabled for this
              disposition. A new corresponding sales order and line will be
              created if one does not already exist. The billing should be
              handled on the new sales order. When there are line items on the
              return authorization having the disposition ship and the timing
              is <guilabel>Upon Receipt</guilabel>, then all the ship
              disposition line items will be created on the new sales order at
              the same time—at the moment when the return is first
              received.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Reason Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the reason for the return authorization. Reason codes
        are used to explain why a customer return is being authorized. The
        line item inherits the reason code from the header, but may be
        overridden at the line level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the item you want to authorize. The
        items you may select will vary depending on the line item disposition.
        For example, only job items may be selected for line items having the
        service disposition. Once an item number is entered, the inventory
        unit of measure and item description will automatically appear.</para>
        <para>If a returned item is an average-cost item, is linked to a sales
        order, and will result in an inventory receipt, the average cost for
        the item on the sales order will be pulled into the return line item
        as the default value. If there is no sales order to reference, the
        cost on the receipt will default to the standard cost for the item. If
        the item site is average cost, the unit cost will actually be editable
        on the return line item, so you can manually or automatically change
        the value to whatever makes sense for your business practice.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer P/N</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the customer part number (i.e., item alias) that
        corresponds to the item number entered in the <guilabel>Item
        Number</guilabel> field. The customer part number will display only if
        you enter an item alias in the <guilabel>Item Number</guilabel>
        field—or if an alias was used on the original sales order. To enter an
        item alias, place the cursor in the <guilabel>Item Number</guilabel>
        field and then use the keyboard shortcut <guibutton>CTRL +
        A</guibutton>. After you have entered a valid item alias, hit the
        <guibutton>TAB</guibutton> key. A list of items that use the specified
        item alias will be displayed. Select the desired item from the list.
        The item alias will display as the customer part number. Item aliases
        are defined on the Item master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sites</primary>
          <secondary>for receiving returns</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>return authorizations</primary>
          <secondary>receiving sites for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Recv. Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the site where you want the returned item quantity to be
        received.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sites</primary>
          <secondary>for shipping returns</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>return authorizations</primary>
          <secondary>shipping sites for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Ship Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the site where you want authorized return authorization
        quantity to be shipped from. This option is only available for line
        items having a disposition which requires creation of a new sales
        order (i.e., replace, service, ship).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Auth.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the specified item you want to
        authorize.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The quantity authorized is based on the quantity unit of
          measure.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the unit of measure (UOM) to be used when selling the
        line item. Sold items may be assigned multiple selling UOMs. These
        alternate UOMs may be defined on the Item master. You may also select
        a global conversion ratio here. Global conversions have the label
        <literal>Global</literal> appended to them. If a line item has no
        selling UOM defined, then the inventory UOM will be used here by
        default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Sold</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the line item quantity sold on the original sales order
        line if the line item was imported from an original sales
        order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Received</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the quantity received against the return authorization
        line item to date, if any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Shipped</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the return authorization line item quantity shipped to
        date, if any. This value applies to line items having a corresponding
        line on a new sales order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If the return authorizations involves giving a customer credit
        for the line item, then you may specify the following options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Restock Charge %</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the amount of any restock charge discount, if any.
              This field is only displayed when the return authorization is
              being applied to an original order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>sales orders</primary>
                <secondary>line item pricing for</secondary>
              </indexterm>Net Unit Price</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the net unit price for the sales order item. This
              information will be imported automatically for return
              authorizations linked to an original sales order if header
              disposition was credit or return when the order was imported. If
              there is no linked sales order, then the system will choose the
              lower of the following two prices: A) The most-specific pricing
              schedule assignment or B) any sale in effect at the time of
              order entry. The specificity of pricing schedule assignments is
              determined in the following descending order: by customer
              ship-to address (most specific), by customer, by customer type,
              by customer type pattern, by all customers. The lookup feature
              located to the right of the field leads to a Price List
              screen.</para>
              <para>If your pricing schedule has multiple UOMs on it (or if
              several pricing schedules share the same level of price
              specificity, but they have different UOMs) then the UOM which
              matches the selected UOM will be chosen—that is, as long as the
              quantity break does not exceed the quantity being priced. If no
              entry matches the UOM with a quantity break less than the
              quantity being priced, then the lowest value price for any UOM
              will be chosen. To make sure a specific UOM is always chosen at
              the desired level of price specificity, then your pricing
              schedules should include at least one UOM with a quantity break
              of 0.</para>
              <note>
                <para>The price controls will be automatically disabled for
                line items if a credit method has not been specified or for
                line items having the following dispositions: service and
                ship.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Price UOM</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The price UOM is the same as the selling UOM. If an item
              has selling UOMs defined, then you will be able to select from
              between the inventory UOM and any defined selling UOMs. If no
              selling UOMs have been defined, then the inventory UOM will be
              used here by default.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Extended Price</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the extended price. The extended price for a line
              item is based on the quantity ordered multiplied by the net unit
              price.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sale</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If the return authorizations involves re-selling the line item
        to the customer, then you may specify the following options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Discount %</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the amount of any discount, if any.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>sales orders</primary>
                <secondary>line item pricing for</secondary>
              </indexterm>Net Unit Price</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the net unit price for the sales order item. This
              information will be imported automatically for return
              authorizations linked to an original sales order if header
              disposition was credit or return when the order was imported. If
              there is no linked sales order, then the system will choose the
              lower of the following two prices: A) The most-specific pricing
              schedule assignment or B) any sale in effect at the time of
              order entry. The specificity of pricing schedule assignments is
              determined in the following descending order: by customer
              ship-to address (most specific), by customer, by customer type,
              by customer type pattern, by all customers. The lookup feature
              located to the right of the field leads to a Price List
              screen.</para>
              <para>If your pricing schedule has multiple UOMs on it—or if
              several pricing schedules share the same level of price
              specificity, but they have different UOMs—then the UOM which
              matches the selected UOM will be chosen—that is, as long as the
              quantity break does not exceed the quantity being priced. If no
              entry matches the UOM with a quantity break less than the
              quantity being priced, then the lowest value price for any UOM
              will be chosen. To make sure a specific UOM is always chosen at
              the desired level of price specificity, then your pricing
              schedules should include at least one UOM with a quantity break
              of zero.</para>
              <note>
                <para>The price controls will be automatically disabled for
                line items if a credit method has not been specified or for
                line items having the following dispositions: service and
                ship.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Price UOM</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The price UOM is the same as the selling UOM. If an item
              has selling UOMs defined, then you will be able to select from
              between the inventory UOM and any defined selling UOMs. If no
              selling UOMs have been defined, then the inventory UOM will be
              used here by default.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Extended Price</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the extended price. The extended price for a line
              item is based on the quantity ordered multiplied by the net unit
              price.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/returnAuthorizationItem_saleTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Return Authorization Sales tab</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scheduled Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The scheduled date is the date when the line item quantity
        should be shipped. The user who enters the line item is responsible
        for determining the scheduled date. After entering the scheduled date,
        hit the <guibutton>TAB</guibutton> key on your keyboard to display
        values in the remaining display only fields.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Warranty</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the line item is a warranty item. If selected, the
        cost of warranty account will be used when shipping the line item,
        instead of the cost of sales account. It will also be used when
        receiving warranty items through a return authorization, instead of
        the cost of returns account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>When entering return authorizations you have the ability to view
  current availability for line items. You may also create replenishment
  orders if they are needed.</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Availability</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to display item availability
        information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>return authorizations</primary>
          <secondary>availability of items for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Availability</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If showing item availability, the following information will be
        shown:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Available QOH</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the current available quantity on hand (QOH)
              value.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Allocated</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the quantity allocated to current sales orders
              and/or work orders in the system. An item is considered
              allocated to a sales order if a sales order line item exists for
              the item—and that line item has not yet been issued to shipping.
              An item is considered allocated to a work order if the item is a
              material requirement—and the material has not yet been issued to
              the work order. Once the current line item is saved, the
              allocated value will increase by the quantity ordered.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Unallocated</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the QOH remaining after allocations have been
              accounted for, as in:</para>
              <para>QOH - Allocated Qty. = Unallocated Qty.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>On Order</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>If the line item is a manufactured item, the quantity
              ordered by current work orders will be displayed. If the line
              item is a purchased item, the quantity ordered by current
              purchase orders will be displayed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Available</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the available quantity. Available quantity is
              determined using the following formula: Unallocated Qty. + On
              Order Qty. = Available Qty.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Lead Time</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the item site lead time for the specified line
              item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
        <tip>
          <para>The <guilabel>Show Availability</guilabel> feature can be
          turned on or off by default at the system level. If the feature is
          turned on, the availability totals will display only after a
          scheduled date has been entered for the line item.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>return authorizations</primary>
          <secondary>work orders generated by</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>work orders</primary>
          <secondary>generated by return authorizations</secondary>
        </indexterm> Create Work Order</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If the line item is a manufactured item, select this option to
        automatically create a work order for the specified quantity. For
        make-to-order manufactured items, this option will be selected
        automatically. A work order will be created to meet the return
        authorization demand once you save the line item to the order. An item
        is designated as make-to-order if the <guilabel>Create W/Os to meet
        sales Demand</guilabel> flag on the Item Site master is selected. A
        work order created automatically from a return authorization line item
        will assume the same order number as the new sales order the return
        authorization line item is associated with—even if that order number
        has already been used by a previous work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>W/O Qty.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The quantity ordered by the line item will display here.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>W/O Due Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the scheduled date of the line item will display
        here.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>W/O Status</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the current status of the work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>For lot/serial items, you have the option to authorize only specific
  lot/serial quantities. The <guimenuitem>Lot/Serial</guimenuitem> tab will
  only be enabled for lot/serial items. To authorize specific lot/serial
  quantities, select the <guimenuitem>Lot/Serial</guimenuitem> tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/returnAuthorizationItem_lotserial.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Return Authorization Lot/Serial tab</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When authorizing specific lot/serial quantities, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Lot/Serial</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays any lot/serial quantities specifically authorized for
        the return authorization.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Authorize only these Lot/Serial Numbers</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enable the lot/serial selection process. When this
        option is selected, you will be able to select specific lot/serial
        quantities for authorization.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view costs or adjust tax information for a return authorization
  line item, select the <guimenuitem>Detail</guimenuitem> tab at the bottom of
  the screen, as shown below:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/returnAuthorizationItem_detail.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Return Authorization line item Detail tab</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When viewing costs or adjusting tax information for a return
  authorization line item, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Unit Cost (Inv. UOM)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the standard cost per unit based on the inventory
        UOM.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>List Price</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the sales list price per unit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>discount percentages for</secondary>
        </indexterm>List Discount %</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the percentage discount off the list price. Indicates
        the difference between the list price for an item and the net unit
        price as a percentage. This is the margin between the net unit price
        and the list price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The following tax options are available, should you need to
        override the <guilabel>Tax Selection</guilabel> settings for the line
        item:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Tax Type</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the tax type for the line item. If the Item master
              does not have a tax type for the return authorization's tax
              authority, then no tax will be charged.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guibutton>Tax</guibutton></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the amount of tax to be charged for the line item
              quantity. To get a detailed view of the tax calculation, click
              on the <guibutton>Tax</guibutton> link using your mouse.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To enter notes related to a return authorization line item, select the
  <guimenuitem>Notes</guimenuitem> tab at the bottom of the screen, as shown
  below:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/returnAuthorizationItem_comments.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Return Authorization line item Notes tab</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding notes related to a return authorization line item, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general notes related to the return authorization line item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If a return authorization item is marked to create a work order, the
    production notes for the created work order will contain the sales order
    number, the customer name, and any additional sales order line item
    notes.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To define an alternate cost of sales account for a return
  authorization line item, select the <guimenuitem>Accounting</guimenuitem>
  tab at the bottom of the screen, as shown below:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/returnAuthorizationItem_accounts.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Return Authorization line item Accounting tab</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When defining an alternate cost of sales account for a return
  authorization line item, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Alternate cost of sales Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify an alternate account to be used for the cost of sales.
        The account you specify will be used instead of the typical account
        pre-defined in the sales account assignments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add comments to a return authorization line item, select the
  <guimenuitem>Comments</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/returnAuthorizationItem_commentsTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Return Authorization line item Comments tab</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/comments.xml" xpointer="commentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
  <xi:include href="returnAuthItemLotSerial.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
