<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="salesOrderItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales orders</primary>

      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Sales Order Item</title>

  <para>To add a new sales order line item, select the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderItem.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Create New Sales Order Line Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating a new sales order line item, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the sales order number specified on the sales order
        header.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the line item number for the current line item.</para>

        <note>
          <para>If the sales order was generated from a return authorization,
          the return authorization number and corresponding Line Number will
          also be displayed at the top of the screen.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Refresh Order</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate you want the Sales Order header to be
        refreshed immediately in the background. When the header is refreshed
        immediately, you will be able to see the rows of line items being
        added to the order. However, this feature can impact performance when
        entering sales order line items. If you are experiencing performance
        issues, you should not select this option. The sales order will be
        refreshed when you close the Sales Order Line Item screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Return Auth.#</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the return authorization number associated with the
        sales order, if any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Line #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the line number for the item listed on the return
        authorization, if any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the item you want to sell. The item
        list will contain sold items available for sale to the specified
        customer. The list of available items may vary from customer to
        customer, depending on how pricing schedules are implemented at your
        site. Once an item number is entered, the inventory unit of measure
        and item description will automatically appear.</para>

        <note>
          <para><indexterm significance="normal">
              <primary>job items</primary>

              <secondary>creating demand for</secondary>
            </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
              <primary>sales orders</primary>

              <secondary>job items and</secondary>
            </indexterm>If the item is a job item, a linked work order will
          automatically be created. Creating a sales order for job items is
          the only way to create a job item work order. Production for job
          item work orders is posted automatically when the linked sales order
          item is linked to shipping.</para>
        </note>

        <tip>
          <para>Kit items must be shipped complete before they can be
          invoiced.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer P/N</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the customer part number (i.e., item alias) that
        corresponds to the item number entered in the Item Number field. If
        the alias is associated with a particular customer account, then the
        alias will only be displayed for sales orders and quotes entered for
        that customer. Item aliases are defined on the Item master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Substitute for</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Optional selection used solely for gathering information related
        to sales order line item substitutions. This feature can be used, for
        example, to gather information about inventory shortages or customer
        first preferences. There is no impact on the system of using this
        feature. Its function is simply to store information in the database,
        where it may be accessed for reporting purposes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sites</primary>

          <secondary>sold from for sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>

          <secondary>selling sites for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the site the sales order item is sold from. Items may be
        supplied to sales orders from multiple item sites. After an item
        Number is entered above, the system checks for available item sites
        for the item. Any item sites having the "Sold from" flag set on them
        will be selectable from this site list. By default, the item site
        having the highest Ranking will be selected as the first available
        site. If more than one item site share a Ranking of "1," the sites
        will be sorted in alphabetical order. Item site Rankings are set on
        the Item Site master.</para>

        <tip>
          <para>If a preferred Selling site is specified for the customer,
          then that site will be selected here by default. If the preferred
          Selling site is not selected—and you think it should be—verify that
          the Item Site master for the line item in question is marked as a
          "Sold from" site.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="distribution">
      <term>ADV. ITEM SEARCH</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Advanced Item Search (AIS) is a feature designed specifically
        with distribution in mind. This feature allows distributors and end
        users to quickly search for both items and item aliases?as well as
        current inventory levels?filtering every keystroke. From this screen
        you also have the ability to create an item alias.</para>

        <note>
          <para>When using the Advanced Item Search, you must enter at least
          three characters (i.e., numbers, letters or a combination of both)
          before any search results will be returned. This is for speed of
          performance reasons.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="distribution">
      <term>VENDOR CATALOG</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to use the External Vendor Catalog screen to view items
        as they appear within the various vendor catalogs you are subscribed
        to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="distribution">
      <term>VIEW IMAGE</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view an item image, if available.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="distribution">
      <term>VIEW SPEC</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view a specification sheet for the item, if
        available.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Ordered</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the specified item being ordered.</para>

        <para role="standard"><note>
            <para>If the sales order item is being edited and the quantity
            ordered is reduced then all reservations for the line item will be
            removed.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. UOM</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the unit of measure (UOM) to be used when selling the
        line item. Sold items may be assigned multiple Selling UOMs. These
        alternate UOMs may be defined on the Item master. You may also select
        a global conversion ratio here. Global conversions have the label
        <literal>Global</literal> appended to them. If a line item has no
        Selling UOM defined, then the inventory UOM will be used here by
        default.<tip>
            <para>When sales orders are entered, the system will search for
            quantity break matches between the sales order item and any
            relevant pricing schedule. If duplicate quantity breaks are found,
            the lowest price for the given quantity will be used.</para>
          </tip></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Shipped</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the line item quantity shipped to date, if any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>List Price</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays either the list price found on the Item master or the
        alternate list price, if alternate List Pricing is being used. To
        learn more about how alternate List Pricing works, please see the
        <ulink
        url="https://xtupleuniversity.xtuple.com/library/articles/alternate-list-pricing">Alternate
        List Pricing article</ulink> at xTupleU.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount %</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>If standard List Pricing is being used, this field will display
        the default discount percentage (if any) for the specified customer,
        as defined on the Customer master. On the other hand, if alternate
        List Pricing is being used, the field will display the percentage
        difference between the alternate list price and the net unit price.
        You also have the option to manually override the discount
        percentage.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Price</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the best applicable price from all available Pricing
        Schedules.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount %</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the percentage difference between the customer price
        and the net unit price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>

          <secondary>line item pricing for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Net Unit Price</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays either the list price minus the customer Discount or
        the price from any applicable pricing schedule or Sale. If a pricing
        schedule is in effect, the <emphasis>most specific</emphasis> pricing
        schedule assignment will be used. The specificity of pricing schedule
        assignments is determined in the following descending order: by
        customer ship-to address (most specific), by customer, by customer
        type, by customer type pattern, by all customers. The lookup feature
        located to the right of the field leads to a Price List screen.</para>

        <tip>
          <para>The system can be configured to prevent users from editing the
          net unit price. If your system is configured that way, the Net Unit
          Price field will not be editable. The unit cost and unit cost Markup
          % values on the Details tab can also be configured to be editable
          with permission settings. These values, if changed, will adjust the
          net unit price.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Price UOM</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The price unit of measure is the same as the Selling UOM. If an
        item has Selling UOMs defined, then the item may be sold and priced in
        these alternate UOMs. You may also select a global conversion ratio
        here. Global conversions have the label <literal>Global</literal>
        appended to them. If no Selling UOMs are defined, then the inventory
        UOM will be used here by default.</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>If your pricing schedule has multiple UOMs on it (or if
            several pricing schedules share the same level of price
            specificity, but they have different UOMs) then the UOM which
            matches the selected UOM will be chosen—that is, as long as the
            quantity break does not exceed the quantity being priced. If no
            entry matches the UOM with a quantity break less than the quantity
            being priced, then the lowest value price for any UOM will be
            chosen. To make sure a specific UOM is always chosen at the
            desired level of price specificity, then your pricing schedules
            should include at least one UOM with a quantity break of 0.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Extended Price</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the extended price. The extended price for a line item
        is based on the quantity ordered multiplied by the net unit
        price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scheduled Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The scheduled date is the date when the line item quantity
        should be shipped. The user who enters the line item is responsible
        for determining the scheduled date. After entering the scheduled date,
        hit the TAB key on your keyboard to display values in the remaining
        display only fields.</para>

        <note>
          <para>The sales order item having the earliest scheduled date will
          determine the ship date for the sales order.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Promised Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the date when you promised delivery of the line item. This
        is an optional field. It will only be displayed on the screen if your
        system is configured to enable promise dates.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Warranty</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the line item is a warranty item. If selected, the
        cost of Warranty account will be used when shipping the line item,
        instead of the cost of sales account. It will also be used when
        receiving warranty items through a return authorization, instead of
        the P/O Liability Clearing account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>When entering sales orders you have the ability to view current supply
  considerations, including item availability and dependencies. You may also
  create replenishment orders (if they are needed) and change work order
  materials and operations.</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>

          <secondary>availability of items for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Show Availability</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display availability information for the sales order
        item in the following categories. If the feature is turned on, the
        availability totals will display only after a scheduled date has been
        entered for the line item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select option to view inventory availability. The display lists
        item availability for dependencies.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Available QOH</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the current available quantity on hand (QOH)
              value.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Allocated</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the quantity allocated to current sales orders
              and/or work orders in the system. An item is considered
              allocated to a sales order if a sales order line item exists for
              the item—and that line item has not yet been issued to shipping.
              An item is considered allocated to a work order if the item is a
              material requirement—and the material has not yet been issued to
              the work order. Once the current sales order line item is saved,
              the "Allocated" value will increase by the quantity
              ordered.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Unallocated</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the QOH remaining after allocations have been
              accounted for, as in: QOH - Allocated Qty. = Unallocated
              Qty.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>On Order</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>If the sales order item is a manufactured item, the
              quantity ordered by current work orders will be displayed. If
              the sales order item is a purchased item, the quantity ordered
              by current purchase orders will be displayed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Available</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the available quantity. Available quantity is
              determined using the following formula: Unallocated Qty. + On
              Order Qty. = Available Qty.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry role="standard">
            <term>Reserved</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the item quantity already reserved.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry role="standard">
            <term>Reservable</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the available item quantity remaining to be
              reserved.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Lead Time</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the item site Lead Time for the specified Line
              item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>As Of</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Show Availability using one of the following
              criteria:</para>

              <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Scheduled Date</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select to show projected availability based on the
                    scheduled date.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>

                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Lead Time</term>

                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select to show projected availability based on the
                    Lead Time specified in the Item Site master.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Show Dependencies as Indented BOM</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays component items associated with sold manufactured
              items in a nested list with a plus ("+") sign located to the far
              left of the screen next to each line that may be expanded to
              lower levels. By clicking your mouse on a plus sign, you reveal
              lower levels of information related to the line item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Supply Order</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>If you wish to maintain work order materials and operations for
        a manufactured item, select the "Supply Order" option on the "Supply"
        tab. The following will be displayed:<mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderItem_availabilitySupply.png"/>
            </imageobject>

            <caption><para>Supply Order Information For Manufactured
            Item</para></caption>
          </mediaobject><note>
            <para>Supply orders are created as soon as a valid item, order
            quantity, and scheduled date are entered.</para>
          </note></para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>sales orders</primary>

                <secondary>work orders generated by</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>work orders</primary>

                <secondary>generated by sales orders</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>purchase requests</primary>

                <secondary>generated by sales orders</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>sales orders</primary>

                <secondary>purchase requests generated by</secondary>
              </indexterm>Create Work Order</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>If the line item is a manufactured item, select this
              option to automatically create a work order for the specified
              quantity. For make-to-order manufactured items, this option will
              be selected automatically?as long as the item site's "Stocked"
              flag is set to "False." The work order will be created once you
              save the sales order line item. Work orders created
              automatically from a sales order will assume the same order
              number as the sales order—even if that order number has already
              been used by a previous work order.</para>

              <para>For purchased items, the following two different options
              may appear, depending on how the item site for the item is set
              up: "Create Purchase Request" or "Create Purchase Order." In
              either case, you will be given the option to override any item
              source price(s) which are in place. Also, linked purchase orders
              will be updated when sales order details are changed. If your
              site is configured to use drop shipping, an additional "Drop
              Ship" flag will also be shown for linked purchase orders. The
              drop ship function will search for an existing purchase order
              linked to the sales order with a matching ship-to address and
              add the line item to that order—or create a new order if none
              exists. Drop ship purchase orders inherit the ship-to address
              and contact information from the sales order. Item sources must
              be defined for drop ship items—including each component of a Kit
              item.</para>

              <tip>
                <para>This option will not be selected by default if the
                relevant item site has the "Stocked" setting selected.</para>
              </tip>

              <note>
                <para>When changing an existing sales order line item, you
                will be asked for confirmation before the work order is
                rescheduled.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The number of the newly created work order is displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Line item number for the work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Status</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The work order status is displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty.</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The quantity ordered by the sales order line item will display
        here. If the line item is a purchased item, purchase quantity
        information will appear instead. Whenever sales order line item
        quantity is changed, the change will also be reflected in any linked
        work orders, purchase orders, or purchase requests.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Due Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The scheduled date of the sales order line item will display
        here. If the line item is a purchased item, the purchasing due dates
        will appear instead.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sites</primary>

          <secondary>for make-to-order</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>

          <secondary>supplying sites and</secondary>
        </indexterm>Supplying Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the site a corresponding work order would be supplied
        from. Work orders may only be created for manufactured items having a
        supplying site. Sites designated as "Supplied at" sites in the Item
        Site master for an item are considered supplying sites. If no
        supplying site exists for an item, a work order may not be created for
        the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>W/O Materials and Operations</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists an exploded view of the materials and operations
        for the work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>NEW MATL.</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to add materials to the BOM for the work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>NEW OPER.</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to add operations to the routing for this order item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>EDIT</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The materials and operations can be changed from this screen
        while placing the order. To do this, click the <guibutton>EDIT</guibutton> button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>DELETE</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>To remove materials or operations from the work order, highlight
        the line in the exploded work order view and click the <guibutton>DELETE</guibutton> button.
        Repeat for every line that needs to be removed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Rollup Prices</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>If this option is selected, the price will be based on the price
        of all materials and operations. These material and operations prices
        can be edited from the Sales Order Item screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following will be displayed when the item is a purchased
  item:</para>

  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderItem_availabilitySupply2.png"/>
    </imageobject>

    <caption><para>Supply Order Information For Bought Item</para></caption>
  </mediaobject>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Override Price</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>If your site has enabled the "Allow Inventory Receipt Cost
        Override" option in the Inventory setup, then you will be able to
        override the default unit price here. This option applies only to
        average cost items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Drop Ship</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select this option if the item should be automatically shipped
        when the purchase order receipt is posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To see a list of item sources, select the "Item Sources" option on the
  "Supply" tab. Available item sources will be displayed:</para>

  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderItem_availabilityItemSources.png"/>
    </imageobject>

    <caption><para>Available Item Sources</para></caption>
  </mediaobject>

  <para>To display a list of substitutes for the selected item or site with
  availability information, select the "Substitutes" option on the "Supply"
  tab. The following will be displayed:</para>

  <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderItem_availabilitySubstitutes.png"/>
    </imageobject>

    <caption><para>Available Substitutes</para></caption>
  </mediaobject>

  <note>
    <para>Substitutes are defined on the Item master. Right-click on an item
    in the list and select <guimenuitem>Substitute</guimenuitem> to set the
    selected item as a line item substitute. The original line item will be
    moved to the <guilabel>Substitute For</guilabel> field.</para>
  </note>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>PREVIOUS</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view previous line items associated with the sales
        order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>CANCEL ITEM</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to cancel the current sales order line item. Records of
        canceled line items will be retained for informational purposes. To
        view canceled line items associated with a sales order, select the
        "Show Canceled Line Items" option on the Sales Order header's "Line
        Items tab.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To view historical information related to the sales order line item,
  select the "History" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderItem_costsHistory.png"/>
      </imageobject>

      <caption><para>Costs History</para></caption>
    </mediaobject></para>

  <para>When viewing costing history for the sales order line item, you will
  be presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Start Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Purchase orders entered on or after this date will be included
        in the display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>End Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Purchase orders entered on or before this date will be included
        in the display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Costing Method:</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the item's inventory costing method (i.e., standard,
        average, or job).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Unit Cost</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the item's inventory unit cost.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Purchase Orders</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists purchase orders for the item, using the specified
        date range.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To view sales history for the sales order line item, select the "Sales
  History" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderItem_salesHistory.png"/>
      </imageobject>

      <caption><para>Sales History</para></caption>
    </mediaobject></para>

  <para>When viewing sales history for the sales order line item, you will be
  presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Start Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Invoices entered on or after this date will be included in the
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>End Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Invoices entered on or before this date will be included in the
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Orders</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total number of historical sales orders for the
        item, within the date range specified.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. per Order</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the calculated average quantity per historical sales
        order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Costing Method:</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the item's inventory costing method (i.e., standard,
        average, or job).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Unit Cost</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the item's inventory unit cost.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Purchase Orders</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists invoices for the item, using the specified date
        range.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>If an item has characteristics associated with it, you have the option
  of linking those characteristics to a sales order line item. And, in the
  case where sales order demand automatically generates either a purchase
  request or a work order, the characteristics defined here will be inherited
  by those subsequent orders.</para>

  <tip>
    <para>For configured items, an additional pricing field will be available
    on the Item Characteristic screen. This pricing information will be passed
    to sales order line items when particular configurations are sold. The
    price for configured items may vary depending on the characteristics
    selected at sales order entry time.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>To associate characteristics with a sales order line item, select the
  "Item Characteristics" tab at the bottom of the screen, as shown
  below:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderItem_itemCharacteristicsTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Sales Order line item Characteristics</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When selecting or editing characteristics for a sales order line item,
  you are presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name of any item characteristics associated with
        the item. Characteristics defined as item characteristics may be
        associated with items on the Item master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Value</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the default value associated with an item
        characteristic, but permits you to specify an alternate value. When
        associating characteristic values with a sales order line item, you
        have four options: 1) Select the default value; 2) select an alternate
        pre-defined value; 3) manually enter a new value in place of the
        pre-defined value; or 4) make no selection. Making no selection means
        the characteristics will not be associated with the sales order line
        item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Base Price</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>If the sales order item is a configured item (i.e., job or
        Reference item), the "Base Price" option will be shown.
        Characteristics associated with configured items may have additional
        list prices associated with them. As a result, when characteristics
        are added to a sales order item, the overall price of the item may
        increase. The base price shows the price before any characteristic
        list prices have been added to the net unit price. To learn more about
        adding price characteristics to configured items, see <xref
        linkend="configItemChar"/>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>During the creation of a new sales order for a configured item, the
    work order is imploded and the characteristics will remain enabled and may
    be edited. When the <guibutton>SAVE</guibutton> button is clicked, the work order characteristics
    are updated and the work order is exploded. To edit the sales order item
    for a configured item, the work order needs to be manually imploded first.
    This will enable the characteristics and allow editing. When the <guibutton>SAVE</guibutton>
    button is clicked, the work order characteristics will be updated and the
    work order exploded.</para>
  </note>

  <para>To view costs or adjust tax information for a sales order line item,
  select the "Detail" tab at the bottom of the screen, as shown below:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderItem_costs.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Sales Order Line Item Detail</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When viewing costs or adjusting tax information for a sales order line
  item, you are presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Unit Cost</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Depending on configuration settings, the unit cost displays the
        wholesale price or the standard or average inventory cost. For average
        cost items having zero QOH, the standard cost will be used instead of
        the average cost, if it exists.<note>
            <para>This value can be changed if the user has the necessary
            permissions. A change in this value will result in a new net unit
            price.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>List Price</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the sales list price per unit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer Price</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the price given to the specified customer. Special
        customer prices can be set for individual customers or customer Groups
        by using a pricing schedule.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>

          <secondary>discount percentages for</secondary>
        </indexterm>List Price Discount %</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the percentage discount off the list price. Indicates
        the difference between the list price for an item and the net unit
        price as a percentage. This is the margin between the net unit price
        and the list price.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Unit Cost Markup %</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the effective markup which is based on the unit cost
        and net unit price values.<note>
            <para>Like the unit cost, this value can be changed by a user with
            sufficient permissions and such a change will adjust net unit
            price.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Margin</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the difference between extended price and extended
        cost.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The following tax options are available, should you need to
        override the Tax Selection settings for the line item:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Tax Type</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the tax type for the sales order item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Tax</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the amount of tax to be charged for the sales
              order line item quantity. To get a detailed view of the tax
              calculation, click on the Tax link using your mouse.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To enter notes related to a sales order line item, select the "Notes"
  tab at the bottom of the screen, as shown below:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderItem_notesTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Sales Order Line Item Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When adding notes related to a sales order line item, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general notes related to the sales order line item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
    <para>If a sales order item is marked to create a work order, the
    Production notes for the created work order will contain the sales order
    number, the customer Name, and any additional sales order line item
    notes.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>To add comments related to a sales order line item, select the
  "Comments" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderItem_commentsTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Sales Order Line Item Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <note>
    <para>Whenever sales order line items are created or their quantities are
    changed, the system will automatically generate a comment, which will
    appear in the list of line item comments.</para>
  </note>

  <xi:include href="../widgets/comments.xml" xpointer="commentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

  <para>To define an alternate cost of sales account for a sales order Line
  item, select the "Accounting" tab at the bottom of the screen, as shown
  below:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderItem_costofsalesTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Sales Order Line Item Accounting</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When defining an alternate cost of sales account or alternate Revenue
  account for a sales order line item, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Alternate Cost of Sales Account</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify an alternate account to be used for the cost of sales.
        This account will be used instead of the typical account pre-defined
        in the sales accounts assignments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Alternate Revenue Account</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify an alternate account to be used as the Revenue account.
        This account will be used instead of the typical account predefined in
        the receivables assignments.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <xi:include href="priceList.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
