<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="salesOrderSimple">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales orders</primary>
      <secondary>creating new simple</secondary>
    </indexterm>New Simple Sales Order</title>
  <para>To support environments where you don't need complex sales orders
  (e.g., counter sales, retail, etc.), xTuple offers a simple sales order. As
  its name implies, the simple sales order provides an easy-to-use interface
  for quickly processing simple sales orders. The screen provides an
  alternative to the regular sales order entry screen and may be used in
  conjunction with it. Because the simple sales order is optional, it must be
  specifically enabled in the Sales module configuration before it can be
  used.</para>
  <para>To create a new simple sales order, select the "New Simple" option.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderSimple.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Simple Sales Order</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new simple sales order, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Next available sales order number will automatically display,
        unless your system requires you to enter sales order numbers manually.
        Default values and input parameters for sales order numbers are
        configurable at the system level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. PO #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a customer purchase order number, as needed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the supplied from site for the Order. By default, the
        logged in User's preferred site will be used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Zone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the tax zone for the Order. If the default customer (or
        other specified customer) does not have a default Ship-to Address and
        associated tax zone, then the tax zone for the site will be
        used.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the customer associated with the sales order. By
        default, the cash-paying customer defined in your Sales module
        configuration will be displayed here. However, you may easily select a
        different, pre-existing customer?or enter a new customer record?during
        order entry.</para>
        <note>
          <para>If the specified customer has exceeded their credit limit, the
          screen will revert to using the default cash-paying customer.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the number of the preferred Ship-To Address. Customers may
        maintain multiple Ship-To Addresses.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the item you want to sell. The item
        list will contain sold items available for sale to the specified
        customer. The list of available items may vary from customer to
        customer, depending on how Pricing Schedules are implemented at your
        site.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the specified item being ordered. By
        default, the quantity entered will be "1." However, you may manually
        override the default quantity.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>HOLD ORDER</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to save the Order and save it for processing later. You
        may be prompted to print a sales order acknowledgement form if your
        Sales module is configured to do so.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW ORDER</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enter a new simple sales order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To process payment for the Order, select the "Payment" tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderSimpleCCPay.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Credit Card Payment</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>When processing a credit card payment for the Order, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Credit Card</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>List will display credit cards already on file for the customer,
        if any. Highlight the credit card you want to use for the transaction
        prior to selecting the CHARGE button. If none exist, you can create a
        new credit card record by selecting the NEW button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Amount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The Order total will be displayed here.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CVV Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the Card Verification Value (CVV) Code found on the back
        of the specified credit card. This may be an optional feature at your
        site. Contact your Systems Administrator for details.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>NEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to create a new credit card record for the
        customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>VIEW</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a credit card record on file and then select this
        button to view the credit card information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CHARGE CC AND COMPLETE ORDER</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to charge the highlighted credit card and complete the
        Order. You may be prompted to print a shipping Packing List and/or an
        invoice if your Sales module is configured to do so.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To process a cash payment for the Order, select the "Cash" tab. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrderSimpleCashPay.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Cash Payment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>When processing a Cash Receipt for the Order, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Total</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total for the Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Balance</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the balance due for the Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Available Credit</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the value of the customer's outstanding credits, if
        any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Amount Received</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of Cash being received against the Order. If
        the customer's credit status is good and the Funds Type is set to "On
        Account," this field will be disabled.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Funds Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the type of funds being used for the Cash Receipt.
        Choose from the following types: On account, Cash, Check, Certified
        Check, Wire Transfer, and Other.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The "On Account" Funds Type will only be shown if the
          specified customer has not exceeded their credit limit. If they
          have, the type will be hidden and the default cash-paying customer
          will be used instead.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Payment/Document #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use this field to enter the customer's Payment Number,
        transaction number, credit card number, or any other Document Number
        you wish to associate with the Cash Receipt.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Payment/Document Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use this field to specify the date on the payment you received.
        This is the Document date used when running the Receivables aging
        report.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the bank account you want to post the Cash Receipt to.
        The Asset account used for the selected bank account is specified on
        the Bank Account master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following button is unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>POST PAYMENT AND COMPLETE ORDER</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to post the Cash Receipt and complete the Order. You may
        be prompted to print a shipping Packing List and/or an invoice if your
        Sales module is configured to do so.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
