<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="salesOrder">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales orders</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>New Sales Order</title>
  <para>Creating a new sales order requires a detailed mix of customer, sales
  representative, and shipping information. To access the sales order area,
  select the <guimenuitem>New Sales Order</guimenuitem> option. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrder.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Sales Order</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>Be sure to close all sales order windows before exiting the system.
    This will prevent the creation of orphaned sales order records.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new sales order, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Next available sales order number will automatically display,
        unless your system requires you to enter sales order numbers manually.
        Default values and input parameters for sales order numbers are
        configurable at the system level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays current day's date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scheduled Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the order's earliest scheduled date. The scheduled date
        corresponds to the earliest scheduled date for an included sales order
        item. If there are no existing line items, the date entered here will
        become the default schedule date for the first one. If line items do
        exist and the date is changed, you will be asked whether you want all
        editable lines to change. If the change affects pricing, you will be
        asked whether you want prices to be updated as well. If hidden, this
        field can be viewed by selecting the <guibutton>MORE</guibutton>
        button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>pack dates</primary>
          <secondary>for sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>pack dates for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Pack Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The pack date is the same date as the ship date. Because the
        field can be edited, you have the ability to change the pack date and
        make it different from the ship date. This field can be viewed by
        selecting the <guibutton>MORE</guibutton> button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Print on Save</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to automatically print the sales order when it is
        saved.</para>
        <para role="xtconnect"><note>
            <para>If the customer specified on the sales order has an EDI
            profile attached, you may encounter an EDI processing interface
            when printing the sales order.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the customer number of the customer to be billed for the
        sale. The lookup feature located to the right of the field leads to a
        searchable customers list. You may also access this list using the
        keyboard shortcut <guibutton>CTRL + L</guibutton>. Once a customer
        number is entered, the customer name and billing address will display.
        Select the <guibutton>?</guibutton> or <guibutton>$</guibutton> symbol to view customer information for the
        specified customer. If a customer's credit is <guilabel>In Good Standing</guilabel>, the
        button will feature a black question mark (<guibutton>?</guibutton>) icon. If the icon
        turns to an orange dollar sign (<guibutton>$</guibutton>), the customer's credit status is
        <guilabel>On Credit Warning</guilabel>. A red dollar sign (<guibutton>$</guibutton>) indicates the customer's
        credit status is <guilabel>On Credit Hold</guilabel>. You may also create a new customer
        record by selecting the "+" button.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>A valid customer number must be entered in the
          <guilabel>Customer #</guilabel> field before line items can be added
          to a sales order. If no valid customer number is entered, you will
          not be able to add line items to the sales order. Additionally,
          sales orders may only be entered for active customers.</para>
        </tip>
        <note>
          <para>Sales orders may not be entered for customers whose credit
          status is either <guilabel>On Credit Warning</guilabel> or <guilabel>On Credit Hold</guilabel>. Only users
          with special privileges may override these credit settings.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The customer name is displayed in an editable text field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the number of the preferred ship-to address. Customers may
        maintain multiple ship-to addresses. If the Customer master for the
        specified customer indicates that free-form Ship-To's are allowed,
        then any address may be entered. If free-form Ship-To's are not
        allowed, then the ship-to address must be entered using the browse
        button located to the right of the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The Ship-To name is displayed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. PO #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a customer purchase order number, as needed.</para>
        <note>
          <para>You will be required to enter a customer purchase order number
          for customers who require them. If required, duplicate numbers will
          only be allowed if the customer uses blanket purchase orders. All
          customer requirements are specified on the Customer master.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>hold types</primary>
          <secondary>for sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>hold types for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Hold Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a hold type (if any) from the available options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>None</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Indicates no hold is applied, meaning the order may be
              processed and shipped.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Credit</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Indicates the open balance for the customer has exceeded
              the credit limit defined on their Customer master record. Users
              will be prevented from issuing Stock to shipping with this hold
              type.</para>
              <note>
                <para>If the sales order is paid in full, as in a counter
                sales scenario for cash-only customers, the order may be
                issued to shipping.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Shipping</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Indicates a shipping hold has been placed on the order.
              Users who attempt to ship an order on shipping hold will be
              prevented from doing so.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Packing</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Indicates a Packing hold has been placed on the order.
              Users who attempt to issue stock to shipping for an order on
              Packing hold will be prevented from doing so.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry role="standard">
            <term>Return</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>This hold type is set automatically when a sales order is
              created from a return authorization and the disposition requires
              inventory to be received before the replacement order can be
              shipped.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the shipping site associated with the sales order. The
        site selected here acts as the default free on board (FOB) location. A
        site may be designated as a shipping site on the Site master. This
        field can be viewed upon selecting the <guibutton>MORE</guibutton>
        button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sale Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the sales type. Sales account assignments by sales type
        are available.</para>
        <note>
          <para>If the sales order setup setting <guilabel>Display Sales Order
          Line Items Tab by Default</guilabel> is checked, the
          <guimenuitem>Line Items</guimenuitem> tab will be displayed on the
          opening window for sales order entry.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>setting terms for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Terms</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the billing terms associated with the order. By default,
        the customer's standard billing terms will appear in the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales representatives</primary>
          <secondary>commissions for</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>commissions on</secondary>
        </indexterm>Sales Rep.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the sales representative—or Outside Rep, in the
        Distribution Edition—associated with the order. Sales representatives
        are linked to a customer on the Customer master—either by a default
        setting or through the assignment of ship-to addresses. Each ship-to
        address may have a different sales representative associated with it.
        Consequently, the name of the sales representative appearing on the
        Sales Order header will be the same as specified for the ship-to
        address being used. If you are using the Enhanced Commissions package,
        the sales rep information is moved to a separate tab.</para>
        <note>
          <para>When creating a new sales order, only active sales reps will
          be available for selection. For future changes to an existing sales
          order, all sales reps (active and inactive) will be listed to ensure
          that the original sales rep will still appear.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Commission</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the commission percentage recorded on the Customer
        master will be automatically entered in this field. If for some reason
        you select a non-default sales representative at order entry, the
        commission rate will not change. To adjust the commission rate, you
        must make the change manually. This field can be viewed by selecting
        the <guibutton>MORE</guibutton> button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax zones</primary>
          <secondary>for sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm>Tax Zone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the tax zone associated with the sales order. The tax
        zone for the specified ship-to address will be entered here by
        default. Otherwise, the primary tax zone for the customer will be
        entered. This field can be viewed upon selecting the
        <guibutton>MORE</guibutton> button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>F.O.B.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter free on board (FOB) terms for the order. By default, FOB.
        Terms entered on the Shipping Site master will appear in this field.
        The default terms may be changed during order entry—and also at later
        stages during the billing cycle.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Via</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The preferred ship via method for the customer will appear in
        the field. You may change the default ship via using the list. You may
        also enter a free-form ship via simply by typing the name of the ship
        via into the field.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>The system supports up-to-date shipment tracking with links to
          the websites of many leading shipping companies (i.e., "Ship
          Vias").</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Form</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the shipping form associated with the order. The
        preferred shipping form for the customer will appear in the field.
        This field is optional and can be viewed upon selecting the
        <guibutton>MORE</guibutton> button.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Shipping defaults specified on the Customer master will
          transfer to the Sales Order header when a new sales order is entered
          for a customer.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>shipping charges on</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>shipping</primary>
          <secondary>charges on sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>shipping forms on</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>shipping forms</primary>
          <secondary>selecting on sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm>Shipping Chgs.</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the shipping charges associated with the order. The
        preferred shipping charges type for the customer will appear in the
        field. This field can be viewed upon selecting the
        <guibutton>MORE</guibutton> button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Zone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the shipping zone. Sales account assignments by shipping
        zone are available.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Complete</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to require that all sales order line item quantities be
        issued to shipping before the order is shipped. This feature is
        designed to prevent partial shipments. If selected, users will be
        prevented from shipping the order unless all line item quantities have
        been issued to shipping. If not selected, partial shipments for the
        order will be allowed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>billing information for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Bill-To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the customer billing information below:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Address</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the customer's bill-to address. You may manually
              override the displayed address information in the fields
              below—or use the lookup feature to select another address. If a
              new address is manually entered here, that address will be added
              automatically to the master list of Addresses. For additional
              documentation related to creating addresses, see <xref
              linkend="address"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Billing Contact</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the customer's billing contact. You may manually
              override the displayed contact information in the fields
              below—or use the lookup feature to select another contact. If a
              new contact is manually entered here, that contact will be added
              automatically to the master list of Contacts. For additional
              documentation related to creating addresses, see <xref
              linkend="contact"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Copy to Ship-to -&gt;</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to copy contents of billing address into
        <guilabel>Ship-To Address</guilabel> field. This option is enabled if
        the Customer master for the specified customer indicates that
        free-form ship-tos are allowed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>ship-to details for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Ship-To</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify shipping details below:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Address</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the specified ship-to address. You may manually
              override the displayed address information in the fields
              below—or use the lookup feature to select another address. If a
              new address is manually entered here, that address will be added
              automatically to the master list of Addresses. For additional
              documentation related to creating addresses, see <xref
              linkend="contact"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Shipping Contact</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the shipping contact for the ship-to address. You
              may manually override the displayed contact information in the
              fields below—or use the lookup feature to select another
              contact. If a new contact is manually entered here, that contact
              will be added automatically to the master list of Contacts. For
              additional documentation related to creating addresses, see
              <xref linkend="contact"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>CLEAR</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to refresh the Sales Order screen so that you can enter a
        new sales order. Using the CLEAR button does not erase or in any way
        change the information on the sales order you are clearing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>SAVE AND ADD TO PACKING LIST BATCH</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the sales order, saves it, and adds it to the list of
        orders available for printing on the packing list batch.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>MORE</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display extra information related to the sales order.
        To hide the extra information, simply select the
        <guibutton>MORE</guibutton> button again.</para>
        <para role="xtconnect"><note>
            <para>If the customer specified on the sales order has an EDI
            profile attached, you may encounter an EDI processing interface
            when printing the sales order.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales orders</primary>
      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create or modify sales order line items, select the
  <guimenuitem>Line Items</guimenuitem> tab at on the Sales Order screen. The
  following will be displayed:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrder_lineItemsPage.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Sales Order Line Items</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating or modifying sales order line items, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists line items for this sales order. A valid customer
        number must be entered in the <guilabel>Customer #</guilabel> field
        before line items can be added to the order. The shipping-related
        columns will not be visible if the system is configured to hide
        shipping options at sales order entry. However, if the shipping
        options are enabled, the Line items may display in different colors,
        depending on their scheduling. If the scheduled date for an unshipped
        line item is in the future, the date will display in green text. If
        the scheduled date for an unshipped line item is not in the future,
        the date will display in red text. Once shipped, all line items revert
        to black text. For Kit items, the Kit components will be given sub
        line numbers which will be displayed in an indented view. If a line
        item is firmed, that means it cannot be edited. Firmed line items must
        be softened before they can be edited.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Sales order line items may exist in any of the following
          statuses:</para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>"O" = Open</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>"C" = Closed</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>"X" = Cancelled</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>"R" = Ready for Shipment (i.e., quantity available)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>"I" = Invoiced</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>"P" = Partially-invoiced</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>"H" = On credit hold (added to others, for example,
              "OH")</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>"F" = Firm (added to others, for example, "OF," "IF,"
              etc.)</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Require sufficient Inventory</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to ensure you have enough quantity on hand (QOH) in stock
        of a line item prior to issuing Stock to shipping. If selected, this
        option will prevent you from issuing line item quantity to shipping if
        doing so would force QOH for the item site to fall below zero. Not
        selecting this option means issuing Stock to shipping may drive item
        site QOH negative. This option will not be visible if the system is
        configured to hide shipping options at sales order entry.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Canceled Line Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include in the line items display sales order line
        items which have been specifically canceled. Displaying canceled line
        items can provide useful customer and order history
        information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description to identify the miscellaneous charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Sales Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a sales account to assign the miscellaneous charge
        to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Allocated CM/Invoice</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the monetary value of any credit memos and/or credit
        card charges which have been specifically allocated to the sales
        order. If your system is configured to automatically allocate open
        credit memo balances to new sales orders, then the monetary value of
        these allocated credit memos—plus any credit card charges applied to
        the order—will display here. You can also select the "Allocated
        Credit" link to manually allocate credit memos to the sales
        order.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The automatic allocation of available credit memos occurs only
          once—when a sales order is saved for the first time. After that
          first save, any additional allocations will need to be applied
          manually.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Outstanding Credit</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total monetary value of all unallocated credit
        memos for the customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Authorized CC Payments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the monetary value of any credit card
        pre-authorizations for the order. Credit card charges may be
        pre-authorized using the options found under the
        <guimenuitem>Payment</guimenuitem> tab. When a credit card charge is
        pre-authorized, the authorization is stored and may later be posted as
        a completed charge using the Receivables Workbench.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight Weight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the combined weight of all sales order line items.
        Freight weight represents the sum of an item's product weight and
        packaging weight, both of which are defined on the Item master. The
        per unit freight weight multiplied by the quantity per gives you the
        line item freight weight. The sum of all line item freight weights is
        the combined weight for the order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Margin</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total profit margin for the order. The profit
        margin is based on the following formula:</para>
        <para>Order Subtotal - Total Standard Costs for all line items</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Margin %</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the profit margin percentage for the order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>At Shipping</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the monetary value of sales order line items at
        shipping. The shipment value represents the total of the extended
        prices for all items included in the Shipment. The amount does not
        include freight or tax. This displayed information will not be visible
        if the system is configured to hide shipping options at sales order
        entry.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subtotal</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the subtotal for the sales order line items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of any miscellaneous charge. Examples of
        miscellaneous charges include palletization costs, co-op refund, etc.
        Before entering a miscellaneous charge amount, you must first assign
        the charge to a sales account and also enter a description of the
        charge.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>If you do not use miscellaneous charges at your site, you can
          hide these fields so they are not visible when entering sales
          orders. To do so, simply select the <guilabel>Hide Misc.
          Charges</guilabel> option in the system-level configuration.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>freight</primary>
          <secondary>on sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>
          <secondary>freight charges on</secondary>
        </indexterm>Freight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Manually enter the amount of freight charges to be added to the
        specified order, unless the freight amount is automatically
        calculated. The freight amount displayed here represents the total for
        all line items. To get a detailed view of the freight calculation,
        click on the Freight link using your mouse. Freight charges may be
        entered during the creation or modification of a sales order—or at the
        time of shipment. The system can be configured to automatically
        calculate freight amounts per quantity and Shipment. To learn more
        about freight configuration, see <xref
        linkend="configureSO_freightPricing"/>.</para>
        <note>
          <para>If you are manually entering freight, all freight charges will
          be added to the initial Shipment for an order. Any subsequent
          backorder Shipments will not include freight.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount of tax to be charged on the sales
        order. Sales tax is calculated at the sales order line item level. The
        tax amount displayed here represents the total for all line item tax
        amounts. To get a detailed view of the tax calculation, click on the
        Tax link using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount of the sales order.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>If the sales order is paid in full, the order can be shipped
          even though the customer may be on credit hold. This is to
          accommodate cash customers who do not typically have a credit
          limit.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Balance</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the projected total due for the sales order. The
        outstanding balance represents the amount the customer would owe if
        all allocated and outstanding credit memos and credit card
        pre-authorizations were applied to the order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="distribution">
      <term>Quick Item Entry</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Distribution Edition users will have the option to enter line
        items quickly on this screen, without having to first open the Sales
        Order Item screen:</para>
        <para><variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Item Number</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Enter the item number of the item you want to sell. The
                item list will contain sold items available for sale to the
                specified customer. The list of available items may vary from
                customer to customer, depending on how pricing schedules are
                implemented at your site. Once an item number is entered, the
                inventory unit of measure and item description will
                automatically appear.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Site</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Specify the site the sales order item is sold from.
                Items may be supplied to sales orders from multiple item
                sites. After an item number is entered above, the system
                checks for available item sites for the item. Any item sites
                having the <guilabel>Sold from</guilabel> flag set on them
                will be selectable from this site list. By default, the item
                site having the highest Ranking will be selected as the first
                available site. If more than one item site share a Ranking of
                "1," the sites will be sorted in alphabetical order. Item site
                Rankings are set on the Item Site master.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Qty. Ordered</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Enter the quantity of the specified item being ordered.
                The quantity will be set to "1" by default.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Scheduled Date</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>The scheduled date is the date when the line item
                quantity should be shipped. The user who enters the line item
                is responsible for determining the scheduled date. After
                entering the scheduled date, hit the
                <guibutton>TAB</guibutton> key on your keyboard to display
                values in the remaining display only fields.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>Net Unit Price</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Displays the unit price for the sales order item. By
                default, the system will choose the lower of the following two
                prices: A) The most-specific pricing schedule assignment or B)
                any Sale in effect at the time of order entry. The specificity
                of pricing schedule assignments is determined in the following
                descending order: By customer ship-to address (most specific),
                by customer, by customer type, by customer type pattern, by
                all customers. The lookup feature located to the right of the
                field leads to a Price List screen.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>ADD ITEM</term>
              <listitem>
                <para>Select to add another line item to the order.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
          </variablelist></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry role="distribution">
      <term><guibutton>FAVORITES</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to bring up an interactive screen showing a
        list of items the customer has purchased in the past. On the Favorites
        screen you'll have the option to add one or multiple items from the
        customer's traditional favorite items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>CLOSE</guibutton></term>
      <listitem id="salesOrderCLOSE1">
        <para>Highlight a sales order line item and then select this button to
        close the sales order line item. If the highlighted line item is
        already closed, this button will revert to an OPEN button, which may
        be used to open the closed line item. Closing the sales order line
        item will remove all existing reservations.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="distribution">
      <term><guibutton>MOVE UP</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a sales order line item and then select this button to
        move the line item up the list of line items. Sequence numbers are
        automatically adjusted to reflect the change in position.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="distribution">
      <term><guibutton>MOVE DOWN</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a sales order line item and then select this button to
        move the line item down the list of line items. Sequence numbers are
        automatically adjusted to reflect the change in position.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="distribution">
      <term><guibutton>SMOOTH MARGIN</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight one or multiple sales order line items and then select
        this button to reach the Margin Smoothing screen. On the Smooth Margin
        screen you will be given the option to smooth the margin for the
        selected items by a percentage you determine.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term><guibutton>RESERVE STOCK</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a sales order line item and then select this button to
        reserve inventory quantity for the line item.<note>
            <para>In order to manually reserve or unreserve stock for a line
            item, the Sales Configuration option <guilabel>"Allow Manual
            Reservations"</guilabel> must be selected.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term><guibutton>RES. LINE BAL.</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a sales order line item and then select this button to
        reserve inventory quantity for the remaining line item balance.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>shipping</primary>
          <secondary>issuing stock to</secondary>
        </indexterm><guibutton>ISSUE STOCK</guibutton></term>
      <listitem id="salesOrderISSUE1STOCK">
        <para>Highlight a sales order line item and then select this button to
        issue quantity to shipping. This button will not be visible if the
        system is configured to hide shipping options at sales order
        entry.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>You may select multiple line items for issuing to shipping by
          highlighting them using your mouse—or a combination of your mouse
          and either the <guibutton>SHIFT</guibutton> or
          <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>ISSUE LINE BAL.</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a sales order line item and then select this button to
        issue the balance of the line item quantity to shipping. This button
        will not be visible if the system is configured to hide shipping
        options at sales order entry.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The shipping-related options will not be visible if the system
          is configured to hide shipping options at sales order entry.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term><guibutton>ISSUE ORDER AVAILABLE</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to issue all material available to fill the
        current sales order. Only stock that is available to be issued to
        shipping will be issued. If an item is on backorder, that stock will
        have to be issued at a future point.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>SHIP ORDER</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a sales order line item and then select this button to
        ship the order. This button will not be visible if the system is
        configured to hide shipping options at sales order entry.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term><guibutton>ISSUE AVAILABLE AND SHIP</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to issue all material available and then ship
        the sales order, all in one step. Only stock that is available to be
        issued to shipping will be issued. If an item is on backorder, that
        stock will have to be issued at a future point.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/allocateARCreditMemo.xml"
              xpointer="allocateARCMs"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
  <para>To define or maintain relationships for sales orders, select the
  <guimenuitem>Relationships</guimenuitem> tab. The following will be
  displayed:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrder_relationshipsTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Sales Order Relationships</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When defining relationships for sales orders, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If your system is configured to use projects, select a project
        number to associate with the sales order. If a sales order is created
        from a converted quote—and the quote had a project number associated
        with it—then the project number from the originating quote will
        automatically be entered here. Once a project number is associated
        with a sales order, any work orders or purchase orders created by the
        sales order demand will automatically be linked to the same project
        number as the sales order. In this way, sales orders, work orders, and
        purchase orders may be linked to the same project.</para>
        <para role="xtprjaccnt">When you have the xTuple Project Accounting
        package installed—and you link a project to the sales
        order—transactions related to the sales order will include the Project
        number as the final segment of affected G/L account numbers. Account
        numbers related to the following transactions will include the project
        number as the final segment: Issue to shipping, return Stock, Ship
        Shipment, Recall Shipment, and Post invoice.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>If your site is configured to create projects automatically
          whenever new sales orders or quotes are entered, the projects
          generated in this way will assume the number of the sales order or
          quote which caused their creation.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Opportunity</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select an opportunity to associate with the sales order, using
        the lookup feature located to the right of the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>From Quote</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If a sales order was converted from a quote, the originating
        quote number will display here.</para>
        <para role="standard"><note>
            <para>If the sales order was generated from a return
            authorization, the return authorization number will display
            here.</para>
          </note></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Sales order characteristics are user-defined definitions which may be
  used to provide additional layers of description about sales orders. These
  descriptions are static and not processed by the system, but are useful for
  informational purposes.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>For configured items, an additional pricing field will be available
    on the Item Characteristic screen. This pricing information will be passed
    to sales order line items when particular configurations are sold. The
    price for configured items may vary depending on the characteristics
    selected at sales order entry time.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To enter characteristics associated with a sales order, select the
  <guimenuitem>Characteristics</guimenuitem> tab. The following will be
  displayed:</para>
  <para><mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrder_characteristics.png"/>
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Sales Order Characteristics</para></caption>
    </mediaobject></para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/characteristic.xml"
              xpointer="characteristiclWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
  <para>To add comments related to a sales order, select the
  <guimenuitem>Comments</guimenuitem> tab. The following will be
  displayed:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrder_comments.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Sales Order Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/comments.xml" xpointer="commentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
  <para>Order notes added to a sales order are used for internal purposes
  only. If an invoice results from the sales order, these notes will be
  transferred to the invoice. To add notes to a sales order, select the
  <guimenuitem>Order Notes</guimenuitem> tab on the Sales Order screen. The
  following will be displayed:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrder_orderNotes.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Sales Order Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When adding notes to a sales order, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general notes related to the sales order. These notes are for internal
        use only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Shipping notes are drawn from the customer master—specifically
        from the <guimenuitem>Shipping Notes</guimenuitem> tab on the Ship-To
        Address master. The notes may vary depending on the ship-to address
        specified for the order. These notes provide a mechanism for
        transferring shipping information from the Customer master to the
        sales order. Ultimately, shipping notes may be printed on shipping
        paperwork. While shipping notes content may originate from the
        Customer master, you can edit the notes to fit the requirements of an
        order. Shipping notes may be printed on shipping paperwork.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To associate documents with a sales order, select the
  <guimenuitem>Documents</guimenuitem> tab. The following will be
  displayed:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrder_documents.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Sales Order Documents</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/documents.xml" xpointer="documentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>credit cards</primary>
      <secondary>sales orders and</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales orders</primary>
      <secondary>credit cards and</secondary>
    </indexterm>To receive payments for the sales order, select the
  <guimenuitem>Payment</guimenuitem> tab at the top of the Sales Order screen.
  To authorize or charge customer credit cards, select the <guimenuitem>Credit
  Card</guimenuitem> tab in the window. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrder_paymentCredit.png"/>
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Customer Credit Card Payment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When authorizing or charging customer credit cards, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Payment</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists credit card information for the specified
        customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>MOVE UP</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a credit card and then select this button to move the
        credit card up in the sequence of credit cards. Sequence numbers are
        automatically adjusted to reflect the change in position.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>MOVE DOWN</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a credit card and then select this button to move the
        credit card down the sequence of credit cards. Sequence numbers are
        automatically adjusted to reflect the change in position.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>AUTHORIZE</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>After entering an amount below, highlight an active credit card
        and then select this button to pre-authorize the credit card charge
        for the amount specified. Pre-authorized credit card charges will be
        displayed in the <guilabel>Authorized CC Payments</guilabel> field on
        the <guimenuitem>Line Items</guimenuitem> tab. After a credit card
        charge has been pre-authorized, the charge may then be post-authorized
        using the Receivables Workbench—thereby completing the credit card
        transaction.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>CHARGE</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>After entering an amount below, highlight an active credit card
        and then select this button to charge the credit card for the amount
        specified. When a credit card is charged, both a credit memo and a
        cash receipt are posted for the charge amount. The total due from the
        customer will be automatically adjusted on the invoice to reflect the
        amount of any credit card charges. If, by chance, you charge a
        customer's credit card but fail to save the sales order, the link
        between the order and the charge will be broken; however, the
        transactions resulting from the charge will remain in the
        system.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Amount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of the credit card pre-authorization or charge.
        By default, the outstanding balance due will be displayed here.
        However, you may edit the default amount.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>CVV Code</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the card verification value (CVV) code found on the back
        of the specified credit card. This may be an optional feature at your
        site. Contact your Systems Administrator for details.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To post a cash payment, select the <guimenuitem>Cash</guimenuitem> tab
  in the Payments window. The following screen will be displayed:</para>
  <para><mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrder_paymentCash.png"/>
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Customer Cash Payment</para></caption>
    </mediaobject>When posting cash to the sales order, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Total</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Sales Order total.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Balance</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the difference between the sales order total and any
        payments that have been applied.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Amount Received</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the cash payment amount that should be applied to the
        sales order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Funds Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the type of the cash receipt. Choose from following
        Funds types: check, certified check, cash, Wire Transfer, and
        Other.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>You can use the Funds type "Other" for entering credit card
    information if you are not using xTuple's credit card processing
    functionality at your site.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Payment/Document #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use this field to enter the customer's check number, transaction
        number, credit card number, or any other Document Number associated
        with the cash receipt.</para>
        <para role="distribution">The username of the logged-in user will
        display as the default document number, when the XWD package is
        enabled. This value can be changed, if desired.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Payment/Document Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use this field to specify the date on the check you received.
        This is the Document date used when running the Receivables aging
        report.</para>
        <para role="distribution">The current date will display here, when the
        XWD package is enabled. This date can be changed, if desired.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Post to</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the bank account you want to post the cash receipt to.
        The Asset account used for the selected bank account is specified on
        the Bank Account master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <tip>
    <para>If your site uses a unique bank account for receiving credit card
    payments, make sure to select the appropriate bank account when entering
    payments from a credit card.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Distribution Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date of the cash distribution. This is the date the
        cash receipt will hit the general ledger (G/L). By default, the
        current day's date will appear. If the distribution date precedes the
        application date, the label "Apply Balance As" will change to "Record
        Receipt as" to clarify that the cash will be recorded as a credit memo
        or customer Deposit until the application date arrives. On the
        application date, the credit memo or customer Deposit will
        automatically be applied to its specified receivable
        document(s).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Application Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date you want the cash to be applied to the selected
        receivables. By default, the current day's date will appear. To
        prevent Receivable aging and G/L balance mismatches, you may not enter
        an application date prior to the earliest document date of receivables
        the cash is being applied to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Alternate Receivables Account From Sales Category</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the following optional Receivables
        accounts:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Sales Category</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify a sales category whose <guilabel>Receivables
              Account</guilabel> option you want to use instead of the default
              Receivables account.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>If an alternate Receivables account is not specified, the system
    will use the default Receivables account specified for the customer type
    under Receivables account assignments.</para>
  </note>
  <para>To view shipments associated with the order, select the
  <guimenuitem>Shipments</guimenuitem> tab. The following will be
  displayed:</para>
  <para><mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/salesOrder_shipments.png"/>
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Sales Order Shipments</para></caption>
    </mediaobject></para>
  <para>When viewing Shipments associated with the order, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the sales order number of the current sales
        order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the order date of the current sales order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the customer Name associated with the specified sales
        order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. Phone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the customer's phone number.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>P/O Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the purchase order number associated with the specified
        sales order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipments</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists Shipments for the sales order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view email associated with the sales order, select the
  <guimenuitem>Email</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/emailWidget.xml" xpointer="emailWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
  <xi:include href="salesOrderItem.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
