<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="salesAccount">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>sales assignments</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Sales Assignment</title>
  <para>To create a new sales assignment, select the
  <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/salesAccount.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create new Sales Assignment</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new sales assignment, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <tip>
    <para>The account numbers assigned to cost categories should not all be
    the inventory account. Instead, they should be individual accounts
    selected specifically for each cost-tracking purpose. This will increase
    your visibility into your inventory costs and valuation.</para>
  </tip>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify site to be associated with the account
        assignment.</para>
        <note>
          <para>In the case of conflicts between sales assignments, the system
          by default selects specific assignments before all-inclusive ones.
          For example, if there were a choice between an assignment featuring
          <guilabel>WHSE-1</guilabel> as the supplying site and another
          featuring <guilabel>ANY</guilabel> site, the more-specific
          <guilabel>WHSE-1</guilabel> would be selected.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Customer Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to associate all customer types with the sales
        assignment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the customer type you want to associate with the sales
        assignment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a customer type pattern to select a range of customer
        types. Refine your search using regular expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Product Categories</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to associate all product categories with the sales
        assignment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the product category you want to associate with the
        sales assignment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a product category pattern to select a range of product
        categories. Refine your search using regular expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Zone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a shipping zone to associate with the sales
        assignment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sale Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a sale type to associate with the sales
        assignment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory Sales Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a general ledger (G/L) account to assign as the default
        inventory sales account. This is a revenue account. It will be
        credited when invoices are posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Credit Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to assign as the default sales credit
        account. This is a revenue contra account. It will be debited when
        sales credits are posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cost of Sales Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to assign as the default cost of sales
        account. This is an expense account. It will be debited when sales
        order items are shipped. It will be credited when sales order items
        are returned to stock—either through shipping or the processing of a
        sales credit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Returns Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to assign as the default returns account.
        This is a contra revenue account. It will be debited when returns
        created by a return authorization are posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Cost of Returns Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to assign as the default cost of returns
        account. This is a contra expense account. It will be credited when
        return authorization quantity is posted as received.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Cost of Warranty Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Identify a G/L account to assign as the default warranty
        account. This is a contra expense account. It will be debited when
        warranty items are shipped and credited when warranty items are
        received.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
