<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="scrapWoMaterialFromWIP">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>scrap</primary>
      <secondary>from work order materials</secondary>
    </indexterm>Scrap Work Order Material</title>
  <para>To scrap work order materials which have been specifically issued to a
  work order using a material issue transaction, select the "Scrap Work Order
  Material from Work Order" option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/scrapWoMaterialFromWIP.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Scrap Work Order Material from Work Order</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>You may only scrap work order materials which have been specifically
    issued to a work order. In other words, material requirements having the
    Push issue method may be scrapped.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When scrapping work order materials from a work order, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Transaction Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date you want the transaction to be posted to the
        general ledger. The current day's date will display by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Work Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the work order number of the work order whose materials
        you want to scrap.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays site code automatically when work order number is
        entered into "Work Order #" field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays item number automatically when work order number is
        entered into "Work Order #" field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Status</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays work order status automatically when work order number
        is entered into "Work Order #" field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Method</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Indicates whether selected work order is an Assembly or
        Disassembly work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Top-Level Finished Item</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to scrap parent-level items.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Qty.</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the quantity of top-level finished items you want to
              scrap. You may scrap top-level items after they have been
              received into inventory—or before. Keep in mind that if you
              scrap top-level items prior to receiving them, material
              requirements for those items may or may not have been issued to
              the work order yet. You should make any necessary adjustments to
              account for those requirements. For example, you may need to
              issue the components—either manually or through a material
              backflush—and then scrap them retroactively.</para>
              <tip>
                <para>Shop Floor Workbench users should only scrap top-level
                items after they have posted production sufficient to cover
                the scrap quantity. For example, if a user assembles 10
                top-level items successfully but significantly damages the
                11th, the user should post a quantity of 11 produced and then
                scrap one (i.e., 11 - 1 = 10).</para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Production receipt already posted</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select this option if a production receipt has already
              been posted.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scrap Component</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to scrap component items issued to the work
        order.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Component Item Number</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select one of the component items from the parent item's
              work order material requirements will be listed.</para>
              <note>
                <para>You may scrap component items regardless of their issue
                method. However, components must first be issued to a work
                order before they can be scrapped from it. Components are
                issued to work orders either manually or through a material
                backflush.</para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>UOM</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Inventory unit of measure.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Qty. Per</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the component quantity per each specified on the
              parent item's work order material requirements.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Fxd. Qty.</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the fixed quantity of material issued, if
              applicable.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Scrap %</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the component scrap percentage specified on the
              item's bill of materials.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Qty. Required</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the component quantity required to fulfill the
              work order material requirements.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Qty. Issued</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the component quantity currently issued to the
              work order. You may only scrap components which have already
              been issued to a work order—either manually or through a
              material backflush.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Qty. Scrapped from WIP</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays a running total of the component quantity already
              scrapped—if any.</para>
              <tip>
                <para>You may not scrap the full quantity of a work order
                material requirement from a work order.</para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Qty.</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the quantity of the component item you want to scrap
              from the work order.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>POST</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Scraps the specified quantity of the component item from the
        work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
