<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="scriptEditor">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>scripts</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Script Editor</title>
  <para>To create a new script, select the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following screen
  will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/scriptEditor.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Script</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>You may edit multiple scripts at the same time. To do so, open
    scripts for editing side-by-side.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When creating a new script, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name to identify the script. The name of the script must
        match the name of the screen the script will be used for. If the
        script name does not match the screen name, the script will not be
        used. Because a single screen may require more than one script, you
        may save multiple scripts having the same name. The order, notes, and
        content of each script will distinguish one from the other.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a brief description of the script.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the order in which the script should be run. The script
        having the lowest number (i.e., "0") will be run first, and then
        following scripts will be run in consecutive order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Package</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name of the package the script belongs to, if
        any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Enabled</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to enable the script. If not selected, the script will be
        disabled. A disabled script will not be run when the corresponding
        screen is executed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Script</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the content of the script using QtScript. You may type the
        script directly into this window, or you may import a script using the
        <guibutton>IMPORT SCRIPT</guibutton> button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The spin box in the lower left hand corner shows you the current
        line number—and allows you to jump to specific line numbers within the
        script.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Search</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a search term in the field and then select the <guibutton>FIND</guibutton> button
        to locate matches within the script.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>FIND</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to locate search term matches within the script.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>EXTRACT WIDGETS</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the following available options to extract widget
        nodes from the selected Script's XML source. Either option should
        insert <literal>var _foo = mywindow.findChild("_foo");</literal> for
        the widgets in the screen. The information will appear above the main
        text of the Script.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guibutton>INCLUDING LABELS</guibutton></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Selecting this option should include
              <literal>XLabel</literal> and <literal>QLabel</literal>
              widgets.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><guibutton>EXCLUDING LABELS</guibutton></term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Selecting this option should exclude
              <literal>XLabel</literal> and <literal>QLabel</literal>
              widgets.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>IMPORT SCRIPT</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to import a script from your local file system into the
        database. This option is useful if you prefer to do your scripting
        using an external script editor. The script you import will be shown
        in the script window.</para>
        <warning>
          <para>Every time you import a script file, the new script will
          replace the script which was shown in the script window
          previously.</para>
        </warning>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>EXPORT SCRIPT</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to export the script shown in the script window to your
        local file system. You would use this option if you need or want to
        edit the script and do not have a copy stored locally on your system.
        Once exported, the script can be edited using an external editor—and
        then re-imported into the database using the </guilabel>Import</guilabel> option. Whenever
        you import a script file, it automatically replaces whatever script
        was in place before it.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
