<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="selectOrderForBilling">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>billing</primary>
      <secondary>approve order for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Approve Order for Billing</title>
  <para>This utility enables you to manually enter billing details for
  individual sales order line items. Both shipped orders and unshipped line
  items may be approved for billing in this manner. This individualized
  approach differs from the approach taken by the Select All Shipped Orders
  for Billing utility, which by default approves for billing the full line
  item quantities for all shipped orders. To approve an individual shipped
  order for billing, go to <guimenuitem>Sales &gt; Billing &gt; Invoice &gt;
  </guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Approve Order for Billing</guimenuitem>. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/selectOrderForBilling.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Approve Order for Billing</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>When you approve an order for billing, you are indicating that you
    wish to create an invoice for the order. Invoice numbers are assigned when
    an invoice is printed.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When approving an order for billing, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Sales Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the sales order number of the sales order you want to
        approve for billing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the original sales order date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the most-recent ship date will appear in the field.
        You may override the default value by entering ship date information
        manually.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Invoice Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the current (today's) date will appear in the field.
        You may override the default value by entering invoice date
        information manually.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cust. Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Name: displays customer's name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>P/O Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays purchase for the specified sales order. Indicates the
        customer purchase order number assigned to the specified sales
        order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays ship-to name.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax zones</primary>
          <secondary>for sales orders</secondary>
        </indexterm>Tax Zone</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the tax zone associated with the sales order. The tax
        zone for the specified ship-to address will be entered here by
        default. Otherwise, the primary tax zone for the customer will be
        entered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Via</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>By default, the preferred ship via method for specified customer
        will appear in the field. You may enter a free-form ship via simply by
        typing the name of the ship via into the field. Default ship vias may
        be defined at the system level.</para>
        <para><tip>
            <para>The system supports up-to-date shipment tracking with links
            to the websites of many leading shipping companies (i.e., ship
            vias).</para>
          </tip></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Closed Line Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to show closed line items in the Line Items
        display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Close all Open Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to close all open sales order line items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>billing</primary>
          <secondary>at line item level</secondary>
        </indexterm>Line Items</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the sales order line items approved for billing.
        Double-clicking on a line item—or highlighting it and approving the
        <guibutton>EDIT SELECTION</guibutton> button—enables you to approve a
        billing quantity for that item.</para>
        <note>
          <para>In the Line Items display, the <guilabel>Uninvoiced</guilabel>
          column refers to quantity that has been shipped but not yet
          invoiced. Quantity must have been shipped to appear in the
          <guilabel>Uninvoiced</guilabel> column. If no quantity has been
          shipped, then no quantity will appear as uninvoiced.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Subtotal</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the subtotal for the sales order line items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>billing</primary>
          <secondary>related charges for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Misc. Amount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of the miscellaneous charge. Before entering a
        miscellaneous charge amount, you must first assign the charge to a
        sales account and also enter a description of the charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description to identify the miscellaneous charge.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Misc. Charge Sales Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a sales account to assign the miscellaneous charge
        to.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of freight charge to be added to the specified
        order. The freight charge may be entered during the creation or
        modification of a sales order—or at the time of shipment.</para>
        <note>
          <para>The <guilabel>Payment Received</guilabel> field is an optional
          field which may be used to provide visibility into prepaid amounts.
          Because the field exists for visual purposes only, entering an
          amount in this field will not affect the amount due. The only way an
          invoice may be offset is through the application of a cash receipt
          or a credit memo.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the amount of tax that will be added to the sales
        order, as defined by the specified tax code. To get a detailed view of
        the tax calculation, click on the <guibutton>Tax</guibutton> link
        using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount of all uninvoiced sales orders.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>EDIT ORDER</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Brings you to the Sales Order screen, where you may edit the
        specified sales order. The Sales Order screen is described at length
        in <xref linkend="salesOrder" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>APPROVE BALANCE</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a line item, then select this button to approve the
        full balance for billing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>When the <guimenuitem>Notes</guimenuitem> tab is clicked, the screen
  will appear as follows:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/selectOrderForBilling_notes.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Approve Order for Billing Notes</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        notes related to the sales order approved for billing. Notes entered
        on this screen will follow the order through the billing process. For
        example, you may view notes associated with a posted invoice within
        the invoice information report.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="selectBillingQty.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
