<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="selectShippedOrders">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>billing</primary>
      <secondary>approve shipped orders for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Approve Shipped Orders for Billing</title>
  <para>This utility enables you to approve groups of shipped orders for
  billing in one operation. When used, the full order quantity of shipped
  orders will be approved for billing. You may later change the billing
  details for individual line items using the right-click menu on the billing
  edit list. All approved orders will appear on the billing edit list after
  the Approve Shipped Orders for Billing utility is run. This approach differs
  from the approach used by the Approve Order for Billing utility, which
  requires you to manually enter billing details for individual orders. To
  approve multiple shipped orders for billing, go to <guimenuitem>Sales &gt;
  Billing &gt; Invoice &gt; </guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Approve Shipped Orders
  for Billing</guimenuitem>. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/selectShippedOrders.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Approve Shipped Orders for Billing</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>When you approve an order for billing, you are indicating that you
    wish to create an invoice for the order.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When approving multiple shipped orders for billing, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Customer Types</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Choose to select all customer types for billing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the customer type you want to approve for
        billing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a customer type pattern to select a range of customer
        types. Refine your search using regular expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>All Sites</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Choose to approve all shipped orders for billing for all
        sites.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify site whose shipped orders you want to approve for
        billing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
