<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="standardOperation">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>standard operations</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Standard Operation</title>
  <para>To create a new standard operation, select the
  <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/standardOperation.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create new Standard Operation</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new standard operation, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Std. Oper. #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a number or code to identify the standard
        operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate the standard operation is active. If not
        selected, the standard operation will be considered inactive.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a description to further identify the operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Work Center #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the work center you want to use for the standard
        operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Operation Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select an operation type to categorize the standard
        operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tool Reference</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use this field to briefly describe any tooling required for the
        operation. For example, if you are making plastic products, the
        tooling reference might refer to the mold used to form the
        plastic.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>units of measure</primary>
          <secondary>in operations</secondary>
        </indexterm>Production UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the unit of measure (UOM )to use for the production
        UOM—or enter a free-form UOM. Specify a UOM to be used optionally when
        work order operations are posted for the specified operation.
        Operations may be posted using either the inventory or production UOM.
        In addition, different operations in a single routing may use
        different production UOMs. For example, if you are producing soup, you
        might mix the soup in one operation using UOM = BATCH. But when
        canning the soup, the canning operation might use UOM = CAN. If you
        post operations using the production UOM, the inventory/production UOM
        ratio normalizes the posting so that the inventory impact is recorded
        using the inventory UOM.</para>
        <note>
          <para>When posting work order operations, you are given the option
          to post operations using production UOMs or inventory UOMs.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory/Production UOM Ratio</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>When work order operations are posted using the production UOM,
        the inventory/production UOM ratio normalizes the posting so that the
        inventory impact is recorded in the inventory UOM. The ratio is set up
        in the same way as the capacity/inventory UOM ratio described in <xref
        linkend="item" />.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Standard Times</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to activate fields for standard times below. Standard
        times will be associated with the standard operation if
        selected.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Labor and overhead costs associated with setup and run times
          must be reported if they are to be tracked in the G/L and elsewhere.
          To report setup and run times, select the appropriate boxes in the
          Operation screen.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>setup time</primary>
          <secondary>for operations</secondary>
        </indexterm>Setup Time (min)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Amount entered represents the number of minutes required to set
        up the work center for the operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report Cost as (Setup Time)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify whether you want to report setup costs as
        <guimenuitem>Direct Labor</guimenuitem>,
        <guimenuitem>Overhead</guimenuitem>, or
        <guimenuitem>None</guimenuitem>. Specify the
        <guimenuitem>None</guimenuitem> option if you would do not want to
        track setup time as part of the operation's cost.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report Setup Time</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to report setup time. Must be selected for labor costs
        associated with setup to be tracked in the G/L and elsewhere. If not
        selected, these costs will not be reported.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>run time</primary>
          <secondary>for standard operations</secondary>
        </indexterm>Run Time (min)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Amount entered represents the number of minutes required to run
        the operation.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>per</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the standard quantity that will be produced during a
        typical run-time period. The value entered here is equivalent to a run
        size, batch size, or economic order quantity (EOQ) for this particular
        operation. Because work order operations roll into the actual and
        standard costs for manufactured items, you should specify a per
        quantity which accurately reflects your normal batch size for the
        operation. Specifying a standard batch size helps ensure your
        operations costs are evenly distributed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report Cost as (Run Time)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify whether you want to report setup costs as
        <guimenuitem>Direct Labor</guimenuitem>,
        <guimenuitem>Overhead</guimenuitem>, or
        <guimenuitem>None</guimenuitem>. Specify the
        <guimenuitem>None</guimenuitem> option if you would do not want to
        track run rime as part of the operation's cost.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Report Run Time</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to report run time. Must be selected for labor costs
        associated with run time to be tracked in the G/L and elsewhere. If
        not selected, these costs will not be reported.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Instructions</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        special instructions or comments related to the work center.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
