<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="systemMessage">
  <title>Schedule System Message</title>

  <para>System Messages enable <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>xtuple administrators</primary>

      <secondary>system messages scheduled by</secondary>
    </indexterm>system administrators and other users who have been granted
  the IssueSystemMessages privilege to broadcast system messages to all
  application users. System messages are displayed when a user logs in to the
  application. They can be any message intended for distribution to all users.
  For example, a system message might notify users about an upcoming system
  shutdown.</para>

  <note>
    <para>Once a system message is scheduled, it cannot be deleted. These
    messages should be handled carefully by qualified users. You can also
    prevent unnecessary confusion by entering a specific expiration date and
    time whenever you schedule a system message. Users who log in to the
    application after a system message has expired will not see the outdated
    message on their screen.</para>
  </note>

  <para>The following screen will appear when you select the
  <guimenuitem>Schedule System Message</guimenuitem> option:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/systemMessage.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>System Message</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>system messages</primary>

      <secondary>options for</secondary>
    </indexterm>When creating a new system message, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Posted</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays date system message was posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>At</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays time of day when system message was posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Posted by</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays username of user who posted system message.</para>

        <tip>
          <para>Hitting the <guibutton>TAB</guibutton> key in the
          <guilabel>Scheduled</guilabel> field will automatically cause a
          scheduled date of ASAP to be entered in the field. With an ASAP
          scheduled date, a system message will be delivered as soon as server
          resources allow.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scheduled</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date when you want to begin broadcasting the system
        message to all users who log in to the application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>At</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a standard time format (e.g., "HH:MM:SS").</para>

        <para>Specify the time of day—including the hour, minute, and
        second—when you want to begin broadcasting the system message to all
        users who log in to the application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expires</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date when you want to stop broadcasting the system
        message to all users who log in to the application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>At</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a standard time format (e.g., "HH:MM:SS") for when the
        defined system message is will expire.</para>

        <para>Specify the time of day—including the hour, minute, and
        second—when you want to stop broadcasting the system message to all
        users who log in to the application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Message</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering a
        system message. System messages are broadcast to all users when they
        log in to the application.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>REPLY</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to reply to the system message. The reply will be sent to
        the user who initiated the system message.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
