<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="taxAuthority">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>tax authorities</primary>

      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Tax Authority</title>

  <para>To create a new tax authority, select the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton>
  button. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/taxAuthority.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Create new Tax Authority</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating a new tax authority, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Code</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a code to identify the tax authority.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name to describe the tax authority.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ext. Ref</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Use this field to record any external accounting references for
        the tax authority—if applicable.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Currency</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the currency to be used for tax calculations when
        transactions are governed by the tax authority.</para>

        <para>The currency selection affects only tax calculations for
        transactions governed by the tax authority. It has no impact on the
        currency used for line items, etc. on an order. If the tax authority
        requires tax to be collected in the base currency, then do not make a
        selection; leave this field blank. This option won't even be available
        if your site does not have multiple currencies defined.</para>

        <tip>
          <para>If a tax authority collects tax in your base currency, then
          leave the currency selection blank.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>County</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the county which the tax authority has jurisdiction
        over—if applicable.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Default Ledger Account</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the G/L account to credit when payment (check) to tax
        authority is posted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Address</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Manually enter tax authority's address information in the fields
        below—or use the lookup feature to select pre-existing address
        information. If a new address is manually entered here, that address
        will be added automatically to the master list of addresses. For
        additional documentation related to creating addresses, see <xref
        linkend="address"/>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>ACCOUNT</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to open the tax authority's account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
