<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="timeExpenseSheets" role="xtte">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>worksheets</primary>

      <secondary>management of</secondary>
    </indexterm>Worksheets</title>

  <para>Worksheets are documents used to capture time and expenses for
  employees and contractors. When worksheets are created, they appear on this
  Worksheets screen where managers can review and approve them all in one
  place.</para>

  <note>
    <para>For more information on using worksheets to help manage projects,
    please see the eBook <ulink
    url="https://www.xtuple.org/sites/default/files/prodguide/project/index.html">Managing
    Projects with xTuple</ulink>.</para>
  </note>

  <para>The following set up information will help ensure your worksheets are
  complete when you process them:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Employees</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Should have compensation rate defined, but billing rate is
        optional. The compensation rate is used to determine the labor cost of
        employees when their time entries are posted to the general ledger
        (G/L). The billing rate may be used when employees are doing billable
        work for a customer, depending on the billing rate hierarchy defined
        for the customer. To ensure employees can be reimbursed for their
        expenses, employees must also be defined as vendors in the
        system.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Contractors</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Should also have compensation rate, but billing rate is
        optional. For contractors, the compensation rate is used to determine
        the amount owed to contractors for their time entries. Contractor
        costs are not posted directly as a labor cost, as they are for
        employees. Instead, contractor time is vouchered and then checks are
        written to the contractors—thereby closing the vouchers. Because
        contractors are paid both for their time and their expenses,
        contractors must be defined as vendors in the system. Like employees,
        the billing rate for contractors may be used when contractors are
        doing billable work for a customer, depending on the billing rate
        hierarchy defined for the customer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To review worksheets, go to <guimenuitem>CRM &gt; Project &gt;
  Worksheets</guimenuitem>. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/timeExpenseSheets.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Worksheets</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When reviewing worksheets, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Employees</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which employee worksheets you want to include in the
        display, using the specified date range:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>All</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include worksheets for all employees in the
              display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Selected</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include a specific employee's worksheets in the
              display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Direct Reports</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include employee worksheets for a specific
              manager in the display. Managers are linked to employees on the
              employee record.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Week of</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a date range for the worksheets you want to
        review:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Start Date</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Worksheets dated on and after this date will be included
              in the display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>End Date</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Worksheets dated on and before this date will be included
              in the display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Status</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which worksheet statuses you want to include in the
        display:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Open</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include open worksheets in the display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Approved</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include approved worksheets in the
              display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Closed</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to include closed worksheets in the display.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Worksheets</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display will list worksheets based on the specified parameters.
        By right-clicking on a worksheet, you can perform several actions,
        including edit, print, delete, and approve.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>When Processing</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select one or more of the following options to be performed
        automatically when processing worksheets:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Invoice</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to generate an invoice to bill the specified
              customer for their billable time and/or expense entries on the
              selected worksheet(s). This option only applies to billable
              entries.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Voucher</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to generate a voucher to reimburse contractor type
              employees for their expenses. In the case of contractors,
              expense reimbursement may also be combined with payment for
              hours worked. Regular employees are not paid in this way.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Post Time</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to post employee labor and overhead costs to the
              general ledger. This step applies to employees only and does not
              apply to contractors.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>NEW</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to create a new worksheet.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>APPROVE</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight one or multiple open worksheets and then select this
        button to approve the highlighted worksheets.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>PROCESS</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight one or multiple open worksheets and then select this
        button to process the highlighted worksheets, using the processing
        instructions indicated at the bottom of the screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <xi:include href="timeExpenseSheet.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
