<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="transformTrans" role="standard">
  <title>Transform</title>

  <para>Transformation is the process of converting quantity of one item into
  quantity of another item. The Transform utility can be applied in multiple
  scenarios. For example, let's say you manufacture an item—but when supplies
  run low, you purchase replenishment quantity from a vendor. You would
  receive the replenishment quantity using an item number having the
  <guilabel>Purchased</guilabel> item type. This purchased quantity would then
  be transformed into quantity of your manufactured item.</para>

  <note>
    <para>You may only transform an item if the source item is located in the
    same site as the target item.</para>
  </note>

  <para>To transform inventory quantity, go to <guimenuitem>Inventory &gt;
  Transactions &gt; Transform</guimenuitem>. The following screen will
  appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/transformTrans.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Transform utility</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When transforming inventory quantity, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Transaction Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date you want the transaction to be posted to the
        general ledger. The current day's date will display by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the source item whose quantity you want
        to transform.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify site where desired source item quantity is
        located.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Source</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays available site locations. Highlight the location
        containing quantity you want to transform. If the item is
        multiply-located in the specified site, all locations having valid
        quantity will display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Target Item Number</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which item you want to transform the source item
        quantity to. Target item numbers are defined using the
        <guimenuitem>Transformations</guimenuitem> tab on the Item master for
        the source item. If no target item is defined on the Item master, no
        transformations may occur.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. to Transform</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the source item quantity you want to transform into
        target item quantity.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
