<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="transferOrderItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>transfer orders</primary>

      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>Transfer Order Item</title>

  <para>To add a new transfer order line item, select the NEW button. The
  following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/transferOrderItem.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Create New Transfer Order Line Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating a new transfer order line item, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the transfer order number specified on the Transfer
        Order header screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Line item number for the current line item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the item you want to sell. The item
        list will contain items having valid item sites in the From (i.e.,
        Source) site.</para>

        <note>
          <para>Because Kit items are non-stock items, they may not be added
          to transfer orders.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sites</primary>

          <secondary>source for transfer orders</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>

          <secondary>selling sites for</secondary>
        </indexterm>From Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the Source site specified on the Transfer Order header
        screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Ordered</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity of the specified item to be
        transferred.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Shipped</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Shipped to Date: Displays the total quantity shipped of the
        specified line item to date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Standard Cost</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the standard cost per unit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Item Freight</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the amount of freight charges for the entire line item
        quantity.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the amount of Tax to be charged for the transfer order
        line item quantity. Sales Tax is calculated at the transfer order Line
        item level. To get a detailed view of the Tax calculation, click on
        the Tax link using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scheduled Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The scheduled date is the date when the line item should be
        Shipped. The user who enters the line item is responsible for
        determining the scheduled date. After entering the scheduled date, hit
        the TAB key on your keyboard to display values in the remaining
        display only fields.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>The transfer order item having the earliest scheduled date will
    determine the ship date for the transfer order.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Promise Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>An additional informational date that can be used for a user
        defined purpose.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PREVIOUS</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to view previous line items associated with the Transfer
        Order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>CANCEL ITEM</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to cancel the current transfer order line item. Records
        of canceled line items will be retained for informational purposes. To
        view canceled line items associated with a transfer order, select the
        "Show Canceled Line Items" option on the Transfer Order header's "Line
        Items tab.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>If there is no item site for the item in the destination site, you
    will automatically be presented with an Item Site screen. Simply enter the
    required information to create an item site in the destination site. An
    item site must exist in the Destination site before material can be
    received successfully.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>sales orders</primary>

          <secondary>availability of items for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Show Availability</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to display availability supply information for the
        transfer order item in the following categories:</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Inventory</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select option to view available inventory.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>On Hand</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the current quantity on hand (QOH) value.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Allocated</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the quantity allocated to current sales orders,
              transfer orders, and/or work orders in the system. An item is
              considered allocated to a sales order/transfer order if a
              transfer order line item exists for the item—and that line item
              has not yet been issued to shipping. An item is considered
              allocated to a work order if the item is a material
              requirement—and the material has not yet been issued to the work
              order. Once the current transfer order line item is saved, the
              "Allocated" value will increase by the quantity ordered.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Unallocated</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the QOH remaining after allocations have been
              accounted for, as in: QOH - Allocated Qty. = Unallocated
              Qty.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>On Order</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>If the transfer order item is a manufactured item, the
              quantity ordered by current work orders will be displayed. If
              the transfer order item is a purchased item, the quantity
              ordered by current purchase orders will be displayed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Available</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the available quantity. Available quantity is
              determined using the following formula: Unallocated Qty. + On
              Order Qty. = Available Qty.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Dependencies</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select option to review any components dependent on manufactured
        line item.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Show Dependencies as Indented BOM</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays components items associated with sold
              manufactured item in a nested list with a plus ("+") sign
              located to the far left of the screen next to each line that may
              be expanded to lower levels. By clicking your mouse on a plus
              sign, you reveal lower levels of information related to the line
              item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>When selecting or editing characteristics for a transfer order line
  item, you are presented with the following options:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/transferOrderItem_itemCharacteristicsTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Transfer Order Line Item Characteristics</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot><variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>Name</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Displays the name of any item characteristics associated with
          the item. Characteristics defined as item characteristics may be
          associated with items on the Item master.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Value</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Displays the default Value associated with an item
          characteristic, but permits you to specify an alternate Value. When
          associating characteristic Values with a transfer order line item,
          you have four options: 1) Select the default Value; 2) select an
          alternate pre-defined Value from the list; 3) manually enter a new
          Value in place of the pre-defined Value; or 4) make no selection.
          Making no selection means the characteristics will not be associated
          with the transfer order line item.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist><tip>
      <para>You can link characteristics and Values to an item by using the
      Item master. Once entered, these characteristics and Values will be
      available to users entering transfer order line items.</para>
    </tip></para>

  <para>To enter notes related to a transfer order line item, select the
  "Notes" tab at the bottom of the screen, as shown below:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/transferOrderItem_notesTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Transfer Order Line Item Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When adding notes to a transfer order line item, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general notes related to the transfer order line item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To add comments related to a transfer order line item, select the
  "Comments" tab. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/transferOrderItem_commentsTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Transfer Order Line Item Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <note>
    <para>Whenever transfer order line items are created or their quantities
    are changed, the system will automatically generate a comment, which will
    appear in the list of line item comments.</para>
  </note>

  <xi:include href="../widgets/comments.xml" xpointer="commentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
