<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="transferOrder" role="standard">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>transfer orders</primary>

      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>New Transfer Order</title>

  <para>Transfer orders are used to move inventory between sites. They are
  distinct from Inter-site Transfers in three primary ways: 1) you can add
  multiple items to a single transfer order and transfer all the items at
  once; 2) all transfer order transfers involve a Transit site, for tracking
  inventory while it is "in transit"; and 3) there are reports (i.e.,
  paperwork) associated with transfer orders. To enter a new transfer order,
  select the "New Transfer Order" option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/transferOrder.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Create New Transfer Order</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating a new transfer order, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Next available transfer order number will automatically display,
        unless your system requires you to enter transfer order numbers
        manually. Default values and input parameters for transfer order
        Numbers are configurable at the system level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays current day's date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Scheduled Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the order's earliest scheduled date. The scheduled date
        corresponds to the earliest scheduled date for an included transfer
        order item. Because transfer orders may contain multiple transfer
        order items, the scheduled date indicates the most recent scheduled
        date. No scheduled date will display in the "Scheduled Date" field
        until a transfer order line item has been created and a scheduled date
        assigned to it.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>pack dates</primary>

          <secondary>for transfer orders</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>transfer orders</primary>

          <secondary>pack dates for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Pack Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The pack date is the same date as the ship date. Because the
        field can be edited, you have the ability to change the pack date and
        make it different from the ship date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Status</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select the current status of the transfer order. Transfer orders
        may be either Unreleased = "U", Open = "O" or Closed = "C". The
        default status for a new transfer order is Unreleased. The
        ReleaseTransferOrders privilege is required to change the status to
        Open. The transfer order must be released before shipping and
        receiving transactions are allowed. Changing the order status will
        also make the appropriate status changes to the order line
        items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Agent</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Agent associated with the transfer order. By
        default, the name of the logged-in user will be entered as Purchasing
        Agent-assuming that user is designated as a Purchasing Agent. If the
        user is not a Purchasing Agent, the first alphabetical name in the
        list of Purchasing Agents will be entered.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>tax zones</primary>

          <secondary>for transfer orders</secondary>
        </indexterm>Tax Zone</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the tax zone for this transfer order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Complete</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to require that all transfer order line item quantities
        be issued to shipping before the order is shipped. This feature is
        designed to prevent partial shipments. If selected, users will be
        prevented from shipping the order unless all line item quantities have
        been issued to shipping. If not selected, partial shipments for the
        order will be allowed.</para>

        <note>
          <para>Transfer orders may not be received before they have been
          shipped.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select a project number to associate with the transfer order.
        projects may be used to link transfer orders with work orders, sales
        orders, purchase orders, etc.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship From</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the following details related to the site the order is
        being shipped from:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Site</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select a source site from the available options.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Address</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the default address for the specified ship-from
              site. You may manually override the displayed address
              information in the fields below—or use the lookup feature to
              select another address. If a new address is manually entered
              here, that address will be added automatically to the master
              list of Addresses. For additional documentation related to
              creating addresses, see <xref linkend="address"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Site Contact</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the default contact for the specified ship-from
              site. You may manually override the displayed contact
              information in the fields below—or use the lookup feature to
              select another contact. If a new contact is manually entered
              here, that contact will be added automatically to the master
              list of Contacts. For additional documentation related to
              creating addresses, see <xref linkend="contact"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship-To</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the following details related to the site the order is
        being shipped to:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Site</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select a destination site from the available
              options.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Address</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the default address for the specified ship-to
              site. You may manually override the displayed address
              information in the fields below—or use the lookup feature to
              select another address. If a new address is manually entered
              here, that address will be added automatically to the master
              list of Addresses. For additional documentation related to
              creating addresses, see <xref linkend="address"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Site Contact</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the default contact for the specified ship-to
              site. You may manually override the displayed contact
              information in the fields below—or use the lookup feature to
              select another contact. If a new contact is manually entered
              here, that contact will be added automatically to the master
              list of Contacts. For additional documentation related to
              creating addresses, see <xref linkend="contact"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Ship Via</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the ship via associated with the transfer order. You may
        enter a free-form ship via simply by typing the name of the ship via
        into the field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Form</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the shipping form associated with the transfer order.
        This field is optional.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>SAVE AND ADD TO PACKING LIST BATCH</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Creates the transfer order, saves it, and adds it to the list of
        orders available for printing on the packing list batch.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>transfer orders</primary>

      <secondary>adding line items to</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create or modify transfer order line items, select the
  "Line Items" tab at the top of the "Transfer Order" screen. The following
  screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/transferOrder_lineItemsPage.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Transfer Order Line Items</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When creating or modifying transfer order line items, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Line Items</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists line items for this transfer order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>Transfer order line items may exist in any of the following
    statuses:</para>

    <para>"U" = Unreleased</para>

    <para>"O" = Open</para>

    <para>"C" = Closed</para>

    <para>"X" = Cancelled</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Canceled Line Items</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include in the line items display transfer order line
        items which have been specifically canceled. Displaying canceled line
        items can provide useful order history information.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Require sufficient Inventory</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to ensure you have enough quantity on hand (QOH) of a
        line item prior to issuing Stock to shipping. If selected, this option
        will prevent you from issuing line item quantity to shipping if doing
        so would force QOH for the item site to fall below zero. Not selecting
        this option means issuing Stock to shipping may drive item site QOH
        negative.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight Weight</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the combined weight of all transfer order line items.
        Freight weight represents the sum of an item's product weight and
        packaging weight, both of which are defined on the Item master. The
        per unit freight weight multiplied by the quantity per gives you the
        line item freight weight. The sum of all line item freight weights is
        the combined weight for the order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>freight</primary>

          <secondary>on transfer orders</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>transfer orders</primary>

          <secondary>freight charges on</secondary>
        </indexterm>Line Item Freight Subtotal</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the subtotal for all line item freight. Freight charges
        may be added when entering or editing a transfer order line
        item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount of tax to be charged on the transfer
        order. Sales tax is calculated at the transfer order line item level.
        The tax amount displayed here represents the total for all line item
        tax amounts. To get a detailed view of the tax calculation, click on
        the Tax link using your mouse.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the total amount of the transfer order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>Any transfer order line item may be shipped—even if the item or item
    site in question becomes inactive after the sales order has been
    created.</para>
  </note>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>CLEAR</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to clear the contents of the current transfer order and
        open a fresh, new transfer order for order entry. The order number of
        the order being cleared will display next to the <guibutton>CLEAR</guibutton> button.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>Selecting the <guibutton>CLEAR</guibutton> button on the transfer order header does not
    delete any information which has been saved previously.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>CLOSE</guibutton></term>

      <listitem id="transferOrderCLOSE">
        <para>Highlight a transfer order line item and then select this to
        close the transfer order line item. If the highlighted line item is
        already closed, the label will revert to an <guibutton>OPEN</guibutton> button, which may be used to
        open the closed line item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>shipping</primary>

          <secondary>issuing stock to</secondary>
        </indexterm><guibutton>ISSUE STOCK</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a transfer order line item and then select this button
        to issue quantity to shipping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
    <para>You may select multiple line items for issuing to shipping by
    highlighting them using your mouse—or a combination of your mouse and
    either the <guibutton>SHIFT</guibutton> or <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key.</para>
  </tip>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>ISSUE LINE BAL.</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a transfer order line item and then select this button
        to issue the balance of the line item quantity to shipping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>Order notes added to a transfer order are used for internal purposes
  only. To add notes to a transfer order, select the "Order Notes" tab at the
  top of the "Transfer Order" screen. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/transferOrder_orderCommentsPage.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Transfer Order Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When adding notes to a transfer order, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order Notes</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general notes related to the transfer order. These notes are for
        internal use only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To add comments related to a transfer order, select the "Comments"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/transferOrder_comments.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Transfer Order Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <xi:include href="../widgets/comments.xml" xpointer="commentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

  <para>Shipping notes are drawn from the shipping comments (if any)
  associated with transit sites. The notes may vary depending on the Transit
  site being used. These notes provide a mechanism for transferring
  information about Transit sites to the transfer order. To view transfer
  order shipping notes, select the "Shipping Notes" tab at the top of the
  "Transfer Order" screen. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/transferOrder_shippingCommentsPage.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Transfer Order Shipping Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When viewing or editing shipping notes for a transfer order, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Shipping Notes</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>While the content for shipping notes may originate from the
        Transit Site master, you can edit the notes to fit the requirements of
        an order. This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To associate documents with a transfer order, select the "Documents"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/transferOrder_documentsPage.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Transfer Order Documents</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <xi:include href="../widgets/documents.xml" xpointer="documentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

  <para>If you want to speed up your data entry of transfer order line items,
  you can use the Quick Entry interface. This screen allows you to enter
  multiple line items in one session. It also simplifies the process by
  presenting only the minimum required fields. To enter line items using the
  Quick Entry interface, select the "Quick Entry" tab at the top of the
  "Transfer Order" screen. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/transferOrder_qeTab.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Transfer Order Quick Entry</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <tip>
    <para>To get started entering line items, place your cursor in the "Item"
    field. You can then move from field-to-field using the <guibutton>TAB</guibutton> button on your
    keyboard.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>When entering transfer order line items using the Quick Entry
  interface, you are presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter an inventory item number. This field is used for entering
        items stored in inventory.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty.</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the quantity you want to transfer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Standard Cost</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the standard cost per unit.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Freight</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the freight amount, if any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Due Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the due date.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>SAVE QUICK ENTRIES</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to save all the line items entered using the Quick Entry
        interface.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>DELETE QUICK ENTRY</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a line item and then select this button to remove the
        item from the list.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>To view email associated with a transfer order, select the "Email"
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <xi:include href="../widgets/emailWidget.xml" xpointer="emailWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

  <xi:include href="transferOrderItem.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
