<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="transferTrans" role="standard">
  <title>Inter-Site Transfer</title>

  <para>To transfer quantity of an item from one site to another, select the
  <guimenuitem>Inter-Site Transfer</guimenuitem> option. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/transferTrans.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Enter Inter-Site Transfer</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <tip>
    <para>An inter-site transfer can only be executed if the specified item is
    located in more than one site. To add an additional site for an item, go
    to the enter item sites section of the Item Sites menu. Locate the desired
    item number using the item number lookup feature. Then select a new site
    in the <guilabel>Site</guilabel> field. Enter all other required fields and save your
    results. The item will now also be located in the additional site. Repeat
    as often as necessary.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>When creating an inter-site transfer, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Transaction Date</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the date you want the transaction to be posted to the
        general ledger. The current day's date will display by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the item you want to transfer from one
        site to another.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>From Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the source site for the transaction. If an item is
        located in more than one site, be sure to specify the correct site you
        want to transfer the item from. The <guilabel>Before</guilabel> column displays current
        quantity on hand (QOH) for the item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>To Site</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>: Specify the destination site for the transaction. If an item
        is located in more than one site, be sure to specify the correct site
        you want to transfer the item to. The <guilabel>Before</guilabel> column displays current
        QOH for the item</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Transferred Qty.</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>The number entered will adjust the item's QOH in both the "From"
        and "To" sites. The values displayed in the <guilabel>After</guilabel> column represent
        the new QOH in each location. Non-netable QOH is not included in these
        values.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Document #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Creates a user-defined reference for the Inter-site Transfer.
        The Document reference will be posted with the general ledger (G/L)
        transaction record when the Inter-site Transfer is generated. This
        field may be used for internal tracking and auditing purposes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Comments</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        comments related to the transfer.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
