<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="unappliedARCreditMemos">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>credit memos</primary>

      <secondary>list of unapplied</secondary>
    </indexterm>List Unapplied Credit Memos</title>

  <para>Whenever a credit memo amount has not been applied to a specific
  invoice or debit memo—either in whole or in part—that credit memo will
  appear on the list of unapplied credit memos. Both miscellaneous receivables
  credit memos and unapplied credit memos generated from the billing section
  may appear on the list.</para>

  <note>
    <para>A newly-entered miscellaneous credit memo is an unapplied credit
    memo by default. However, credit memos generated from the billing section
    may or may not be unapplied—depending on circumstances. For example, if a
    sales credit is applied to a specific invoice when the credit memo is
    created, then that credit memo is applied and will not appear on the list
    of unapplied credit memos. However, if a sales credit is not applied when
    it is created, it will subsequently appear on the unapplied list.</para>
  </note>

  <para>To access the master list of unapplied credit memos, go to
  <guimenuitem>Accounting &gt; Accounts Receivable &gt; Memos &gt; List
  Unapplied Credit Memos</guimenuitem>. The following screen will
  appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/unappliedARCreditMemos.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Unapplied A/R Credit Memos master list</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>The master list of unapplied credit memos displays basic information
  on all existing unapplied credit memos, including document number, customer
  name, document amount, applied amount, and amount available to apply.</para>

  <note>
    <para>Once the full amount of a credit memo has been applied, the credit
    memo will be removed from the unapplied credit memos list.</para>
  </note>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>APPLY</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight an unapplied credit memo and then select this button
        to apply an amount.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <xi:include href="applyARCreditMemo.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</section>
