<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="updateReorderLevels">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>reorder levels</primary>
      <secondary>updating by planner code</secondary>
    </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>planner codes</primary>
      <secondary>updating reorder levels using</secondary>
    </indexterm>Update Reorder Levels by Planner Code</title>
  <para>To update Reorder Levels by planner code, select the <guimenuitem>Reorder Levels
  by Planner Code</guimenuitem> option. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/updateReorderLevels.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Update Reorder Levels by Planner Code</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>This utility does <emphasis>not</emphasis> update reorder levels for
    items located in Transit sites when it is run.</para>
  </note>
  <para>When updating Reorder Levels by planner code, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>All Planner Codes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update Reorder Levels for all planner codes.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify planner code whose Reorder Levels you want to
        update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Pattern</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a planner code pattern to select a range of planner codes.
        Refine your search using Regular Expressions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Site Selection</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select what sites you want to query.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>All Sites</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to update Reorder Levels by planner code for all
              sites.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Selected</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify site where Reorder Levels by planner code are to
              be updated.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Options</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select whether you would prefer to review results of analysis
        before updating reorder levels or update immediately.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Preview Results</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Review results of analysis prior to updating reorder
              levels.</para>
              <para role="xtconnect">The <guibutton>SCHEDULE</guibutton> button will be disabled in
              this mode.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Update Immediately</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Update reorder levels without previewing analysis
              first.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Days of Stock at Reorder Level</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify number of days using one of the following
        options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item Site Lead Time +</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter
              a value up to a maximum of 99. Average daily usage calculated
              using selected calendar periods will be multiplied by this value
              to determine Reorder Level.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Fixed Days</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter
              a value up to a maximum of 999. Average daily usage calculated
              using selected calendar periods will be multiplied by this value
              to determine Reorder Level.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Periods to Include in Analysis</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the periods to include in the analysis using the
        following calendar options:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Calendar</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select the calendar you want to use for the
              analysis.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Name/Selected Periods</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select as many periods as you want to include in the
              analysis. Selected periods correspond to calendar specified in
              the "Calendar" field. Select individual periods or groups of
              periods together. To select an individual period, highlight the
              period using your mouse button. The period is now selected. To
              select a sequence of periods, highlight the first in the
              sequence using your mouse button. Then, holding down the <guibutton>SHIFT</guibutton>
              key on your keyboard, highlight the last period in the sequence.
              The entire sequence is now selected. To select periods that are
              out of sequence (e.g., January, April, July, October), highlight
              the first period in the group. Then, holding down the <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key
              on your keyboard, highlight the next period you want to select.
              Continue highlighting periods with the <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key depressed until
              all desired periods are selected. The entire group is now
              selected.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UPDATE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The initial <guibutton>QUERY</guibutton> button converts to an <guibutton>UPDATE</guibutton> button once
        results have been queried and the data is ready to be updated. Select
        this button to update reorder levels, using the specified
        criteria.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view Results of query, select the <guimenuitem>Results</guimenuitem> tab. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <screenshot>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/updateReorderLevels_resultsTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption>Review Reorder Level Analysis by Planner Code</caption>
    </mediaobject>
  </screenshot>
  <para>Upon selecting Results a list of analysis results will appear on the
  screen.</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Total Days Analyzed</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Shows how many days were analyzed in your analysis and also
        lists affected item sites.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Item sites subject to Constraint Management must always have a
          minimum Reorder Level of at least one. If your results indicate a
          new level of zero for one of these item sites, you will get an error
          message preventing the update. Item sites having the "Stocked" flag
          turned ON are subject to Constraint Management.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
