<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="updateListPricingSchedules">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>list pricing schedules</primary>
      <secondary>updating</secondary>
    </indexterm>Update List Pricing Schedules</title>
  <para>This utility is designed to update item Prices found within List
  Pricing Schedules. Using this screen, you can update item Prices by Product
  Category, item Group, or by item—all without having to open the individual
  List Pricing Schedules themselves to make the changes. To update List
  Pricing Schedules, select the "Update List Pricing Schedules" option. The
  following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/updateListPricingSchedules.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Update List Pricing Schedules</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When updating item Prices found within List Pricing Schedules, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <note>
    <para>This pricing utility updates item Prices found on List Pricing
    Schedules only. It is not designed to update List Prices or discount
    percentages.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Update By</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which item Prices found within existing List Pricing
        Schedules you want to update:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Product Category</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to update item Prices by Product Category. If items
              appear on a selected List Pricing Schedule and fall within the
              chosen Product Category, then the item Prices for those items
              will be updated by the specified amount.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item Group</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to update item Prices by item Group. If items
              appear on a selected List Pricing Schedule and fall within the
              chosen item Group, then the item Prices for those items will be
              updated by the specified amount.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to update item Prices by item. If the item appears
              on a selected List Pricing Schedule, then the item Price for
              that item will be updated by the specified amount.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Nominal</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to update nominal List Pricing Schedule
        items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to update discount List Pricing Schedule
        items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Markup</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to update markup List Pricing Schedule
        items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Current</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include current List Pricing Schedules in the list of
        available List Pricing Schedules. If not selected, current List
        Pricing Schedules will not be included.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Expired</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include expired List Pricing Schedules in the list of
        available List Pricing Schedules. If not selected, expired List
        Pricing Schedules will not be included.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Future</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include future List Pricing Schedules in the list of
        available List Pricing Schedules. If not selected, future List Pricing
        Schedules will not be included.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Available</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display will list available List Pricing Schedules, based on the
        parameters you specified. Use the &gt; or &gt;&gt; buttons to move one
        or all of the available List Pricing Schedules into the selected List
        Pricing Schedules list. List Pricing Schedules appearing in the
        selected list will be updated when the utility is run.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>You may select multiple List Pricing Schedules to move back
          and forth by highlighting them using your mouse—or a combination of
          your mouse and either the SHIFT or CTRL keys.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display will list List Pricing Schedules which have been
        selected for updating. Use the &lt; or &lt;&lt; buttons to remove one
        or all of the available List Pricing Schedules from the selected List
        Pricing Schedules list. List Pricing Schedules appearing in the
        selected list will be updated when the utility is run.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Update Prices by</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a positive or negative value to indicate how much you want
        to update your item Prices by. The value represents either a
        percentage or fixed amount update, based on the following
        selection:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Percent</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to update item Prices by a percentage
              amount.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Fixed Amount</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to update item Prices by a fixed amount.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Also Update Characteristic Prices</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to also update Prices associated with item
        Characteristics for items in the specified Product Category
        range.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UPDATE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Updates item Prices, using the specified parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
