<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="updatePricingSchedules">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>pricing schedules</primary>
      <secondary>updating</secondary>
    </indexterm>Update Pricing Schedules</title>
  <para>This utility is designed to update item prices found within pricing
  schedules. Using this screen, you can update item prices by product
  category, item group, or by item—all without having to open the individual
  pricing schedules themselves to make the changes. To update pricing
  schedules, go to <guimenuitem>Sales &gt; Pricing &gt; Update Pricing
  Schedules</guimenuitem>. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/updatePricingSchedules.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Update Pricing Schedules</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When updating item prices found within pricing schedules, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <note>
    <para>This pricing utility updates item prices found on pricing schedules
    only. It is not designed to update list prices or discount
    percentages.</para>
  </note>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Update By</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify which item prices found within existing pricing
        schedules you want to update:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Product Category</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to update item prices by product category. If items
              appear on a selected pricing schedule and fall within the chosen
              product category, then the item prices for those items will be
              updated by the specified amount.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item Group</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to update item prices by item group. If items
              appear on a selected pricing schedule and fall within the chosen
              item group, then the item prices for those items will be updated
              by the specified amount.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to update item prices by item. If the item appears
              on a selected pricing schedule, then the item price for that
              item will be updated by the specified amount.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Nominal</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to update nominal pricing schedule
        items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discount</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to update discount pricing schedule
        items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Markup</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to update markup pricing schedule
        items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Current</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include current pricing schedules in the list of
        available pricing schedules. If not selected, current pricing
        schedules will not be included.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Expired</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include expired pricing schedules in the list of
        available pricing schedules. If not selected, expired pricing
        schedules will not be included.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Show Future</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to include future pricing schedules in the list of
        available pricing schedules. If not selected, future pricing schedules
        will not be included.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Available</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display will list available pricing schedules, based on the
        parameters you specified. Use the <guibutton>&gt;</guibutton> or
        <guibutton>&gt;&gt;</guibutton> buttons to move one or all of the
        available pricing schedules into the selected pricing schedules list.
        Pricing schedules appearing in the selected list will be updated when
        the utility is run.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>You may select multiple pricing schedules to move back and
          forth by highlighting them using your mouse—or a combination of your
          mouse and either the <guibutton>SHIFT</guibutton> or
          <guibutton>CTRL</guibutton> key.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Selected</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Display will list pricing schedules which have been selected for
        updating. Use the <guibutton>&lt;</guibutton> or
        <guibutton>&lt;&lt;</guibutton> buttons to remove one or all of the
        available pricing schedules from the selected pricing schedules list.
        Pricing schedules appearing in the selected list will be updated when
        the utility is run.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Update Prices by</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a positive or negative value to indicate how much you want
        to update your item prices by. The value represents either a
        percentage or fixed amount update, based on the following
        selection:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Percent</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to update item prices by a percentage
              amount.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Fixed Amount</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select to update item prices by a fixed amount.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Also Update Characteristic Prices</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to also update prices associated with item
        characteristics for items in the specified product category
        range.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>UPDATE</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Updates item prices, using the specified parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
