<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="updateCreditStatusByCustomer">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>customers</primary>

      <secondary>updating credit status for</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>credit status</primary>

      <secondary>updating by customer</secondary>
    </indexterm>Update Credit Status by Customer</title>

  <para>The credit status of a customer has a direct bearing on whether sales
  orders can be created for that customer. For example, customers who are on
  credit warning or credit hold may not have sales orders entered for them. To
  update a customer's credit status, select the <guimenuitem>Update Credit
  Status by Customer</guimenuitem> option. The following screen will
  appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/updateCreditStatusByCustomer.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Update Credit Status by Customer</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <note>
    <para>The credit status for a customer may also be updated using the
    Customer master. Any updates made using this utility will be reflected in
    the Customer master.</para>
  </note>

  <para>When updating the credit status for a customer, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Customer #</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the customer number of the customer whose credit status
        you want to update. Once a customer number is entered, the customer
        name and billing address will display.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Current Credit Status</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the specified customer's current credit status. Current
        credit status is drawn from the Customer master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>In Good Standing</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate the customer's credit status is good.
        Customers with credit in good standing may have sales orders issued
        for them. A black-colored typeface will be associated with their
        account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>On Credit Warning</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate the customer is on credit warning. Customers
        on credit warning may not have sales orders issued for them. An
        orange-colored typeface will be associated with their account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>On Credit Hold</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate the customer is on credit hold. Customers on
        credit hold may not have sales orders issued for them. A red-colored
        typeface will be associated with their account.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>UPDATE</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Updates the customer's credit status, using the specified
        parameters.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
