<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="updateActualCostsByItem">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>actual costs</primary>

      <secondary>updating by item</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>

      <secondary>updating actual costs for</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>actual costs</primary>

      <secondary>updating by item</secondary>
    </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>items</primary>

      <secondary>updating actual costs for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Update Actual Costs by Item</title>

  <para>Actual costs are the real-time costs associated with an item,
  including current material and production costs. The actual cost of an item
  may fluctuate given changes in the cost for materials, or other costs
  related to changes in bills of materials (BOMs) or routings. For example,
  the actual costs for purchased items may be updated whenever vouchers are
  posted for those items. Actual costs provide a current record of costs
  actually incurred by an item.</para>

  <tip>
    <para>Cost roll ups in xTuple are performed from the bottom up. In other
    words, to update the costs for a parent item you need to roll the costs
    for all the child items up into the parent item. For this reason, updating
    costs by class code is the generally preferred method. That way you can
    guarantee all the required costs are updated—and none are missed.</para>
  </tip>

  <para>To update actual costs individually by item, select the
  <guimenuitem>Update Actual Costs by Item</guimenuitem> option. The following
  screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/updateActualCostsByItem.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Update Actual Costs by Item</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <warning>
    <para>If you are blending the average cost method with the standard cost
    method, your results may vary.</para>
  </warning>

  <para>When updating actual costs by item, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the item whose actual costs you want to
        update. The lookup feature located to the right of the field leads to
        a searchable list of make and buy items.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <tip>
    <para>For manufactured items, rolling up actual costs ensures that lower
    level costs are reflected in the cost for the parent item.</para>
  </tip>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>actual costs</primary>

          <secondary>rolling up of</secondary>
        </indexterm>Roll Up Actual Costs</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to roll up actual costs. When this option is specified,
        all selected costs will be added together to establish a revised total
        actual cost for the item. This revised total goes into effect after
        the <guibutton>UPDATE</guibutton> button is selected. If all costs are
        selected, all costs will be rolled up. If a subset of all costs is
        selected, only the subset will be rolled up. If the <guilabel>Roll Up
        Actual Costs</guilabel> option is not specified, the selected cost
        updates will not be valid above their current level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>material costs</primary>

          <secondary>updating of</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>costing</primary>

          <secondary>updating of material costs</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>actual costs</primary>

          <secondary>updating material costs</secondary>
        </indexterm>Update Lower Level Material Costs</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update lower level material costs. Not selecting means
        lower level material costs will not be included in the cost
        update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term>Update Direct Labor Cost</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update direct labor cost. Not selecting means the
        direct labor cost will not be included in the cost update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term>Update Lower Level Direct Labor Cost</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update lower level direct labor cost. Not selecting
        means the lower level direct labor cost will not be included in the
        cost update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <note>
    <para>You have the flexibility of updating all or only a subset of the
    listed costs. Updating a subset might be desirable if only material or
    user costs have changed, for example.</para>
  </note>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term>Update Overhead Cost</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update overhead cost. Not selecting means the overhead
        cost will not be included in the cost update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term>Update Lower Level Overhead Cost</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update lower level overhead cost. Not selecting means
        the lower level overhead cost will not be included in the cost
        update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term>Update Machine Overhead</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update machine overhead cost. This option is selected
        by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term>Update Lower Machine Overhead</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update lower level machine overhead cost. This option
        is selected by default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>user costs</primary>

          <secondary>updating of</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>costing</primary>

          <secondary>updating of user costs</secondary>
        </indexterm> <indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>actual costs</primary>

          <secondary>updating user costs</secondary>
        </indexterm>Update User Costs</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update user costs. Not selecting means user costs will
        not be included in the cost update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Update Lower Level User Costs</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to update lower level user costs. Not selecting means
        lower level user costs will not be included in the cost update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>UPDATE</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Updates all selected costs for the specified item. If the option
        <guilabel>Roll Up Actual Costs</guilabel> has been selected, the total
        actual cost for the specified item will be updated.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>SELECT ALL COSTS</guibutton></term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Selects all costs for updating. Use this option to save time
        when selecting all costs for updating. The option <guilabel>Roll Up
        Actual Costs</guilabel> must be selected separately if you want to
        include a rolled up total for the parent item in the cost
        update.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
