<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="userCostingElement">
  <title>User Costing Element</title>
  <para><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>costing elements</primary>
      <secondary>creating user-defined</secondary>
    </indexterm>To create a new user-defined costing element, select the
  <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/userCostingElement.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create new User Costing Element</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new user-defined costing element, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Element Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify a name to describe the costing element.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to make the user-defined costing element active.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Accept P/O Distributions</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want the costing element to be used for
        distributing costs related to purchase order vouchers. If selected,
        the costing element will be included as one of the available costing
        elements when voucher item costs are distributed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Use Costing Item for Cost Source</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select if you want to associate the costing element with a
        costing item, for the purpose of tracking item costs. A costing item
        kind of pseudo-item used solely to provide a costed value for a
        costing element. When a user-defined costing element is linked to a
        costing item, the costing element assumes the costs associated with
        the costing item.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Item Number</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enter the item number of the costing item you would like
              to assign to the costing element.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>UOM</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Inventory unit of measure.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Expense Account</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The G/L account specified here will be used for tracking costs
        for the costing element when production is posted for work orders
        which consume the costing element. This feature applies to work order
        costing only and may not be used in conjunction with purchase order
        distributions.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
