<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="viewCheckRun">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>payments</primary>

      <secondary>viewing detailed list of</secondary>
    </indexterm>View Payment Run</title>

  <para>To view a detailed list of payments prepared to be run, select the
  <guimenuitem>View Payment Run </guimenuitem>option. The following screen
  will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/viewCheckRun.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>View Payment Run</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When viewing the detailed list of payments prepared to be run, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Vendor</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select all or specific vendors whose payments you would like to
        view.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Bank Account</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the bank account whose payment run you want to
        view.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Payments</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Display lists details for payments included in the payment run.
        This display is a nested list, with a plus (+) sign located to the far
        left of the display next to each payment. By clicking your mouse on a
        plus sign, you reveal lower levels of information related to the
        payment.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>

  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>PREPARE</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select to prepare a payment run. For more information on
        preparing payment runs, see <xref linkend="prepareCheckRun"/>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>PRINT/WRITTEN/PAID</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select from one of the following options. If a selected payment
        has already been written and/or paid, you will have the ability to
        mark the payment as such on the Print Payment screen. The options
        presented here will be limited if the specified bank account does not
        require payments to be printed. Also, if the bank account is
        configured to use electronic funds transfer (EFT), you will be
        presented with the option to create an EFT file on the Print Payment
        screen.</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>payments</primary>

                <secondary>printing individual</secondary>
              </indexterm>Selected Payment</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Highlight a payment in the list and then select this
              button to either print the payment or mark it as having been
              already printed/paid.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>payment runs</primary>

                <secondary>printing of</secondary>
              </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
                <primary>payments</primary>

                <secondary>printing multiple</secondary>
              </indexterm>Payment Run</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select to print the payment run, using the specified bank
              account. For more information on printing payment runs, see
              <xref linkend="printChecks"/>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Edit List</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Prints a copy of the pending payment run for
              review.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>

        <tip>
          <para>If payments being printed contain reference lines which spill
          over and exceed one standard page, then consider using the report
          definition CheckMultiPage.xml. This payment form is designed to
          support multiple pages for one payment number.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>payments</primary>

          <secondary>posting of</secondary>
        </indexterm>POST</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select from the following context-sensitive posting
        options:<variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>SELECTED PAYMENTS</term>

              <listitem>
                <para>Highlight a payment in the list of payments and then
                select this button to post the payment. If the specified bank
                account requires printing, the payment must be printed or
                marked as already printed/paid before it can be posted. If
                printing is not required, the payment may be posted
                immediately. See the <guilabel>Printed</guilabel> column in
                the display to determine a payment's printed status.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
              <term>ALL PAYMENTS</term>

              <listitem>
                <para>Select to post all payments available for
                posting.</para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
          </variablelist></para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>payments</primary>

          <secondary>voiding of</secondary>
        </indexterm>VOID</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a payment in the list of payments and then select this
        button to void the payment. Voided payments may not be printed or
        posted. When a payment is voided, the payable amount will be reopened
        on the Select Payments screen. In other words, if a payment for
        $100.00 is voided, that amount will once again be made available for
        payment on the Select Payments screen. The reopened amount will again
        be associated with the referring payable document (i.e., voucher or
        debit memo).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>EDIT</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a miscellaneous payment and then select this button to
        edit the payment. Only unprinted miscellaneous payments may be
        edited.</para>

        <note>
          <para>Only unprinted miscellaneous payments may be edited. Regular
          payments may not be edited.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>DELETE</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a voided payment in the list of payments and then
        select this button to delete the payment. Only voided payments may be
        deleted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>payments</primary>

          <secondary>replacing in payment run</secondary>
        </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>payment runs</primary>

          <secondary>replacing payments in</secondary>
        </indexterm>REPLACE</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a voided payment in the list of payments and then
        select this button to replace the payment. Payments must be voided
        before they can be replaced. When a voided payment is replaced, the
        payable amount displayed on the Select Payments screen will be
        removed. In other words, if a voided payment for $500.00 is replaced,
        that amount will no longer be available for payment on the Select
        Payments screen.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>REPLACE ALL</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select this button to replace all payments shown in the list of
        payments. Payments must be voided before they can be replaced.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
