<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="voucherMiscDistrib">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>vouchers</primary>

      <secondary>miscellaneous distributions for</secondary>
    </indexterm>Voucher Misc. Distribution</title>

  <para>In addition to line item specific distributions, you may also enter
  miscellaneous distributions to affect the voucher as a whole. To enter a
  miscellaneous distribution, select the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button
  from the main voucher screen. The following screen will appear:</para>

  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/voucherMiscDistrib.png"/>
        </imageobject>

        <caption>Miscellaneous Voucher Distribution</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>

  <para>When entering a miscellaneous voucher distribution, you are presented
  with the following options:</para>

  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Distribution Options</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select one of the following distribution options:</para>

        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Account</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select a general ledger account to use for the
              distribution.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry role="xtprjaccnt">
            <term>Project</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select a project to associate with the transaction. The
              project number will be added as the final segment of the G/L
              account number.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Expense Category</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select an expense category to use for the
              distribution.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>

          <varlistentry>
            <term>Tax Code</term>

            <listitem>
              <para>Select a tax code to use for the distribution. When using
              this option, the distribution amount will be charged to the
              general ledger account associated with the tax code. To have tax
              calculated automatically for the distribution, use the <guimenuitem>Tax Type</guimenuitem>
              option.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Amount to Distribute</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the amount of the miscellaneous distribution. If there
        is a balance still to be distributed once all voucher items have been
        distributed, then that remaining amount will be entered here by
        default.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Tax Type</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select a tax type to associate with the distribution. Tax will
        be calculated automatically if a tax assignment matches both the tax
        type and the specified tax zone.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Discountable</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>Select if the voucher item is entitled to a terms discount. This
        option may be used on a line-by-line basis—all within one voucher. For
        example, purchased items may be discountable; however, freight charges
        may not be. When selecting a voucher for payment within the discount
        period, only discountable items will be discounted.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>

    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>

      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        general notes related to the voucher. These notes are for internal use
        only.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
