<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="workOrder">
  <title><indexterm significance="normal">
      <primary>work orders</primary>
      <secondary>creating new</secondary>
    </indexterm>Create New Work Order</title>
  <para>Work orders define requirements for the production of manufactured
  items. You may also create Work orders for purchased items that you normally
  purchase, but you occasionally manufacture. These items may have a Bill of
  materials (BOM)—or not. The system supports both BOM-based and non-BOM-based
  work orders.</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>BOM-based</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Material requirements are drawn from the bill of materials when
        the work order is exploded, using the specified Revision. Users may
        add or subtract material requirements as needed.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Non-BOM-based</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Ideal for labor-only work orders having a routing
        but no BOM—for example, service work orders which require labor
        operations only. Also good for items or jobs where the material
        requirements are not-known—but must be added on an ad-hoc
        basis.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To create a new work order, select the <guimenuitem>Create New Work Order</guimenuitem> option.
  The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/workOrder_detailTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Create New Work Order</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <tip>
    <para>To edit a work order after it has been created, use the right-click
    menu in any of the "Work Order Schedule by..." displays. There you will
    find an <guimenuitem>Edit W/O</guimenuitem> option.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>When creating a new work order, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Work Order #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Next available work order number will automatically display,
        unless your system requires you to enter work order numbers manually.
        Default values and input parameters for work order numbers are
        configurable at the system level.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Item Number</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the item number of the item you want to create a work
        order for. You may also enter purchased items that you normally buy,
        but you occasionally make. The lookup feature located to the right of
        the field leads to a searchable list of make and buy items.</para>
        <note>
          <para><indexterm significance="normal">
              <primary>job items</primary>
              <secondary>work orders for</secondary>
            </indexterm><indexterm significance="normal">
              <primary>work orders</primary>
              <secondary>for job items</secondary>
            </indexterm>Work orders for job items are created exclusively by
          sales order demand. It is not possible to create a job item work
          order using the Work Order screen. Similarly, production posting for
          job items occurs in a unique way. Production for job item work
          orders is posted when the sales order which demanded the job item is
          issued to shipping. This is the only way to post production for job
          item work orders.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>UOM</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Inventory unit of measure.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Site</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the site where the item is supplied at. For manufactured
        items to be included on a work order, their item site record must
        indicate they are manufactured for the site.</para>
        <note>
          <para>Order parameters may have an impact on work order quantity if
          the <guilabel>on Manual Orders</guilabel> option is selected in the Item Site master
          for a manufactured item. If order parameters are in effect, the work
          order must conform to those restrictions. Both minimum order size
          and order multiple may be governed by order parameter
          settings.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Assembly</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to identify the work order as an assembly order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Disassembly</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to identify the work order as a disassembly order. When
        disassembling items, the system will not enforce order parameters
        defined at the item site level.</para>
        <note>
          <para>If there are average cost items on a disassembly order, those
          components will be returned to inventory using standard cost when
          they are backflushed.</para>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Ordered</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Value entered specifies the number of item units to be processed
        by the work order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Qty. Received</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the quantity of finished product posted as received
        into inventory to date, if any.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><indexterm significance="normal">
          <primary>work orders</primary>
          <secondary>adjusting lead times for</secondary>
        </indexterm>Lead Time (Days)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
        value up to a maximum of 999. Value entered specifies the
        manufacturing Lead Time required between the date the work order
        starts and the date it is due. Lead Times for items are specified in
        the Item Site master, but may be modified on this screen.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>The <guilabel>Lead Time</guilabel> option is only available when creating a new
          work order. Once the order is created, this option will not be
          visible.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Due Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the date the work order must be completed by.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Start Date</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter the date the work order must be started by. By default,
        this date will be the due date less the Lead Time. The start date may
        be changed by altering the Lead Time field.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Priority</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select a number using the arrow buttons, or manually enter a
        value up to a maximum of 99. Value entered assigns a priority to the
        selected work order. By assigning a priority to a work order, you can
        indicate the relative importance of a work order in comparison to
        other work orders.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Project #</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If your system is configured to use projects, select a project
        number to associate with the work order. If the work order was created
        from sales order demand—and the parent sales order had a project
        number associated with it—then the project number from the parent
        sales order will automatically be entered here. In this way, sales
        orders and work orders may be linked to the same project.</para>
        <para role="xtprjaccnt">When you have the xTuple Project Accounting
        package installed—and you link a project to the work
        order—transactions related to the work order will include the project
        number as the final segment of affected G/L Account Numbers. Account
        numbers related to the following transactions will include the project
        number as the final segment: issue materials, post operations, post
        production, return material, correct post operations, correct post
        production, scrap material.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Detail</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The <guimenuitem>Detail</guimenuitem> tab provides a kind of workbench for managing
        materials, child work orders, and operations associated with a work
        order. Use the context-sensitive right-click menu to perform actions
        related to work order management. The display is a nested list, with a
        plus ("+") sign located to the far left of the display next to each
        row that may be expanded to lower levels. By clicking your mouse on a
        plus sign, you reveal lower levels of information related to the
        group. The following color-coding has been implemented to simplify
        navigation: green (work orders), blue (operations), black
        (materials).</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Show</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Specify the type of work order information you would like
              to include in the display:</para>
              <variablelist>
                <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
                  <term>Operations</term>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select to include information about work order
                    operations in the display.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Materials</term>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select to include information about material
                    requirements in the display. Materials may be issued to
                    exploded work orders only if that option is enabled in the
                    work order configuration. For more information, please see
                    <xref linkend="AllowIssue" />.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                  <term>Indented</term>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>Select to include child work orders in the display.
                    If selected, child work orders will be shown indented in
                    the materials and operations list.</para>
                  </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
              </variablelist>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Print Traveler</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to print a work order traveler at the point when the work
        order is initially created. This option will be hidden once the work
        order has been created.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To add notes to a work order, select the <guimenuitem>Notes</guimenuitem> tab. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/workOrder_notesTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Work Order Notes</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>When adding notes to a work order, you are presented with the
  following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a scrolling text field with word-wrapping for entering
        production notes related to the work order. Production notes are
        printed on pick lists and packing lists for reference by production
        personnel.</para>
        <tip>
          <para>If a work order was created from a sales order, the production
          notes field will contain the sales order number, the customer Name,
          and any additional sales order line item notes.</para>
        </tip>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>If an item has characteristics associated with it, you have the option
  of linking those characteristics to a work order item. And, in the case
  where a work order is generated from a linked sales order, the work order
  will inherit characteristics defined at the sales order level.</para>
  <tip>
    <para>You can link characteristics and values to an item by using the Item
    master. Once entered, these characteristics and values will be available
    to users entering sales order line items.</para>
  </tip>
  <para>To associate characteristics with a work order, select the
  <guimenuitem>Characteristics</guimenuitem> tab. As you can see in the following screenshot, there are
  two types of characteristics available:</para>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Work Order Item Characteristics</emphasis>:
      Inherited from Item Characteristics</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Work Order Characteristics</emphasis>: Ad
      hoc characteristics which may be associated manually with a work
      order</para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/workOrder_itemchar.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Work Order Characteristics</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>When specifying work order item characteristics, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Work Order Item Characteristics</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the name of any item characteristics associated with
        the item. Characteristics defined as item characteristics may be
        associated with items on the Item master.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Value</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Displays the default value associated with an item
        characteristic, but permits you to specify an alternate value. When
        associating characteristic values with a work order item, you have
        four options: 1) Select the default value; 2) select an alternate
        pre-defined value; 3) manually enter a new value in place of the
        pre-defined value; or 4) make no selection. Making no selection means
        the characteristics will not be associated with the work order
        item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Work order characteristics, by contrast, are ad hoc in nature and may
  be created manually and linked to the work order.</para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/characteristic.xml"
              xpointer="characteristiclWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
  <para>To create or view comments related to a work order, select the
  <guimenuitem>Comments</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/workOrder_TabPage.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Add Work Order Comments</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <note>
    <para>Work order comments may not be added at the time of work order
    creation. Instead, use the <guimenuitem>Production Notes</guimenuitem> tab for entering notes related
    to a work order.</para>
  </note>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/comments.xml" xpointer="commentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
  <para>Once a work order is in process—that is, either materials have been
  issued or production or operations have been posted—you can begin to view
  costing information for the work order. To view costing information for the
  work order, select the <guimenuitem>Costing</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><tip>
      <para>The <guimenuitem>Costing</guimenuitem> tab will not be visible until after a work order has
      been created. You will not see costing information when creating a work
      order.</para>
    </tip><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/workOrder_costing.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Work Order Costing</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot>When viewing work order costing information, you are
  presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Accumulated Costs</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Information about the following categories of currently
        accumulated work order costs will be shown:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Posted</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the current posted value of the work order. The
              posted value is equal to the total cost accumulated on the work
              order, including both labor and materials. The posted value will
              be the same as the WIP value until the point when finished goods
              are received. Ultimately, once production (or operations)
              posting is completed, the posted value will be equal to the
              received value. If these two values are different, then a
              variance will result.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Received</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the current value of finished goods received into
              inventory from the work order. The received value is equal to
              the posted value minus WIP.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>WIP</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Displays the current value of Work in Process (WIP) for
              the work order. The WIP value is equal to the posted value minus
              the received value.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Cost Recognition</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Used by work orders for job and average cost items to determine
        how and when costs are recognized:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>To Date</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>All of the costs accumulated against the work order will
              be debited to inventory and credited to WIP.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Proportional</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Costs are recognized in proportion to the total costs
              posted and the total items received to date.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>The default cost recognition method is defined at the system level;
    however, you may change the setting manually at the work order
    level.</para>
  </note>
  <para role="standard">When creating a work order, you have the option to
  specify which revision of the work order item's bill of materials and bill
  of operations you want to use. By default, the active revision will be used.
  Once the work order has been created, these options will become read-only.
  To specify revision information for a work order item, select the <guimenuitem>Revision</guimenuitem>
  tab. The following screen will appear:</para>
  <para role="standard"><screenshot role="standard">
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/workOrder_revision.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Revision Information</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para role="standard"><note>
      <para>You may create work orders for pending Revisions. For work order
      purposes, a pending Revision is considered to be the same as an inactive
      Revision. The Revision status of a pending Revision will not be changed
      if a work order is created for it.</para>
    </note></para>
  <para role="standard">When specifying Revision information for a work order
  item, you are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry role="standard">
      <term>Bill of Materials</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the BOM Revision you want to use for the work order. By
        default, the active Revision will be used.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Revision</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select from the list of existing available Revisions. The
              status of the Revision will also be displayed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry role="manufacturing">
      <term>Routing</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the routing revision you want to use for the work order. You
        can select the current Active or any Substitute routing. By default, the
        active Revision will be used.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Revision</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Select from the list of existing available Revisions. The
              status of the Revision will also be displayed.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>To view the documents associated with a work order, select the
  <guimenuitem>Documents</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will appear:<mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/workOrder_documentsTab.png" />
      </imageobject>
      <caption><para>Work Order Documents</para></caption>
    </mediaobject></para>
  <xi:include href="../widgets/documents.xml" xpointer="documentsWidget"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
