<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section role="standard">
  <title>Dashboard Datasource</title>
  <para>To create new a Datasource, select the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button. The following
  screen will appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/xTDashDatasource.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Dashboard Datasource</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>When creating a new Datasource, you are presented with the following
  options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Title</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a title to identify the Datasource.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a brief description to describe the Datasource.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Type</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>The type indicates how the Datasource will retrieve the data
        used to populate the Charts. The following choices are available:
        MetaSQL, Query item, or URL. Depending on which type you choose, the
        related on-screen options will change, as follows:</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>MetaSQL Datasource Settings</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>In most cases, Datasources will be generated from
              previously written MetaSQL queries. This is the most common
              type. Choose the Group and Name of an existing MetaSQL query to
              define that as the source.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Query Item Datasource Settings</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Query Sets are defined in the import/export area of
              xTuple. To use one of these Query Sets as a Datasource, choose
              the Head name and item.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>URL Datasource Settings</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>The URL Datasource will allow the Datasource data and
              formatting to be downloaded from an external web source/service.
              This will allow information external to xTuple to be included in
              Dashboards. <emphasis role="bold">This feature has not been
              implemented yet</emphasis>.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Chart Options</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Specify the Chart display options you want to make available
        when dashboard panes are created using the datasource.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Chart Types</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Data can be displayed in a number of different graphical
              formats. The following options are available: bar, line, spline,
              step, area, area spline, area step, scatter, pie, donut, and
              gauge. To make a Chart type available for the Datasource, simply
              add the Chart type(s) to the "Granted Types" column.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Layout Grids</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Dashboard Panes can be created to display in varying
              widths per row. Each Dashboard row can contain either one, two,
              or three Panes across, depending on the options allowed by the
              Datasource. To specify the grid layout options available for the
              Datasource, simply add the layout grid(s) to the "Granted Layout
              Grids" column, as shown in the following screenshot:</para>
              <para><screenshot>
                  <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                      <imagedata fileref="images/xTDashDatasourceLayoutGridsTab.png" />
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>Chart Options Layout Grids Tab</caption>
                  </mediaobject>
                </screenshot></para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Active</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate the Datasource is active. If not selected,
        the Datasource will be considered inactive.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Public Access</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select to indicate the Datasource should be available to all
        users. If not selected, the Datasource will be considered private and
        will require users to have the appropriate privileges to access
        it.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Private Access Settings</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>If the Datasource is private (i.e., not public), then you will
        need to specify how users will gain access to the information.</para>
        <variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Privileges</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Control access using system privileges. Any users having
              the specified privilege(s) will be able to use the Datasource
              when adding Dashboard Panes. To specify the desired system
              privileges, simply add the privilege(s) to the "Granted
              Privileges" column.</para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Users</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Control access by user. Any user who has been granted
              access will have access to the Datasource. To give access to
              users, simply add the user(s) to the "Granted Users" column, as
              shown in the following screenshot:</para>
              <para><screenshot>
                  <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                      <imagedata fileref="images/xTDashDatasourceUsersTab.png" />
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>Private Access Settings Users Tab</caption>
                  </mediaobject>
                </screenshot></para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Roles</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Control access by Role. Any users assigned to the
              specified Role(s) will have access to the Datasource. To grant
              access by Role, simply add the Role(s) to the "Granted Roles"
              column, as shown in the following screenshot:</para>
              <para><screenshot>
                  <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                      <imagedata fileref="images/xTDashDatasourceRolesTab.png" />
                    </imageobject>
                    <caption>Private Access Settings Roles Tab</caption>
                  </mediaobject>
                </screenshot></para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>The following buttons are unique to this screen:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>ADD-&gt;</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a specific source in the available sources column,
        then select this button to transfer the source to the granted sources
        column. Double-clicking on an available source will also transfer it
        to the granted sources column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term><guibutton>&lt;-REVOKE</guibutton></term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highlight a specific source in the granted sources column, then
        select this button to remove the source from the granted sources
        column. Double-clicking on a granted source will also remove it from the
        granted sources column.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
</section>
