<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="dashboardDatasources" role="standard">
  <title>Datasources</title>
  <para>All dashboards get their source data and formatting from datasources.
  Datasources are required to provide the information to populate the charts,
  but they are also used to define axis labels, color requirements and other
  presentation aspects of the charts.</para>
  <para>To view the list of available datasources, go to <guimenuitem>System
  &gt; Setup</guimenuitem>. In the Setup window, from the left side menu,
  select <guimenuitem>Configure &gt; Dashboards</guimenuitem> and select the
  <guimenuitem>Datasources</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/xTDashDatasources.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Dashboard datasources</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>The datasources list displays information on all existing datasources,
  including datasource title, description, type, and public, active and system
  statuses.</para>
  <warning>
    <para>Many of the dashboards are marked as <emphasis>system</emphasis>
    dashboards. You should be careful not to edit these, copying their
    information to your own versions instead.</para>
  </warning>
  <para>To view the server side settings for your datasources, select the
  <guimenuitem>Server</guimenuitem> tab. The following screen will
  appear:</para>
  <para><screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/xTDashDatasourcesServerTab.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption>Dashboard Server Options</caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>Server settings define the internal web server that is used to present
  the dashboard charts. It is technically feasible to use these settings to
  view dashboards in an external browser or other software. However, if you
  only intend to view dashboards inside your xTuple client, you can just leave
  the settings as they are.</para>
  <para>When defining your dashboard server settings, you are presented with
  the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Server Hostname</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is the network address of the web server. This is typically
        <literal>127.0.0.1</literal> for an internal (local) address—or you
        could enter the IP address of the PC/server running the xTuple
        client.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>HTTP Server Port</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Defaults to 3000. Typically no change is required, unless there
        is a conflict with other software.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>WebSocket Server Port</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Defaults to 3030. Typically no change is required, unless there
        is a conflict with other software.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Server API Key</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Randomly generated key. This does not require changing.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Server SSL Key (Generate a Self Signed SSL Certificate)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use the default key unless you wish to make the dashboards
        externally available and want to provide a suitably secure SSL
        key.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Server SSL Certificate</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Use the default key unless you wish to make the dashboards
        externally available and want to provide a suitably secure (and
        signed) server certificate.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <xi:include href="xTDashDatasource.xml" xpointer="element(/1)"
              xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</section>
