<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 1998-2013 by xTuple. All rights reserved. -->
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="queryset">
  <title>Query Sets and the QuerySet widget</title>
  <para>A query set is a collection of database queries that are run in
  sequence. They can be used for exporting data, checking the status of the
  database, or performing routine database maintenance tasks. When the query
  set is run, each individual query in the query set is run in the order you
  choose. The results of the individual queries, called query items, are saved
  together in a single file.</para>
  <para>To create, edit, and use a query set, follow this path:
  <guimenuitem>System &gt; Utilities &gt; Export Data</guimenuitem></para>
  <note role="xtconnect">
    <para>If you have xTuple Connect installed and enabled, you can also work
    with query sets when editing an EDI form as part of an EDI profile. The
    EDI form must have CSV, HTML, or XML as its output format. The results of
    the query set are then sent by email or FTP. See the <ulink
    url="http://xtuple.com/docs/reference-guide">xTuple Connect Product
    Guide</ulink> for more information.</para>
  </note>
  <para>You will see a screen that contains the following:<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/queryset_widget.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption><para>Query Set widget</para></caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>In this example there is one query set defined in the database, named
  ARStmt.</para>
  <para>To modify an existing query set, select it from the list and click the
  <guibutton>EDIT</guibutton> button. Similarly, to delete an existing query
  set, select it from the list and click the <guibutton>DELETE</guibutton>
  button.</para>
  <para>To create a new query set, click the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton>
  button. You will see the following screen:<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/queryset.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption><para>New Query Set </para></caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>You are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a short name for this query set.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Description</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a simple description of what this query set does.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Queries in this set</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This is a list of the query items which have already been
        defined as part of this query set.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter notes about this query set—a full description of why you
        created it or what it is intended to do.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>Use the <guibutton>NEW</guibutton> button to add a query item to this
  query set. You will see the following screen:<screenshot>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/queryitem.png" />
        </imageobject>
        <caption><para>The Query Item window showing an example of a custom
        MetaSQL query</para></caption>
      </mediaobject>
    </screenshot></para>
  <para>You are presented with the following options:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Name</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Enter a name for this query item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Order</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Select the position of this query item in the sequence. Query
        items with a lower order value will be run before those with a higher
        order.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Type of Query</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Choose whether this query item should list all data from a
        particular database table or view, if it should use a MetaSQL
        statement already defined in the database for another screen or
        report, or if you want to create a new MetaSQL statement for use just
        by this query item.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>Notes</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>Add comments about this query item here.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <para>If you choose Custom Query as the <guilabel>Type of Query</guilabel>,
  you will see the MetaSQL editor. The MetaSQL language and MetaSQL editor are
  described in the <ulink
  url="http://www.xtuple.org/docs/reference-guide">OpenRPT Product
  Guide</ulink>. To summarize that information, the MetaSQL language lets you
  build SQL queries dynamically and the MetaSQL editor lets you type and test
  MetaSQL statements. The query shown in the example above lists all of the
  header data for every sales order with one or more open line items,
  optionally restricted to a single customer.</para>
  <para>Click <guibutton>SAVE </guibutton>to save this query item.</para>
  <para>To add line item data to this query set, create another query item.
  Set the order to <literal>1</literal>, select Custom Query as the
  <guilabel>Type of Query</guilabel>, and enter the following text in the
  MetaSQL editor:<programlisting>SELECT *
  FROM api.salesline
 WHERE status='O'
&lt;? if exists('cust_number') ?&gt;
  AND order_number IN (SELECT order_number
                         FROM api.salesline
                        WHERE customer_number = &lt;? value('cust_number') ?&gt;)
&lt;? endif ?&gt;
;</programlisting></para>
  <para>If this query set gets run with no active parameters, it will show all
  sales orders with at least one open line item followed by all open sales
  line items. If you make the <literal>cust_number</literal> parameter active
  and set it to a valid customer number, the query set will produce all open
  sales orders and their open sales line items for just that one
  customer.</para>
</section>
